(window.webpackJsonp=window.webpackJsonp||[]).push([[1],{0:function(e,t,r){e.exports=r("zUnb")},Gz50:function(e){e.exports=JSON.parse('[{"Question":"Vehicles with air brakes must comply with The Highway Traffic Act and Regulations. If a vehicle does not comply, both the driver and the operator may be charged.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the tractor protection valve?","options":["Prevents total air loss from the trailer if the trailer breaks away","Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away","Holds the supply line and emergency line in place not allowing them to break away","Prevents over pressure in the system allowing excess air to escape"],"correctAnswer":"Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away"},{"Question":"What happens when the trailer lines are not connected properly?","options":["Spring brakes may not release","The towing vehicle may lose air","Service brakes will not function properly","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"If air exhausts from the service line, it means that the trailer supply valve is defective.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When checking the buildup rate (compressor operation) the engine should be building air pressure from _____ psi to ____ psi within two minutes:","options":["45 - 65","65 - 85","85 - 100","100 - 125"],"correctAnswer":"85 - 100"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed in one minute on a tractor with two or more trailers?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","5 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"6 psi"},{"Question":"When the pushrod stroke exceeds the adjustment limit of the brake chamber, the brake:","options":["Is out of adjustment","Is in adjustment","Needs to be replaced","Has a minor defect"],"correctAnswer":"Is out of adjustment"},{"Question":"If air loss exceeds the maximum allowable limit specified for your vehicle, it would be considered a major defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What should you do before you exit the vehicle or get underneath it?","options":["Start the vehicle","Secure the vehicle","Grab your safety equipment","Turn off the vehicle"],"correctAnswer":"Secure the vehicle"},{"Question":"What happens if a single brake malfunctions?","options":["It puts more pressure on the other brakes","It causes the other brakes to quickly overheat","It could cause the other brakes to fail","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What is the size of an air brake chamber based on?","options":["The type of chamber","The area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches","The pushrod travel distance","The make and model of the vehicle"],"correctAnswer":"The area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel is within the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This:","options":["Is a minor defect","Is a major defect","Passes the inspection","Is a broken or defective part"],"correctAnswer":"Passes the inspection"},{"Question":"What are the three different types of foundation brake systems?","options":["\'S\' cam brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes","ABS brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes","ABS brakes, \'S\' cam brakes, and wedge brakes","\'S\' cam brakes, ABS brakes, and disc brakes"],"correctAnswer":"\'S\' cam brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes"},{"Question":"In order to make a service brake application?","options":["Pull the yellow button","Pull the red button","Push the brake pedal","Push the red and yellow buttons"],"correctAnswer":"Push the brake pedal"},{"Question":"The first air tank that air enters is called the supply (wet tank).","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"If air pressure drops below the normal cut-in setting what should the driver do?","options":["Continue driving until the spring brakes apply","Make several full brake applications","Nothing","Bring the vehicle to a safe stop as soon as possible"],"correctAnswer":"Bring the vehicle to a safe stop as soon as possible"},{"Question":"Spring brakes use air to apply the brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When testing the compressor, if there is a trailer attached, the trailer supply valve must be closed.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Brake lining is defective when it is:","options":["Cracked","Missing","Loose","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Inspecting a vehicle\u2019s air brake chambers includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Audible air leaks","Cracks and non-manufactured holes","Brakes with different air brake chamber sizes on each end of a steering axle","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"As brakes heat up, you may experience a reduction in their effectiveness. This is known as:","options":["ABS brakes","Anti-lock braking","Brake fade","Combination braking"],"correctAnswer":"Brake fade"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not exceed:","options":["90 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"145 psi"},{"Question":"Operating a vehicle with defects or failing to conduct the required inspections can result in:","options":["Charges against the driver and/or operator","Detainment or impoundment of the vehicle","Fines","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Your spring brakes should be used when parking or in an emergency when your service brakes fail?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"How would you know if the anti-lock braking system had a malfunction?","options":["The brakes won\'t function at all","The brakes will function intermittently","Only the trailer hand valve functions","The ABS malfunction warning light illuminates"],"correctAnswer":"The ABS malfunction warning light illuminates"},{"Question":"In what order should air tanks be drained?","options":["Wet, primary, secondary","Primary, secondary, wet","Primary, wet, secondary","All at the same time"],"correctAnswer":"Wet, primary, secondary"},{"Question":"Failure of the spring brakes to hold the vehicle stationary indicates defective service brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What controls an air brake system\u2019s pressure range (cut-in and cut-out settings)?","options":["The governor","The compressor","The engine","The turbo-charger"],"correctAnswer":"The governor"},{"Question":"Inspecting the brake components includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum","Damaged, missing or malfunctioning foundation brake components","Cracked, loose, missing or contaminated brake lining, improper drum contact or lining thickness that is less than required","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"A brake chamber that includes both service brake and spring brake sections is called a:","options":["Brake chamber","Spring brake chamber","DD3 brake chamber","Service brake chamber"],"correctAnswer":"Spring brake chamber"},{"Question":"The brake on each end of an axel should have a different sized air brake chamber to ensure brake forces are balanced.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed in one minute on a tractor with two or more trailers?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","5 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"6 psi"},{"Question":"When should the supply tank be drained?","options":["First","Last","In whatever order is most convenient for the driver","The supply tank should never be drained"],"correctAnswer":"First"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle\u2019s air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel exceeds the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This is:","options":["A minor defect","A major defect","Within the acceptable adjustment limit","Something to keep track of"],"correctAnswer":"A major defect"},{"Question":"What can indicate that an air tank or mounting bracket is not secure?","options":["Unusual movement","An air leak","A fluid leak","A deflated airbag"],"correctAnswer":"Unusual movement"},{"Question":"When testing the compressor, if there is a trailer attached, the trailer supply valve must be closed.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the safety valve?","options":["Starts building air pressure at 100 psi","Stops building air pressure at 140 psi","Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting","Ensures the trucks safety features are working correctly"],"correctAnswer":"Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting"},{"Question":"What are the three different types of foundation brake systems?","options":["\'S\' cam brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes","ABS brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes","ABS brakes, \'S\' cam brakes, and wedge brakes","\'S\' cam brakes, ABS brakes, and disc brakes"],"correctAnswer":"\'S\' cam brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes"},{"Question":"In Manitoba, who can perform brake adjustments on manual slack adjusters so the pushrod is less than the adjusted limit?","options":["A licensed driver with an A endorsement or a certified technician","A licensed driver with an S endorsement","The owner for the vehicle","A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"],"correctAnswer":"A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"},{"Question":"At what level must the low pressure warning device activate?","options":["At or above 60 psi","Between 40 - 50 psi","At or above 85 psi","At or above 55 psi"],"correctAnswer":"At or above 55 psi"},{"Question":"What is a reliable method for inspecting your brake adjustment?","options":["Measuring the applied pushrod stroke","Checking the slack adjustment","Checking the condition of the brake drum","Measuring the brake chamber size"],"correctAnswer":"Measuring the applied pushrod stroke"},{"Question":"What controls an air brake system\u2019s pressure range (cut-in and cut-out settings)?","options":["The governor","The compressor","The engine","The turbo-charger"],"correctAnswer":"The governor"},{"Question":"When checking the air pressure buildup rate (compressor operation), what should the engine be idling between?","options":["200 - 500 rpm","500 - 800 rpm","600 - 900 rpm","900 - 1200 rpm"],"correctAnswer":"600 - 900 rpm"},{"Question":"The size of an air brake chamber is based on the area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Why are automatic slack adjusters used?","options":["They make inspections and adjustments unnecessary","As a backup to a manual slack adjuster","To avoid the need to regularly perform manual re-adjustments","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To avoid the need to regularly perform manual re-adjustments"},{"Question":"Failure of the spring brakes to hold the vehicle stationary indicates defective service brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not exceed:","options":["90 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"145 psi"},{"Question":"What does ABS stand for?","options":["Automatic Brake Stop","Automatic Braking System","Anti-lock Brake System","Accelerated Braking System"],"correctAnswer":"Anti-lock Brake System"},{"Question":"When testing the air-loss rate of the brake system, the brake application must be held for:","options":["30 seconds","One minute","Two minutes","Three minutes"],"correctAnswer":"One minute"},{"Question":"In what order should air tanks be drained?","options":["Wet, primary, secondary","Primary, secondary, wet","Primary, wet, secondary","All at the same time"],"correctAnswer":"Wet, primary, secondary"},{"Question":"Why should the gladhands be stored properly when not in use?","options":["To keep the seals from cracking","To make them easier to find next time they\u2019re needed","To keep them clean and in good condition","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To keep them clean and in good condition"},{"Question":"The Highway Traffic Act and Regulations prohibit the operation of a vehicle with a brake that is out of adjustment.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Air compressors can be inspected with the engine running or stopped.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"There is often a noticeable change in the behaviour of brakes with drums or rotors that are defective, cracked or broken.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle\u2019s air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel exceeds the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This is:","options":["A minor defect","A major defect","Within the acceptable adjustment limit","Something to keep track of"],"correctAnswer":"A major defect"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not be lower than:","options":["60 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"120 psi"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed in one minute on a tractor with two or more trailers?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","5 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"6 psi"},{"Question":"How often is it recommended that the air tanks be drained?","options":["At the beginning of every trip","At the end of every trip","Every day","Once a week"],"correctAnswer":"Every day"},{"Question":"When checking the buildup rate (compressor operation) the engine should be building air pressure from _____ psi to ____ psi within two minutes:","options":["45 - 65","65 - 85","85 - 100","100 - 125"],"correctAnswer":"85 - 100"},{"Question":"What happens when the trailer lines are not connected properly?","options":["Spring brakes may not release","The towing vehicle may lose air","Service brakes will not function properly","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"A brake chamber that includes both service brake and spring brake sections is called a:","options":["Brake chamber","Spring brake chamber","DD3 brake chamber","Service brake chamber"],"correctAnswer":"Spring brake chamber"},{"Question":"When testing the air-loss rate of the brake system, the brake pedal must be fully applied.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When should the supply tank be drained?","options":["First","Last","In whatever order is most convenient for the driver","The supply tank should never be drained"],"correctAnswer":"First"},{"Question":"What should you do before you exit the vehicle or get underneath it?","options":["Start the vehicle","Secure the vehicle","Grab your safety equipment","Turn off the vehicle"],"correctAnswer":"Secure the vehicle"},{"Question":"Inspecting a vehicle\u2019s air lines includes checking for the following defects:","options":["Audible air leak","Damaged or worn air lines","Improper fittings used to connect or repair air lines","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"When the pushrod stroke exceeds the adjustment limit of the brake chamber, the brake:","options":["Is out of adjustment","Is in adjustment","Needs to be replaced","Has a minor defect"],"correctAnswer":"Is out of adjustment"},{"Question":"Testing the performance of your brakes requires performing separate tests of each braking system.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed when testing the air-loss rate of the brake system on a tractor and trailer?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","6 psi","10 psi"],"correctAnswer":"4 psi"},{"Question":"What happens if a single brake malfunctions?","options":["It puts more pressure on the other brakes","It causes the other brakes to quickly overheat","It could cause the other brakes to fail","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Automatic slack adjusters, if working properly, require regular re-adjustment.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"The brake on each end of an axel should have a different sized air brake chamber to ensure brake forces are balanced.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the governor?","options":["The governor causes the compressor to start and stop pumping air (cut-in and cut-out)","The governor controls the amount of moisture the air dryer removes from the system","Once air flows through the supply tank, the governor prevents it from returning","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"The governor causes the compressor to start and stop pumping air (cut-in and cut-out)"},{"Question":"Spring brakes use air to apply the brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Actual cut-in pressure for the governor should never be less than 90 PSI?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Actual cut-in pressure of the governor should never be less than:","options":["55 psi","80 psi","100 psi","120 psi"],"correctAnswer":"100 psi"},{"Question":"Inspecting the brake components includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum","Damaged, missing or malfunctioning foundation brake components","Cracked, loose, missing or contaminated brake lining, improper drum contact or lining thickness that is less than required","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What can indicate that an air tank or mounting bracket is not secure?","options":["Unusual movement","An air leak","A fluid leak","A deflated airbag"],"correctAnswer":"Unusual movement"},{"Question":"What happens when the trailer lines are not connected properly?","options":["Spring brakes may not release","The towing vehicle may lose air","Service brakes will not function properly","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Where are air brake chambers located?","options":["At each wheel","At the drive wheels only","At the trailer wheels only","At both the drive and trailer wheels"],"correctAnswer":"At each wheel"},{"Question":"When the brakes are applied, a brake malfunction is indicated by the brake lining not contacting the drum.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What do anti-lock braking systems (ABS) do?","options":["Help maintain steering control during emergency braking","Help prevent wheel lock","Do not shorten the stopping distance","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not be lower than:","options":["60 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"120 psi"},{"Question":"At what level must the low pressure warning device activate?","options":["At or above 60 psi","Between 40 - 50 psi","At or above 85 psi","At or above 55 psi"],"correctAnswer":"At or above 55 psi"},{"Question":"There is often a noticeable change in the behaviour of brakes with drums or rotors that are defective, cracked or broken.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Testing the performance of your brakes requires performing separate tests of each braking system.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"The brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum is an example of:","options":["A foundation brake component defect","An issue with the brake chamber","An incorrectly measured pushrod","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"A foundation brake component defect"},{"Question":"When conducting an inspection of the air brake system, be sure to:","options":["Park the vehicle on level ground","Park the vehicle away from traffic","Turn the engine off","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Air compressors can be inspected with the engine running or stopped.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not exceed:","options":["90 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"145 psi"},{"Question":"When damage extends into the reinforcing or inner layer, the air line is defective.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle\u2019s air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel exceeds the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This is:","options":["A minor defect","A major defect","Within the acceptable adjustment limit","Something to keep track of"],"correctAnswer":"A major defect"},{"Question":"In order to make a service brake application?","options":["Pull the yellow button","Pull the red button","Push the brake pedal","Push the red and yellow buttons"],"correctAnswer":"Push the brake pedal"},{"Question":"Who is responsible for ensuring air brakes are correctly adjusted?","options":["The employer","The manufacturer","The last person driving the vehicle","The current driver"],"correctAnswer":"The current driver"},{"Question":"The first air tank that air enters is called the supply (wet tank).","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Wheels, dust shields, and other parts of the vehicle have no impact on your view of the brake drums and rotors.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the safety valve?","options":["Starts building air pressure at 100 psi","Stops building air pressure at 140 psi","Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting","Ensures the trucks safety features are working correctly"],"correctAnswer":"Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting"},{"Question":"What is the size of an air brake chamber based on?","options":["The type of chamber","The area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches","The pushrod travel distance","The make and model of the vehicle"],"correctAnswer":"The area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed in one minute on a tractor with two or more trailers?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","5 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"6 psi"},{"Question":"Your spring brakes should be used when parking or in an emergency when your service brakes fail?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"The air pressure must build from 85 psi to 100 psi in _______?","options":["30 seconds","One minute","Two minutes","Three minutes"],"correctAnswer":"Two minutes"},{"Question":"A brake chamber that includes both service brake and spring brake sections is called a:","options":["Brake chamber","Spring brake chamber","DD3 brake chamber","Service brake chamber"],"correctAnswer":"Spring brake chamber"},{"Question":"Why are automatic slack adjusters used?","options":["They make inspections and adjustments unnecessary","As a backup to a manual slack adjuster","To avoid the need to regularly perform manual re-adjustments","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To avoid the need to regularly perform manual re-adjustments"},{"Question":"Automatic slack adjusters, if working properly, require regular re-adjustment.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not be lower than:","options":["60 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"120 psi"},{"Question":"At what pressure do the spring brakes normally start to apply because there is no longer enough pressure to keep them released?","options":["20 psi","40 psi","60 psi","85 psi"],"correctAnswer":"60 psi"},{"Question":"When testing brake performance (tug tests), it would be considered a major defect if:","options":["The spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle in place","The service brakes fail to stop the vehicle","Only if the tractor spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle","Both A and B"],"correctAnswer":"Both A and B"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed in one minute on a tractor with two or more trailers?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","5 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"6 psi"},{"Question":"Older air systems may operate with lower pressure settings.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"The brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum is an example of:","options":["A foundation brake component defect","An issue with the brake chamber","An incorrectly measured pushrod","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"A foundation brake component defect"},{"Question":"When conducting an inspection of the air brake system, be sure to:","options":["Park the vehicle on level ground","Park the vehicle away from traffic","Turn the engine off","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"When the brakes are applied, a brake malfunction is indicated by the brake lining not contacting the drum.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"If the governor fails to signal the compressor to cut-out what allows the excess air pressure to escape?","options":["The air dryer","A one way check valve","The low pressure warning system","A safety valve"],"correctAnswer":"A safety valve"},{"Question":"What does ABS stand for?","options":["Automatic Brake Stop","Automatic Braking System","Anti-lock Brake System","Accelerated Braking System"],"correctAnswer":"Anti-lock Brake System"},{"Question":"The size of an air brake chamber is based on the area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What happens when the trailer lines are not connected properly?","options":["Spring brakes may not release","The towing vehicle may lose air","Service brakes will not function properly","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Inspecting the brake components includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum","Damaged, missing or malfunctioning foundation brake components","Cracked, loose, missing or contaminated brake lining, improper drum contact or lining thickness that is less than required","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"The brake on each end of an axel should have a different sized air brake chamber to ensure brake forces are balanced.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What can cause damage or deterioration to brake hoses and tubes?","options":["Wear and cuts","Wear, cuts, and heat damage","Wear, cuts, abrasions, and heat damage","Abrasions and heat damage"],"correctAnswer":"Wear, cuts, abrasions, and heat damage"},{"Question":"Inspecting a vehicle\u2019s air brake chambers includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Audible air leaks","Cracks and non-manufactured holes","Brakes with different air brake chamber sizes on each end of a steering axle","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Where are air brake chambers located?","options":["At each wheel","At the drive wheels only","At the trailer wheels only","At both the drive and trailer wheels"],"correctAnswer":"At each wheel"},{"Question":"What is a reliable method for inspecting your brake adjustment?","options":["Measuring the applied pushrod stroke","Checking the slack adjustment","Checking the condition of the brake drum","Measuring the brake chamber size"],"correctAnswer":"Measuring the applied pushrod stroke"},{"Question":"What controls an air brake system\u2019s pressure range (cut-in and cut-out settings)?","options":["The governor","The compressor","The engine","The turbo-charger"],"correctAnswer":"The governor"},{"Question":"In Manitoba, who can perform brake adjustments on manual slack adjusters so the pushrod is less than the adjusted limit?","options":["A licensed driver with an A endorsement or a certified technician","A licensed driver with an S endorsement","The owner for the vehicle","A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"],"correctAnswer":"A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"},{"Question":"What can cause damage to the foundation brake components?","options":["Debris","Component failure","Deterioration","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What can cause damage or deterioration to brake hoses and tubes?","options":["Wear and cuts","Wear, cuts, and heat damage","Wear, cuts, abrasions, and heat damage","Abrasions and heat damage"],"correctAnswer":"Wear, cuts, abrasions, and heat damage"},{"Question":"Why should the gladhands be stored properly when not in use?","options":["To keep the seals from cracking","To make them easier to find next time they\u2019re needed","To keep them clean and in good condition","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To keep them clean and in good condition"},{"Question":"The air pressure must build from 85 psi to 100 psi in _______?","options":["30 seconds","One minute","Two minutes","Three minutes"],"correctAnswer":"Two minutes"},{"Question":"The safety valve will open to allow excess air pressure to escape at a level no higher than?","options":["140 psi","145 psi","150 psi","155 psi"],"correctAnswer":"150 psi"},{"Question":"The Highway Traffic Act and Regulations prohibit the operation of a vehicle with a brake that is out of adjustment.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When checking the air pressure buildup rate (compressor operation), what should the engine be idling between?","options":["200 - 500 rpm","500 - 800 rpm","600 - 900 rpm","900 - 1200 rpm"],"correctAnswer":"600 - 900 rpm"},{"Question":"Inspecting the brake components includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum","Damaged, missing or malfunctioning foundation brake components","Cracked, loose, missing or contaminated brake lining, improper drum contact or lining thickness that is less than required","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Why would a brake chamber need to be \'caged\'?","options":["To move the vehicle in an emergency","To allow for proper braking","To measure your pushrod travel","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To move the vehicle in an emergency"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the tractor protection valve?","options":["Prevents total air loss from the trailer if the trailer breaks away","Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away","Holds the supply line and emergency line in place not allowing them to break away","Prevents over pressure in the system allowing excess air to escape"],"correctAnswer":"Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away"},{"Question":"If any single brake malfunctions, what affect will it have on the other brakes?","options":["None","The malfunctioning brake will overheat causing damage","They will overheat quickly and possibly fail","The braking power will be slightly reduced"],"correctAnswer":"They will overheat quickly and possibly fail"},{"Question":"A brake chamber that includes both service brake and spring brake sections is called a:","options":["Brake chamber","Spring brake chamber","DD3 brake chamber","Service brake chamber"],"correctAnswer":"Spring brake chamber"},{"Question":"Vehicles with air brakes must comply with The Highway Traffic Act and Regulations. If a vehicle does not comply, both the driver and the operator may be charged.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"To ensure balanced braking, slack adjusters on each side of an axel should:","options":["Be the same effective lengths","Have no more than 1 inch difference","Be attached using different holes","Both B and C"],"correctAnswer":"Be the same effective lengths"},{"Question":"An inspection of a vehicle\u2019s brake drums and rotors includes checking for the following defect:","options":["Cracked or broken brake drums","Cracked or broken rotors","Both A and B","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Both A and B"},{"Question":"If air loss exceeds the maximum allowable limit specified for your vehicle, it would be considered a major defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"If air exhausts from the service line, it means that the trailer supply valve is defective.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Inspecting a vehicle\u2019s air brake chambers includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Audible air leaks","Cracks and non-manufactured holes","Brakes with different air brake chamber sizes on each end of a steering axle","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"If air exhausts from the service line, it means that the trailer supply valve is defective.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When checking the buildup rate (compressor operation) the engine should be building air pressure from _____ psi to ____ psi within two minutes:","options":["45 - 65","65 - 85","85 - 100","100 - 125"],"correctAnswer":"85 - 100"},{"Question":"When testing the tractor protection system, the trailer supply valve must close before the pressure drops below:","options":["20 psi","55 psi","60 psi","100 psi"],"correctAnswer":"20 psi"},{"Question":"Inspecting the air compressor includes checking for which defects?","options":["Loose air compressor drive belt pulley","Loose, cut or frayed air compressor drive belt","Insecure air compressor mounting, bracket or fasteners","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"If the compressor takes longer than two minutes to build air from 85 psi to 100 psi, it would be considered a major defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"The brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum is an example of:","options":["A foundation brake component defect","An issue with the brake chamber","An incorrectly measured pushrod","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"A foundation brake component defect"},{"Question":"Failure of the spring brakes to hold the vehicle stationary indicates defective service brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What are the three different types of foundation brake systems?","options":["\'S\' cam brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes","ABS brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes","ABS brakes, \'S\' cam brakes, and wedge brakes","\'S\' cam brakes, ABS brakes, and disc brakes"],"correctAnswer":"\'S\' cam brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes"},{"Question":"When testing brake performance (tug tests), it would be considered a major defect if:","options":["The spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle in place","The service brakes fail to stop the vehicle","Only if the tractor spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle","Both A and B"],"correctAnswer":"Both A and B"},{"Question":"What can indicate that an air tank or mounting bracket is not secure?","options":["Unusual movement","An air leak","A fluid leak","A deflated airbag"],"correctAnswer":"Unusual movement"},{"Question":"What should the air pressure be when performing a brake adjustment inspection at each wheel?","options":["Between 80 - 90 psi","Between 90 - 100 psi","Between 100 - 110 psi","At maximum pressure"],"correctAnswer":"Between 90 - 100 psi"},{"Question":"Damaged or worn air lines are not a concern until they have an obvious leak.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"A sudden increase in the amount of moisture or oil drained from any air-tank:","options":["Means the system is working correctly","Indicates the governor is faulty","Must be reported and repaired","Indicates an engine oil leak"],"correctAnswer":"Must be reported and repaired"},{"Question":"If any single brake malfunctions, what affect will it have on the other brakes?","options":["None","The malfunctioning brake will overheat causing damage","They will overheat quickly and possibly fail","The braking power will be slightly reduced"],"correctAnswer":"They will overheat quickly and possibly fail"},{"Question":"In order to make a service brake application?","options":["Pull the yellow button","Pull the red button","Push the brake pedal","Push the red and yellow buttons"],"correctAnswer":"Push the brake pedal"},{"Question":"Inspecting the vehicle\u2019s air lines includes checking for the following defects:","options":["Audible air leak","Damage or worn air lines","Improper fittings used to connect or repair an air line","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Wheels, dust shields, and other parts of the vehicle have no impact on your view of the brake drums and rotors.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When grease or oil is present on the brake lining:","options":["The brake lining is properly lubricated","Abnormal brake behaviour will result","The brake lining has been over-lubricated","The driver can continue to drive the vehicle as it will not cause any issues with brake function"],"correctAnswer":"Abnormal brake behaviour will result"},{"Question":"In Manitoba, who can perform brake adjustments on manual slack adjusters so the pushrod is less than the adjusted limit?","options":["A licensed driver with an A endorsement or a certified technician","A licensed driver with an S endorsement","The owner for the vehicle","A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"],"correctAnswer":"A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"},{"Question":"Testing the performance of your brakes requires performing separate tests of each braking system.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the governor?","options":["The governor causes the compressor to start and stop pumping air (cut-in and cut-out)","The governor controls the amount of moisture the air dryer removes from the system","Once air flows through the supply tank, the governor prevents it from returning","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"The governor causes the compressor to start and stop pumping air (cut-in and cut-out)"},{"Question":"What does the air compressor do?","options":["The air compressor draws power from the battery to power the vehicle","The air compressor builds air for the trailer only","The air compressor draws air in and forces it into a smaller space increasing air pressure","The air compressor removes moisture from the air brake system"],"correctAnswer":"The air compressor draws air in and forces it into a smaller space increasing air pressure"},{"Question":"There is often a noticeable change in the behaviour of brakes with drums or rotors that are defective, cracked or broken.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"If any single brake malfunctions, what affect will it have on the other brakes?","options":["None","The malfunctioning brake will overheat causing damage","They will overheat quickly and possibly fail","The braking power will be slightly reduced"],"correctAnswer":"They will overheat quickly and possibly fail"},{"Question":"When the pushrod stroke exceeds the adjustment limit of the brake chamber, the brake:","options":["Is out of adjustment","Is in adjustment","Needs to be replaced","Has a minor defect"],"correctAnswer":"Is out of adjustment"},{"Question":"The brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum is an example of:","options":["A foundation brake component defect","An issue with the brake chamber","An incorrectly measured pushrod","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"A foundation brake component defect"},{"Question":"What can cause damage or deterioration to brake hoses and tubes?","options":["Wear and cuts","Wear, cuts, and heat damage","Wear, cuts, abrasions, and heat damage","Abrasions and heat damage"],"correctAnswer":"Wear, cuts, abrasions, and heat damage"},{"Question":"When should the supply tank be drained?","options":["First","Last","In whatever order is most convenient for the driver","The supply tank should never be drained"],"correctAnswer":"First"},{"Question":"The engine must be running when testing the air-loss rate.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What happens if a single brake malfunctions?","options":["It puts more pressure on the other brakes","It causes the other brakes to quickly overheat","It could cause the other brakes to fail","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the tractor protection valve?","options":["Prevents total air loss from the trailer if the trailer breaks away","Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away","Holds the supply line and emergency line in place not allowing them to break away","Prevents over pressure in the system allowing excess air to escape"],"correctAnswer":"Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away"},{"Question":"When grease or oil is present on the brake lining:","options":["The brake lining is properly lubricated","Abnormal brake behaviour will result","The brake lining has been over-lubricated","The driver can continue to drive the vehicle as it will not cause any issues with brake function"],"correctAnswer":"Abnormal brake behaviour will result"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle\u2019s air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel exceeds the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This is:","options":["A minor defect","A major defect","Within the acceptable adjustment limit","Something to keep track of"],"correctAnswer":"A major defect"},{"Question":"If air loss exceeds the maximum allowable limit specified for your vehicle, it would be considered a major defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Air compressors can be inspected with the engine running or stopped.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"The size of an air brake chamber is based on the area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When testing the air-loss rate of the brake system, the brake application must be held for:","options":["30 seconds","One minute","Two minutes","Three minutes"],"correctAnswer":"One minute"},{"Question":"If the governor fails to signal the compressor to cut-out what allows the excess air pressure to escape?","options":["The air dryer","A one way check valve","The low pressure warning system","A safety valve"],"correctAnswer":"A safety valve"},{"Question":"The Highway Traffic Act and Regulations prohibit the operation of a vehicle with a brake that is out of adjustment.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not exceed:","options":["90 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"145 psi"},{"Question":"What does the air compressor do?","options":["The air compressor draws power from the battery to power the vehicle","The air compressor builds air for the trailer only","The air compressor draws air in and forces it into a smaller space increasing air pressure","The air compressor removes moisture from the air brake system"],"correctAnswer":"The air compressor draws air in and forces it into a smaller space increasing air pressure"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the safety valve?","options":["Starts building air pressure at 100 psi","Stops building air pressure at 140 psi","Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting","Ensures the trucks safety features are working correctly"],"correctAnswer":"Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting"},{"Question":"Automatic slack adjusters, if working properly, require regular re-adjustment.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What are the three different types of foundation brake systems?","options":["\'S\' cam brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes","ABS brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes","ABS brakes, \'S\' cam brakes, and wedge brakes","\'S\' cam brakes, ABS brakes, and disc brakes"],"correctAnswer":"\'S\' cam brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes"},{"Question":"What happens if a single brake malfunctions?","options":["It puts more pressure on the other brakes","It causes the other brakes to quickly overheat","It could cause the other brakes to fail","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the governor?","options":["The governor causes the compressor to start and stop pumping air (cut-in and cut-out)","The governor controls the amount of moisture the air dryer removes from the system","Once air flows through the supply tank, the governor prevents it from returning","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"The governor causes the compressor to start and stop pumping air (cut-in and cut-out)"},{"Question":"When damage extends into the reinforcing or inner layer, the air line is defective.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Inspecting the brake components includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum","Damaged, missing or malfunctioning foundation brake components","Cracked, loose, missing or contaminated brake lining, improper drum contact or lining thickness that is less than required","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel is within the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This:","options":["Is a minor defect","Is a major defect","Passes the inspection","Is a broken or defective part"],"correctAnswer":"Passes the inspection"},{"Question":"Who is responsible for ensuring air brakes are correctly adjusted?","options":["The employer","The manufacturer","The last person driving the vehicle","The current driver"],"correctAnswer":"The current driver"},{"Question":"Your spring brakes should be used when parking or in an emergency when your service brakes fail?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What can indicate that an air tank or mounting bracket is not secure?","options":["Unusual movement","An air leak","A fluid leak","A deflated airbag"],"correctAnswer":"Unusual movement"},{"Question":"When inspecting foundation brake components, the driver is expected to be able to identify brake components that are damaged, missing or malfunctioning.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Spring brakes use air to apply the brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When should the supply tank be drained?","options":["First","Last","In whatever order is most convenient for the driver","The supply tank should never be drained"],"correctAnswer":"First"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed in one minute on a tractor with two or more trailers?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","5 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"6 psi"},{"Question":"What happens when the trailer lines are not connected properly?","options":["Spring brakes may not release","The towing vehicle may lose air","Service brakes will not function properly","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Brake lining is defective when it is:","options":["Cracked","Missing","Loose","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"The brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum is an example of:","options":["A foundation brake component defect","An issue with the brake chamber","An incorrectly measured pushrod","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"A foundation brake component defect"},{"Question":"Older air systems may operate with lower pressure settings.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Operating a vehicle with defects or failing to conduct the required inspections can result in:","options":["Charges against the driver and/or operator","Detainment or impoundment of the vehicle","Fines","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What happens when the trailer lines are not connected properly?","options":["Spring brakes may not release","The towing vehicle may lose air","Service brakes will not function properly","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What can cause damage to the foundation brake components?","options":["Debris","Component failure","Deterioration","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"When testing the air-loss rate of the brake system, the brake application must be held for:","options":["30 seconds","One minute","Two minutes","Three minutes"],"correctAnswer":"One minute"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not be lower than:","options":["60 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"120 psi"},{"Question":"What is a reliable method for inspecting your brake adjustment?","options":["Measuring the applied pushrod stroke","Checking the slack adjustment","Checking the condition of the brake drum","Measuring the brake chamber size"],"correctAnswer":"Measuring the applied pushrod stroke"},{"Question":"Inspecting the air compressor includes checking for which defects?","options":["Loose air compressor drive belt pulley","Loose, cut or frayed air compressor drive belt","Insecure air compressor mounting, bracket or fasteners","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"If air pressure drops below the normal cut-in setting what should the driver do?","options":["Continue driving until the spring brakes apply","Make several full brake applications","Nothing","Bring the vehicle to a safe stop as soon as possible"],"correctAnswer":"Bring the vehicle to a safe stop as soon as possible"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed in one minute on a tractor with two or more trailers?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","5 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"6 psi"},{"Question":"When should the supply tank be drained?","options":["First","Last","In whatever order is most convenient for the driver","The supply tank should never be drained"],"correctAnswer":"First"},{"Question":"What should the air pressure be when performing a brake adjustment inspection at each wheel?","options":["Between 80 - 90 psi","Between 90 - 100 psi","Between 100 - 110 psi","At maximum pressure"],"correctAnswer":"Between 90 - 100 psi"},{"Question":"At what level must the low pressure warning device activate?","options":["At or above 60 psi","Between 40 - 50 psi","At or above 85 psi","At or above 55 psi"],"correctAnswer":"At or above 55 psi"},{"Question":"When grease or oil is present on the brake lining:","options":["The brake lining is properly lubricated","Abnormal brake behaviour will result","The brake lining has been over-lubricated","The driver can continue to drive the vehicle as it will not cause any issues with brake function"],"correctAnswer":"Abnormal brake behaviour will result"},{"Question":"The Highway Traffic Act and Regulations prohibit the operation of a vehicle with a brake that is out of adjustment.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Where are air brake chambers located?","options":["At each wheel","At the drive wheels only","At the trailer wheels only","At both the drive and trailer wheels"],"correctAnswer":"At each wheel"},{"Question":"Spring brakes use air to apply the brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Inspecting a vehicle\u2019s air brake chambers includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Audible air leaks","Cracks and non-manufactured holes","Brakes with different air brake chamber sizes on each end of a steering axle","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"A sudden increase in the amount of moisture or oil drained from any air-tank:","options":["Means the system is working correctly","Indicates the governor is faulty","Must be reported and repaired","Indicates an engine oil leak"],"correctAnswer":"Must be reported and repaired"},{"Question":"Actual cut-in pressure of the governor should never be less than:","options":["55 psi","80 psi","100 psi","120 psi"],"correctAnswer":"100 psi"},{"Question":"The engine must be running when testing the air-loss rate.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When the brakes are applied, a brake malfunction is indicated by the brake lining not contacting the drum.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not exceed:","options":["90 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"145 psi"},{"Question":"In Manitoba, who can perform brake adjustments on manual slack adjusters so the pushrod is less than the adjusted limit?","options":["A licensed driver with an A endorsement or a certified technician","A licensed driver with an S endorsement","The owner for the vehicle","A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"],"correctAnswer":"A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"},{"Question":"When testing the air-loss rate of the brake system, the brake pedal must be fully applied.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"In order to make a service brake application?","options":["Pull the yellow button","Pull the red button","Push the brake pedal","Push the red and yellow buttons"],"correctAnswer":"Push the brake pedal"},{"Question":"Inspecting the air compressor includes checking for which defects?","options":["Loose air compressor drive belt pulley","Loose, cut or frayed air compressor drive belt","Insecure air compressor mounting, bracket or fasteners","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"When inspecting foundation brake components, the driver is expected to be able to identify brake components that are damaged, missing or malfunctioning.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"At what pressure do the spring brakes normally start to apply because there is no longer enough pressure to keep them released?","options":["20 psi","40 psi","60 psi","85 psi"],"correctAnswer":"60 psi"},{"Question":"The brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum is an example of:","options":["A foundation brake component defect","An issue with the brake chamber","An incorrectly measured pushrod","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"A foundation brake component defect"},{"Question":"There is often a noticeable change in the behaviour of brakes with drums or rotors that are defective, cracked or broken.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When conducting an inspection of the air brake system, be sure to:","options":["Park the vehicle on level ground","Park the vehicle away from traffic","Turn the engine off","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What safety equipment is recommended while conducting an air brake inspection?","options":["Fire extinguisher, safety glasses, and  protective footwear","Safety glasses, protective headgear, and protective footwear","Protective headgear, ear plugs, and safety glasses","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Safety glasses, protective headgear, and protective footwear"},{"Question":"How can air brake chamber air leaks usually be detected?","options":["Visually","Audibly","By checking pushrod travel distance","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Audibly"},{"Question":"Wheels, dust shields, and other parts of the vehicle have no impact on your view of the brake drums and rotors.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Actual cut-in pressure for the governor should never be less than 90 PSI?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Why should the gladhands be stored properly when not in use?","options":["To keep the seals from cracking","To make them easier to find next time they\u2019re needed","To keep them clean and in good condition","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To keep them clean and in good condition"},{"Question":"Brake lining is defective when it is:","options":["Cracked","Missing","Loose","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"If the low air-pressure warning device activates below 55 psi, this would be considered a minor defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When damage extends into the reinforcing or inner layer, the air line is defective.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed in one minute on a tractor with two or more trailers?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","5 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"6 psi"},{"Question":"Testing the performance of your brakes requires performing separate tests of each braking system.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When testing the air-loss rate of the brake system, the brake pedal must be fully applied.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What happens if a single brake malfunctions?","options":["It puts more pressure on the other brakes","It causes the other brakes to quickly overheat","It could cause the other brakes to fail","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What do anti-lock braking systems (ABS) do?","options":["Help maintain steering control during emergency braking","Help prevent wheel lock","Do not shorten the stopping distance","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"If air exhausts from the service line, it means that the trailer supply valve is defective.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Brake lining is defective when it is:","options":["Cracked","Missing","Loose","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"If you double your vehicle weight and double your speed, what does your stopping distance increase by?","options":["Four times","Six times","Eight times","Ten times"],"correctAnswer":"Eight times"},{"Question":"If the governor fails to signal the compressor to cut-out what allows the excess air pressure to escape?","options":["The air dryer","A one way check valve","The low pressure warning system","A safety valve"],"correctAnswer":"A safety valve"},{"Question":"If air pressure drops below the normal cut-in setting what should the driver do?","options":["Continue driving until the spring brakes apply","Make several full brake applications","Nothing","Bring the vehicle to a safe stop as soon as possible"],"correctAnswer":"Bring the vehicle to a safe stop as soon as possible"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed when testing the air-loss rate of the brake system on a tractor and trailer?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","6 psi","10 psi"],"correctAnswer":"4 psi"},{"Question":"When should the supply tank be drained?","options":["First","Last","In whatever order is most convenient for the driver","The supply tank should never be drained"],"correctAnswer":"First"},{"Question":"When testing the low air-pressure warning device, the engine can be stopped or running but the ignition must be on.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What can indicate that an air tank or mounting bracket is not secure?","options":["Unusual movement","An air leak","A fluid leak","A deflated airbag"],"correctAnswer":"Unusual movement"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the governor?","options":["The governor causes the compressor to start and stop pumping air (cut-in and cut-out)","The governor controls the amount of moisture the air dryer removes from the system","Once air flows through the supply tank, the governor prevents it from returning","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"The governor causes the compressor to start and stop pumping air (cut-in and cut-out)"},{"Question":"Inspecting a vehicle\u2019s air brake chambers includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Audible air leaks","Cracks and non-manufactured holes","Brakes with different air brake chamber sizes on each end of a steering axle","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Damaged or worn air lines are not a concern until they have an obvious leak.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"For the brakes to work, the brake-shoe lining must be greased and pressed against the brake drum when the brakes are applied.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"As brakes heat up, you may experience a reduction in their effectiveness. This is known as:","options":["ABS brakes","Anti-lock braking","Brake fade","Combination braking"],"correctAnswer":"Brake fade"},{"Question":"Failure of the spring brakes to hold the vehicle stationary indicates defective service brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When testing the low air-pressure warning device, the engine can be stopped or running but the ignition must be on.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"An inspection of a vehicle\u2019s brake drums and rotors includes checking for the following defect:","options":["Cracked or broken brake drums","Cracked or broken rotors","Both A and B","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Both A and B"},{"Question":"Vehicles with air brakes must comply with The Highway Traffic Act and Regulations. If a vehicle does not comply, both the driver and the operator may be charged.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle\u2019s air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel exceeds the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This is:","options":["A minor defect","A major defect","Within the acceptable adjustment limit","Something to keep track of"],"correctAnswer":"A major defect"},{"Question":"When the brakes are applied, a brake malfunction is indicated by the brake lining not contacting the drum.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When checking the buildup rate (compressor operation) the engine should be building air pressure from _____ psi to ____ psi within two minutes:","options":["45 - 65","65 - 85","85 - 100","100 - 125"],"correctAnswer":"85 - 100"},{"Question":"The brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum is an example of:","options":["A foundation brake component defect","An issue with the brake chamber","An incorrectly measured pushrod","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"A foundation brake component defect"},{"Question":"If you double your vehicle weight and double your speed, what does your stopping distance increase by?","options":["Four times","Six times","Eight times","Ten times"],"correctAnswer":"Eight times"},{"Question":"How would you know if the anti-lock braking system had a malfunction?","options":["The brakes won\'t function at all","The brakes will function intermittently","Only the trailer hand valve functions","The ABS malfunction warning light illuminates"],"correctAnswer":"The ABS malfunction warning light illuminates"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not be lower than:","options":["60 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"120 psi"},{"Question":"If air exhausts from the service line, it means that the trailer supply valve is defective.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Automatic slack adjusters, if working properly, require regular re-adjustment.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When testing the tractor protection system, the trailer supply valve must close before the pressure drops below:","options":["20 psi","55 psi","60 psi","100 psi"],"correctAnswer":"20 psi"},{"Question":"When conducting an inspection of the air brake system, be sure to:","options":["Park the vehicle on level ground","Park the vehicle away from traffic","Turn the engine off","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Why are automatic slack adjusters used?","options":["They make inspections and adjustments unnecessary","As a backup to a manual slack adjuster","To avoid the need to regularly perform manual re-adjustments","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To avoid the need to regularly perform manual re-adjustments"},{"Question":"There is often a noticeable change in the behaviour of brakes with drums or rotors that are defective, cracked or broken.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Brake lining is defective when it is:","options":["Cracked","Missing","Loose","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the safety valve?","options":["Starts building air pressure at 100 psi","Stops building air pressure at 140 psi","Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting","Ensures the trucks safety features are working correctly"],"correctAnswer":"Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting"},{"Question":"Inspecting the brake components includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum","Damaged, missing or malfunctioning foundation brake components","Cracked, loose, missing or contaminated brake lining, improper drum contact or lining thickness that is less than required","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Spring brakes use air to apply the brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Why would a brake chamber need to be \'caged\'?","options":["To move the vehicle in an emergency","To allow for proper braking","To measure your pushrod travel","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To move the vehicle in an emergency"},{"Question":"How can air brake chamber air leaks usually be detected?","options":["Visually","Audibly","By checking pushrod travel distance","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Audibly"},{"Question":"The Highway Traffic Act and Regulations prohibit the operation of a vehicle with a brake that is out of adjustment.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Spring brakes use air to apply the brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What controls an air brake system\u2019s pressure range (cut-in and cut-out settings)?","options":["The governor","The compressor","The engine","The turbo-charger"],"correctAnswer":"The governor"},{"Question":"When inspecting foundation brake components, the driver is expected to be able to identify brake components that are damaged, missing or malfunctioning.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What can cause damage to the foundation brake components?","options":["Debris","Component failure","Deterioration","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the tractor protection valve?","options":["Prevents total air loss from the trailer if the trailer breaks away","Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away","Holds the supply line and emergency line in place not allowing them to break away","Prevents over pressure in the system allowing excess air to escape"],"correctAnswer":"Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the governor?","options":["The governor causes the compressor to start and stop pumping air (cut-in and cut-out)","The governor controls the amount of moisture the air dryer removes from the system","Once air flows through the supply tank, the governor prevents it from returning","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"The governor causes the compressor to start and stop pumping air (cut-in and cut-out)"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed when testing the air-loss rate of the brake system on a tractor and trailer?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","6 psi","10 psi"],"correctAnswer":"4 psi"},{"Question":"What does ABS stand for?","options":["Automatic Brake Stop","Automatic Braking System","Anti-lock Brake System","Accelerated Braking System"],"correctAnswer":"Anti-lock Brake System"},{"Question":"As brakes heat up, you may experience a reduction in their effectiveness. This is known as:","options":["ABS brakes","Anti-lock braking","Brake fade","Combination braking"],"correctAnswer":"Brake fade"},{"Question":"When the pushrod stroke exceeds the adjustment limit of the brake chamber, the brake:","options":["Is out of adjustment","Is in adjustment","Needs to be replaced","Has a minor defect"],"correctAnswer":"Is out of adjustment"},{"Question":"Wheels, dust shields, and other parts of the vehicle have no impact on your view of the brake drums and rotors.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When the brakes are applied, a brake malfunction is indicated by the brake lining not contacting the drum.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"The engine must be running when testing the air-loss rate.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What safety equipment is recommended while conducting an air brake inspection?","options":["Fire extinguisher, safety glasses, and  protective footwear","Safety glasses, protective headgear, and protective footwear","Protective headgear, ear plugs, and safety glasses","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Safety glasses, protective headgear, and protective footwear"},{"Question":"What should you do before you exit the vehicle or get underneath it?","options":["Start the vehicle","Secure the vehicle","Grab your safety equipment","Turn off the vehicle"],"correctAnswer":"Secure the vehicle"},{"Question":"When testing brake performance (tug tests), it would be considered a major defect if:","options":["The spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle in place","The service brakes fail to stop the vehicle","Only if the tractor spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle","Both A and B"],"correctAnswer":"Both A and B"},{"Question":"At what level must the low pressure warning device activate?","options":["At or above 60 psi","Between 40 - 50 psi","At or above 85 psi","At or above 55 psi"],"correctAnswer":"At or above 55 psi"},{"Question":"In order to make a service brake application?","options":["Pull the yellow button","Pull the red button","Push the brake pedal","Push the red and yellow buttons"],"correctAnswer":"Push the brake pedal"},{"Question":"What does ABS stand for?","options":["Automatic Brake Stop","Automatic Braking System","Anti-lock Brake System","Accelerated Braking System"],"correctAnswer":"Anti-lock Brake System"},{"Question":"What happens when the trailer lines are not connected properly?","options":["Spring brakes may not release","The towing vehicle may lose air","Service brakes will not function properly","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What can cause damage to the foundation brake components?","options":["Debris","Component failure","Deterioration","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"An inspection of a vehicle\u2019s brake drums and rotors includes checking for the following defect:","options":["Cracked or broken brake drums","Cracked or broken rotors","Both A and B","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Both A and B"},{"Question":"Inspecting a vehicle\u2019s air lines includes checking for the following defects:","options":["Audible air leak","Damaged or worn air lines","Improper fittings used to connect or repair air lines","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel is within the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This:","options":["Is a minor defect","Is a major defect","Passes the inspection","Is a broken or defective part"],"correctAnswer":"Passes the inspection"},{"Question":"What can cause damage or deterioration to brake hoses and tubes?","options":["Wear and cuts","Wear, cuts, and heat damage","Wear, cuts, abrasions, and heat damage","Abrasions and heat damage"],"correctAnswer":"Wear, cuts, abrasions, and heat damage"},{"Question":"The safety valve will open to allow excess air pressure to escape at a level no higher than?","options":["140 psi","145 psi","150 psi","155 psi"],"correctAnswer":"150 psi"},{"Question":"When testing the air-loss rate of the brake system, the brake application must be held for:","options":["30 seconds","One minute","Two minutes","Three minutes"],"correctAnswer":"One minute"},{"Question":"Air compressors can be inspected with the engine running or stopped.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"As brakes heat up, you may experience a reduction in their effectiveness. This is known as:","options":["ABS brakes","Anti-lock braking","Brake fade","Combination braking"],"correctAnswer":"Brake fade"},{"Question":"Actual cut-in pressure of the governor should never be less than:","options":["55 psi","80 psi","100 psi","120 psi"],"correctAnswer":"100 psi"},{"Question":"Failure of the spring brakes to hold the vehicle stationary indicates defective service brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When testing the tractor protection system, the trailer supply valve must close before the pressure drops below:","options":["20 psi","55 psi","60 psi","100 psi"],"correctAnswer":"20 psi"},{"Question":"Operating a vehicle with defects or failing to conduct the required inspections can result in:","options":["Charges against the driver and/or operator","Detainment or impoundment of the vehicle","Fines","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the safety valve?","options":["Starts building air pressure at 100 psi","Stops building air pressure at 140 psi","Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting","Ensures the trucks safety features are working correctly"],"correctAnswer":"Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not exceed:","options":["90 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"145 psi"},{"Question":"If the low air-pressure warning device activates below 55 psi, this would be considered a minor defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"On a straight truck, tractor, or bus air loss test, what is the acceptable amount of air loss allowed within one minute?","options":["2 psi","3 psi","4 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"3 psi"},{"Question":"If you double your vehicle weight and double your speed, what does your stopping distance increase by?","options":["Four times","Six times","Eight times","Ten times"],"correctAnswer":"Eight times"},{"Question":"A sudden increase in the amount of moisture or oil drained from any air-tank:","options":["Means the system is working correctly","Indicates the governor is faulty","Must be reported and repaired","Indicates an engine oil leak"],"correctAnswer":"Must be reported and repaired"},{"Question":"Failure of the spring brakes to hold the vehicle stationary indicates defective service brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Inspecting a vehicle\u2019s air brake chambers includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Audible air leaks","Cracks and non-manufactured holes","Brakes with different air brake chamber sizes on each end of a steering axle","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Why are automatic slack adjusters used?","options":["They make inspections and adjustments unnecessary","As a backup to a manual slack adjuster","To avoid the need to regularly perform manual re-adjustments","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To avoid the need to regularly perform manual re-adjustments"},{"Question":"What can cause damage or deterioration to brake hoses and tubes?","options":["Wear and cuts","Wear, cuts, and heat damage","Wear, cuts, abrasions, and heat damage","Abrasions and heat damage"],"correctAnswer":"Wear, cuts, abrasions, and heat damage"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the governor?","options":["The governor causes the compressor to start and stop pumping air (cut-in and cut-out)","The governor controls the amount of moisture the air dryer removes from the system","Once air flows through the supply tank, the governor prevents it from returning","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"The governor causes the compressor to start and stop pumping air (cut-in and cut-out)"},{"Question":"On a straight truck, tractor, or bus air loss test, what is the acceptable amount of air loss allowed within one minute?","options":["2 psi","3 psi","4 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"3 psi"},{"Question":"There is often a noticeable change in the behaviour of brakes with drums or rotors that are defective, cracked or broken.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When inspecting foundation brake components, the driver is expected to be able to identify brake components that are damaged, missing or malfunctioning.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"An inspection of a vehicle\u2019s brake drums and rotors includes checking for the following defect:","options":["Cracked or broken brake drums","Cracked or broken rotors","Both A and B","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Both A and B"},{"Question":"When testing the air-loss rate of the brake system, the brake application must be held for:","options":["30 seconds","One minute","Two minutes","Three minutes"],"correctAnswer":"One minute"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed when testing the air-loss rate of the brake system on a tractor and trailer?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","6 psi","10 psi"],"correctAnswer":"4 psi"},{"Question":"When testing the air-loss rate of the brake system, the brake pedal must be fully applied.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle\u2019s air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel exceeds the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This is:","options":["A minor defect","A major defect","Within the acceptable adjustment limit","Something to keep track of"],"correctAnswer":"A major defect"},{"Question":"Damaged or worn air lines are not a concern until they have an obvious leak.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What is a reliable method for inspecting your brake adjustment?","options":["Measuring the applied pushrod stroke","Checking the slack adjustment","Checking the condition of the brake drum","Measuring the brake chamber size"],"correctAnswer":"Measuring the applied pushrod stroke"},{"Question":"Who is responsible for ensuring air brakes are correctly adjusted?","options":["The employer","The manufacturer","The last person driving the vehicle","The current driver"],"correctAnswer":"The current driver"},{"Question":"When checking the buildup rate (compressor operation) the engine should be building air pressure from _____ psi to ____ psi within two minutes:","options":["45 - 65","65 - 85","85 - 100","100 - 125"],"correctAnswer":"85 - 100"},{"Question":"Where are air brake chambers located?","options":["At each wheel","At the drive wheels only","At the trailer wheels only","At both the drive and trailer wheels"],"correctAnswer":"At each wheel"},{"Question":"What is the size of an air brake chamber based on?","options":["The type of chamber","The area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches","The pushrod travel distance","The make and model of the vehicle"],"correctAnswer":"The area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches"},{"Question":"If air exhausts from the service line, it means that the trailer supply valve is defective.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What is a reliable method for inspecting your brake adjustment?","options":["Measuring the applied pushrod stroke","Checking the slack adjustment","Checking the condition of the brake drum","Measuring the brake chamber size"],"correctAnswer":"Measuring the applied pushrod stroke"},{"Question":"What does the air compressor do?","options":["The air compressor draws power from the battery to power the vehicle","The air compressor builds air for the trailer only","The air compressor draws air in and forces it into a smaller space increasing air pressure","The air compressor removes moisture from the air brake system"],"correctAnswer":"The air compressor draws air in and forces it into a smaller space increasing air pressure"},{"Question":"The air pressure must build from 85 psi to 100 psi in _______?","options":["30 seconds","One minute","Two minutes","Three minutes"],"correctAnswer":"Two minutes"},{"Question":"When testing brake performance (tug tests), it would be considered a major defect if:","options":["The spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle in place","The service brakes fail to stop the vehicle","Only if the tractor spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle","Both A and B"],"correctAnswer":"Both A and B"},{"Question":"On a straight truck, tractor, or bus air loss test, what is the acceptable amount of air loss allowed within one minute?","options":["2 psi","3 psi","4 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"3 psi"},{"Question":"Actual cut-in pressure for the governor should never be less than 90 PSI?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed when testing the air-loss rate of the brake system on a tractor and trailer?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","6 psi","10 psi"],"correctAnswer":"4 psi"},{"Question":"What does ABS stand for?","options":["Automatic Brake Stop","Automatic Braking System","Anti-lock Brake System","Accelerated Braking System"],"correctAnswer":"Anti-lock Brake System"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not be lower than:","options":["60 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"120 psi"},{"Question":"The first air tank that air enters is called the supply (wet tank).","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"If the compressor takes longer than two minutes to build air from 85 psi to 100 psi, it would be considered a major defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Inspecting the air compressor includes checking for which defects?","options":["Loose air compressor drive belt pulley","Loose, cut or frayed air compressor drive belt","Insecure air compressor mounting, bracket or fasteners","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Wheels, dust shields, and other parts of the vehicle have no impact on your view of the brake drums and rotors.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"For the brakes to work, the brake-shoe lining must be greased and pressed against the brake drum when the brakes are applied.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"The brake on each end of an axel should have a different sized air brake chamber to ensure brake forces are balanced.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed in one minute on a tractor with two or more trailers?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","5 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"6 psi"},{"Question":"When testing the compressor, if there is a trailer attached, the trailer supply valve must be closed.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"If the low air-pressure warning device activates below 55 psi, this would be considered a minor defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What can indicate that an air tank or mounting bracket is not secure?","options":["Unusual movement","An air leak","A fluid leak","A deflated airbag"],"correctAnswer":"Unusual movement"},{"Question":"When testing brake performance (tug tests), it would be considered a major defect if:","options":["The spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle in place","The service brakes fail to stop the vehicle","Only if the tractor spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle","Both A and B"],"correctAnswer":"Both A and B"},{"Question":"When testing the tractor protection system, the trailer supply valve must close before the pressure drops below:","options":["20 psi","55 psi","60 psi","100 psi"],"correctAnswer":"20 psi"},{"Question":"At what level must the low pressure warning device activate?","options":["At or above 60 psi","Between 40 - 50 psi","At or above 85 psi","At or above 55 psi"],"correctAnswer":"At or above 55 psi"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed when testing the air-loss rate of the brake system on a tractor and trailer?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","6 psi","10 psi"],"correctAnswer":"4 psi"},{"Question":"Actual cut-in pressure for the governor should never be less than 90 PSI?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"If air pressure drops below the normal cut-in setting what should the driver do?","options":["Continue driving until the spring brakes apply","Make several full brake applications","Nothing","Bring the vehicle to a safe stop as soon as possible"],"correctAnswer":"Bring the vehicle to a safe stop as soon as possible"},{"Question":"Why would a brake chamber need to be \'caged\'?","options":["To move the vehicle in an emergency","To allow for proper braking","To measure your pushrod travel","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To move the vehicle in an emergency"},{"Question":"If the compressor takes longer than two minutes to build air from 85 psi to 100 psi, it would be considered a major defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"In Manitoba, who can perform brake adjustments on manual slack adjusters so the pushrod is less than the adjusted limit?","options":["A licensed driver with an A endorsement or a certified technician","A licensed driver with an S endorsement","The owner for the vehicle","A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"],"correctAnswer":"A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"},{"Question":"The size of an air brake chamber is based on the area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Where are air brake chambers located?","options":["At each wheel","At the drive wheels only","At the trailer wheels only","At both the drive and trailer wheels"],"correctAnswer":"At each wheel"},{"Question":"Operating a vehicle with defects or failing to conduct the required inspections can result in:","options":["Charges against the driver and/or operator","Detainment or impoundment of the vehicle","Fines","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"The safety valve will open to allow excess air pressure to escape at a level no higher than?","options":["140 psi","145 psi","150 psi","155 psi"],"correctAnswer":"150 psi"},{"Question":"Inspecting the vehicle\u2019s air lines includes checking for the following defects:","options":["Audible air leak","Damage or worn air lines","Improper fittings used to connect or repair an air line","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Inspecting the air compressor includes checking for which defects?","options":["Loose air compressor drive belt pulley","Loose, cut or frayed air compressor drive belt","Insecure air compressor mounting, bracket or fasteners","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What can cause damage or deterioration to brake hoses and tubes?","options":["Wear and cuts","Wear, cuts, and heat damage","Wear, cuts, abrasions, and heat damage","Abrasions and heat damage"],"correctAnswer":"Wear, cuts, abrasions, and heat damage"},{"Question":"Air brake chambers from different manufacturers may look different even if they are the same size.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"If air loss exceeds the maximum allowable limit specified for your vehicle, it would be considered a major defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Why are automatic slack adjusters used?","options":["They make inspections and adjustments unnecessary","As a backup to a manual slack adjuster","To avoid the need to regularly perform manual re-adjustments","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To avoid the need to regularly perform manual re-adjustments"},{"Question":"At what pressure do the spring brakes normally start to apply because there is no longer enough pressure to keep them released?","options":["20 psi","40 psi","60 psi","85 psi"],"correctAnswer":"60 psi"},{"Question":"The first air tank that air enters is called the supply (wet tank).","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What do anti-lock braking systems (ABS) do?","options":["Help maintain steering control during emergency braking","Help prevent wheel lock","Do not shorten the stopping distance","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"When conducting an inspection of the air brake system, be sure to:","options":["Park the vehicle on level ground","Park the vehicle away from traffic","Turn the engine off","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Operating a vehicle with defects or failing to conduct the required inspections can result in:","options":["Charges against the driver and/or operator","Detainment or impoundment of the vehicle","Fines","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"The Highway Traffic Act and Regulations prohibit the operation of a vehicle with a brake that is out of adjustment.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Testing the performance of your brakes requires performing separate tests of each braking system.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"As brakes heat up, you may experience a reduction in their effectiveness. This is known as:","options":["ABS brakes","Anti-lock braking","Brake fade","Combination braking"],"correctAnswer":"Brake fade"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel is within the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This:","options":["Is a minor defect","Is a major defect","Passes the inspection","Is a broken or defective part"],"correctAnswer":"Passes the inspection"},{"Question":"Inspecting a vehicle\u2019s air lines includes checking for the following defects:","options":["Audible air leak","Damaged or worn air lines","Improper fittings used to connect or repair air lines","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle\u2019s air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel exceeds the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This is:","options":["A minor defect","A major defect","Within the acceptable adjustment limit","Something to keep track of"],"correctAnswer":"A major defect"},{"Question":"Who is responsible for ensuring air brakes are correctly adjusted?","options":["The employer","The manufacturer","The last person driving the vehicle","The current driver"],"correctAnswer":"The current driver"},{"Question":"If air pressure drops below the normal cut-in setting what should the driver do?","options":["Continue driving until the spring brakes apply","Make several full brake applications","Nothing","Bring the vehicle to a safe stop as soon as possible"],"correctAnswer":"Bring the vehicle to a safe stop as soon as possible"},{"Question":"Inspecting the vehicle\u2019s air lines includes checking for the following defects:","options":["Audible air leak","Damage or worn air lines","Improper fittings used to connect or repair an air line","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed in one minute on a tractor with two or more trailers?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","5 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"6 psi"},{"Question":"What happens if a single brake malfunctions?","options":["It puts more pressure on the other brakes","It causes the other brakes to quickly overheat","It could cause the other brakes to fail","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"When damage extends into the reinforcing or inner layer, the air line is defective.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"If you double your vehicle weight and double your speed, what does your stopping distance increase by?","options":["Four times","Six times","Eight times","Ten times"],"correctAnswer":"Eight times"},{"Question":"Why would a brake chamber need to be \'caged\'?","options":["To move the vehicle in an emergency","To allow for proper braking","To measure your pushrod travel","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To move the vehicle in an emergency"},{"Question":"Damaged or worn air lines are not a concern until they have an obvious leak.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When testing the tractor protection system, the trailer supply valve must close before the pressure drops below:","options":["20 psi","55 psi","60 psi","100 psi"],"correctAnswer":"20 psi"},{"Question":"Inspecting a vehicle\u2019s air brake chambers includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Audible air leaks","Cracks and non-manufactured holes","Brakes with different air brake chamber sizes on each end of a steering axle","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What does the air compressor do?","options":["The air compressor draws power from the battery to power the vehicle","The air compressor builds air for the trailer only","The air compressor draws air in and forces it into a smaller space increasing air pressure","The air compressor removes moisture from the air brake system"],"correctAnswer":"The air compressor draws air in and forces it into a smaller space increasing air pressure"},{"Question":"When the brakes are applied, a brake malfunction is indicated by the brake lining not contacting the drum.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What should the air pressure be when performing a brake adjustment inspection at each wheel?","options":["Between 80 - 90 psi","Between 90 - 100 psi","Between 100 - 110 psi","At maximum pressure"],"correctAnswer":"Between 90 - 100 psi"},{"Question":"Inspecting the brake components includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum","Damaged, missing or malfunctioning foundation brake components","Cracked, loose, missing or contaminated brake lining, improper drum contact or lining thickness that is less than required","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What is a reliable method for inspecting your brake adjustment?","options":["Measuring the applied pushrod stroke","Checking the slack adjustment","Checking the condition of the brake drum","Measuring the brake chamber size"],"correctAnswer":"Measuring the applied pushrod stroke"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel is within the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This:","options":["Is a minor defect","Is a major defect","Passes the inspection","Is a broken or defective part"],"correctAnswer":"Passes the inspection"},{"Question":"If any single brake malfunctions, what affect will it have on the other brakes?","options":["None","The malfunctioning brake will overheat causing damage","They will overheat quickly and possibly fail","The braking power will be slightly reduced"],"correctAnswer":"They will overheat quickly and possibly fail"},{"Question":"A sudden increase in the amount of moisture or oil drained from any air-tank:","options":["Means the system is working correctly","Indicates the governor is faulty","Must be reported and repaired","Indicates an engine oil leak"],"correctAnswer":"Must be reported and repaired"},{"Question":"What happens if a single brake malfunctions?","options":["It puts more pressure on the other brakes","It causes the other brakes to quickly overheat","It could cause the other brakes to fail","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"In Manitoba, who can perform brake adjustments on manual slack adjusters so the pushrod is less than the adjusted limit?","options":["A licensed driver with an A endorsement or a certified technician","A licensed driver with an S endorsement","The owner for the vehicle","A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"],"correctAnswer":"A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"},{"Question":"When testing the compressor, if there is a trailer attached, the trailer supply valve must be closed.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"A spring brake control valve is usually yellow?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What do anti-lock braking systems (ABS) do?","options":["Help maintain steering control during emergency braking","Help prevent wheel lock","Do not shorten the stopping distance","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"When testing the low air-pressure warning device, the engine can be stopped or running but the ignition must be on.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"The brake on each end of an axel should have a different sized air brake chamber to ensure brake forces are balanced.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"At what level must the low pressure warning device activate?","options":["At or above 60 psi","Between 40 - 50 psi","At or above 85 psi","At or above 55 psi"],"correctAnswer":"At or above 55 psi"},{"Question":"Actual cut-in pressure of the governor should never be less than:","options":["55 psi","80 psi","100 psi","120 psi"],"correctAnswer":"100 psi"},{"Question":"If you double your vehicle weight and double your speed, what does your stopping distance increase by?","options":["Four times","Six times","Eight times","Ten times"],"correctAnswer":"Eight times"},{"Question":"When testing brake performance (tug tests), it would be considered a major defect if:","options":["The spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle in place","The service brakes fail to stop the vehicle","Only if the tractor spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle","Both A and B"],"correctAnswer":"Both A and B"},{"Question":"When inspecting foundation brake components, the driver is expected to be able to identify brake components that are damaged, missing or malfunctioning.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Where are air brake chambers located?","options":["At each wheel","At the drive wheels only","At the trailer wheels only","At both the drive and trailer wheels"],"correctAnswer":"At each wheel"},{"Question":"In order to make a service brake application?","options":["Pull the yellow button","Pull the red button","Push the brake pedal","Push the red and yellow buttons"],"correctAnswer":"Push the brake pedal"},{"Question":"Inspecting the air compressor includes checking for which defects?","options":["Loose air compressor drive belt pulley","Loose, cut or frayed air compressor drive belt","Insecure air compressor mounting, bracket or fasteners","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"If the compressor takes longer than two minutes to build air from 85 psi to 100 psi, it would be considered a major defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When testing the compressor, if there is a trailer attached, the trailer supply valve must be closed.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What can cause damage or deterioration to brake hoses and tubes?","options":["Wear and cuts","Wear, cuts, and heat damage","Wear, cuts, abrasions, and heat damage","Abrasions and heat damage"],"correctAnswer":"Wear, cuts, abrasions, and heat damage"},{"Question":"The first air tank that air enters is called the supply (wet tank).","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What safety equipment is recommended while conducting an air brake inspection?","options":["Fire extinguisher, safety glasses, and  protective footwear","Safety glasses, protective headgear, and protective footwear","Protective headgear, ear plugs, and safety glasses","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Safety glasses, protective headgear, and protective footwear"},{"Question":"If you double your vehicle weight and double your speed, what does your stopping distance increase by?","options":["Four times","Six times","Eight times","Ten times"],"correctAnswer":"Eight times"},{"Question":"Testing the performance of your brakes requires performing separate tests of each braking system.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel is within the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This:","options":["Is a minor defect","Is a major defect","Passes the inspection","Is a broken or defective part"],"correctAnswer":"Passes the inspection"},{"Question":"Actual cut-in pressure of the governor should never be less than:","options":["55 psi","80 psi","100 psi","120 psi"],"correctAnswer":"100 psi"},{"Question":"Inspecting the vehicle\u2019s air lines includes checking for the following defects:","options":["Audible air leak","Damage or worn air lines","Improper fittings used to connect or repair an air line","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"If air exhausts from the service line, it means that the trailer supply valve is defective.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When testing the air-loss rate of the brake system, the brake application must be held for:","options":["30 seconds","One minute","Two minutes","Three minutes"],"correctAnswer":"One minute"},{"Question":"When conducting an inspection of the air brake system, be sure to:","options":["Park the vehicle on level ground","Park the vehicle away from traffic","Turn the engine off","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What do anti-lock braking systems (ABS) do?","options":["Help maintain steering control during emergency braking","Help prevent wheel lock","Do not shorten the stopping distance","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"When damage extends into the reinforcing or inner layer, the air line is defective.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When conducting an inspection of the air brake system, be sure to:","options":["Park the vehicle on level ground","Park the vehicle away from traffic","Turn the engine off","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"If any single brake malfunctions, what affect will it have on the other brakes?","options":["None","The malfunctioning brake will overheat causing damage","They will overheat quickly and possibly fail","The braking power will be slightly reduced"],"correctAnswer":"They will overheat quickly and possibly fail"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the tractor protection valve?","options":["Prevents total air loss from the trailer if the trailer breaks away","Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away","Holds the supply line and emergency line in place not allowing them to break away","Prevents over pressure in the system allowing excess air to escape"],"correctAnswer":"Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away"},{"Question":"What happens if a single brake malfunctions?","options":["It puts more pressure on the other brakes","It causes the other brakes to quickly overheat","It could cause the other brakes to fail","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"When testing the tractor protection system, the trailer supply valve must close before the pressure drops below:","options":["20 psi","55 psi","60 psi","100 psi"],"correctAnswer":"20 psi"},{"Question":"When grease or oil is present on the brake lining:","options":["The brake lining is properly lubricated","Abnormal brake behaviour will result","The brake lining has been over-lubricated","The driver can continue to drive the vehicle as it will not cause any issues with brake function"],"correctAnswer":"Abnormal brake behaviour will result"},{"Question":"How often is it recommended that the air tanks be drained?","options":["At the beginning of every trip","At the end of every trip","Every day","Once a week"],"correctAnswer":"Every day"},{"Question":"Failure of the spring brakes to hold the vehicle stationary indicates defective service brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What can cause damage or deterioration to brake hoses and tubes?","options":["Wear and cuts","Wear, cuts, and heat damage","Wear, cuts, abrasions, and heat damage","Abrasions and heat damage"],"correctAnswer":"Wear, cuts, abrasions, and heat damage"},{"Question":"Why are automatic slack adjusters used?","options":["They make inspections and adjustments unnecessary","As a backup to a manual slack adjuster","To avoid the need to regularly perform manual re-adjustments","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To avoid the need to regularly perform manual re-adjustments"},{"Question":"The vehicle must be secured by the spring brakes or by wheel chocks before leaving the driver\u2019s seat or going under the vehicle.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not be lower than:","options":["60 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"120 psi"},{"Question":"The safety valve will open to allow excess air pressure to escape at a level no higher than?","options":["140 psi","145 psi","150 psi","155 psi"],"correctAnswer":"150 psi"},{"Question":"What are the three different types of foundation brake systems?","options":["\'S\' cam brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes","ABS brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes","ABS brakes, \'S\' cam brakes, and wedge brakes","\'S\' cam brakes, ABS brakes, and disc brakes"],"correctAnswer":"\'S\' cam brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes"},{"Question":"The air pressure must build from 85 psi to 100 psi in _______?","options":["30 seconds","One minute","Two minutes","Three minutes"],"correctAnswer":"Two minutes"},{"Question":"When the brakes are applied, a brake malfunction is indicated by the brake lining not contacting the drum.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What is a reliable method for inspecting your brake adjustment?","options":["Measuring the applied pushrod stroke","Checking the slack adjustment","Checking the condition of the brake drum","Measuring the brake chamber size"],"correctAnswer":"Measuring the applied pushrod stroke"},{"Question":"How would you know if the anti-lock braking system had a malfunction?","options":["The brakes won\'t function at all","The brakes will function intermittently","Only the trailer hand valve functions","The ABS malfunction warning light illuminates"],"correctAnswer":"The ABS malfunction warning light illuminates"},{"Question":"What should the air pressure be when performing a brake adjustment inspection at each wheel?","options":["Between 80 - 90 psi","Between 90 - 100 psi","Between 100 - 110 psi","At maximum pressure"],"correctAnswer":"Between 90 - 100 psi"},{"Question":"If air loss exceeds the maximum allowable limit specified for your vehicle, it would be considered a major defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Inspecting a vehicle\u2019s air brake chambers includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Audible air leaks","Cracks and non-manufactured holes","Brakes with different air brake chamber sizes on each end of a steering axle","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Vehicles with air brakes must comply with The Highway Traffic Act and Regulations. If a vehicle does not comply, both the driver and the operator may be charged.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What should you do before you exit the vehicle or get underneath it?","options":["Start the vehicle","Secure the vehicle","Grab your safety equipment","Turn off the vehicle"],"correctAnswer":"Secure the vehicle"},{"Question":"What do anti-lock braking systems (ABS) do?","options":["Help maintain steering control during emergency braking","Help prevent wheel lock","Do not shorten the stopping distance","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"How often is it recommended that the air tanks be drained?","options":["At the beginning of every trip","At the end of every trip","Every day","Once a week"],"correctAnswer":"Every day"},{"Question":"Why would a brake chamber need to be \'caged\'?","options":["To move the vehicle in an emergency","To allow for proper braking","To measure your pushrod travel","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To move the vehicle in an emergency"},{"Question":"Why should the gladhands be stored properly when not in use?","options":["To keep the seals from cracking","To make them easier to find next time they\u2019re needed","To keep them clean and in good condition","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To keep them clean and in good condition"},{"Question":"If any single brake malfunctions, what affect will it have on the other brakes?","options":["None","The malfunctioning brake will overheat causing damage","They will overheat quickly and possibly fail","The braking power will be slightly reduced"],"correctAnswer":"They will overheat quickly and possibly fail"},{"Question":"For the brakes to work, the brake-shoe lining must be greased and pressed against the brake drum when the brakes are applied.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Who is responsible for ensuring air brakes are correctly adjusted?","options":["The employer","The manufacturer","The last person driving the vehicle","The current driver"],"correctAnswer":"The current driver"},{"Question":"When testing the air-loss rate of the brake system, the brake application must be held for:","options":["30 seconds","One minute","Two minutes","Three minutes"],"correctAnswer":"One minute"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle\u2019s air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel exceeds the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This is:","options":["A minor defect","A major defect","Within the acceptable adjustment limit","Something to keep track of"],"correctAnswer":"A major defect"},{"Question":"Why are automatic slack adjusters used?","options":["They make inspections and adjustments unnecessary","As a backup to a manual slack adjuster","To avoid the need to regularly perform manual re-adjustments","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To avoid the need to regularly perform manual re-adjustments"},{"Question":"On a straight truck, tractor, or bus air loss test, what is the acceptable amount of air loss allowed within one minute?","options":["2 psi","3 psi","4 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"3 psi"},{"Question":"A spring brake control valve is usually yellow?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Brake lining is defective when it is:","options":["Cracked","Missing","Loose","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"In order to make a service brake application?","options":["Pull the yellow button","Pull the red button","Push the brake pedal","Push the red and yellow buttons"],"correctAnswer":"Push the brake pedal"},{"Question":"An inspection of a vehicle\u2019s brake drums and rotors includes checking for the following defect:","options":["Cracked or broken brake drums","Cracked or broken rotors","Both A and B","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Both A and B"},{"Question":"Failure of the spring brakes to hold the vehicle stationary indicates defective service brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What can indicate that an air tank or mounting bracket is not secure?","options":["Unusual movement","An air leak","A fluid leak","A deflated airbag"],"correctAnswer":"Unusual movement"},{"Question":"The brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum is an example of:","options":["A foundation brake component defect","An issue with the brake chamber","An incorrectly measured pushrod","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"A foundation brake component defect"},{"Question":"Damaged or worn air lines are not a concern until they have an obvious leak.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What does ABS stand for?","options":["Automatic Brake Stop","Automatic Braking System","Anti-lock Brake System","Accelerated Braking System"],"correctAnswer":"Anti-lock Brake System"},{"Question":"When testing the air-loss rate of the brake system, the brake application must be held for:","options":["30 seconds","One minute","Two minutes","Three minutes"],"correctAnswer":"One minute"},{"Question":"When testing the compressor, if there is a trailer attached, the trailer supply valve must be closed.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When grease or oil is present on the brake lining:","options":["The brake lining is properly lubricated","Abnormal brake behaviour will result","The brake lining has been over-lubricated","The driver can continue to drive the vehicle as it will not cause any issues with brake function"],"correctAnswer":"Abnormal brake behaviour will result"},{"Question":"Inspecting the brake components includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum","Damaged, missing or malfunctioning foundation brake components","Cracked, loose, missing or contaminated brake lining, improper drum contact or lining thickness that is less than required","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"How often is it recommended that the air tanks be drained?","options":["At the beginning of every trip","At the end of every trip","Every day","Once a week"],"correctAnswer":"Every day"},{"Question":"What can cause damage or deterioration to brake hoses and tubes?","options":["Wear and cuts","Wear, cuts, and heat damage","Wear, cuts, abrasions, and heat damage","Abrasions and heat damage"],"correctAnswer":"Wear, cuts, abrasions, and heat damage"},{"Question":"The safety valve will open to allow excess air pressure to escape at a level no higher than?","options":["140 psi","145 psi","150 psi","155 psi"],"correctAnswer":"150 psi"},{"Question":"Air compressors can be inspected with the engine running or stopped.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"If any single brake malfunctions, what affect will it have on the other brakes?","options":["None","The malfunctioning brake will overheat causing damage","They will overheat quickly and possibly fail","The braking power will be slightly reduced"],"correctAnswer":"They will overheat quickly and possibly fail"},{"Question":"To ensure balanced braking, slack adjusters on each side of an axel should:","options":["Be the same effective lengths","Have no more than 1 inch difference","Be attached using different holes","Both B and C"],"correctAnswer":"Be the same effective lengths"},{"Question":"If you double your vehicle weight and double your speed, what does your stopping distance increase by?","options":["Four times","Six times","Eight times","Ten times"],"correctAnswer":"Eight times"},{"Question":"The air pressure must build from 85 psi to 100 psi in _______?","options":["30 seconds","One minute","Two minutes","Three minutes"],"correctAnswer":"Two minutes"},{"Question":"Operating a vehicle with defects or failing to conduct the required inspections can result in:","options":["Charges against the driver and/or operator","Detainment or impoundment of the vehicle","Fines","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel is within the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This:","options":["Is a minor defect","Is a major defect","Passes the inspection","Is a broken or defective part"],"correctAnswer":"Passes the inspection"},{"Question":"For the brakes to work, the brake-shoe lining must be greased and pressed against the brake drum when the brakes are applied.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"In Manitoba, who can perform brake adjustments on manual slack adjusters so the pushrod is less than the adjusted limit?","options":["A licensed driver with an A endorsement or a certified technician","A licensed driver with an S endorsement","The owner for the vehicle","A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"],"correctAnswer":"A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"},{"Question":"On a straight truck, tractor, or bus air loss test, what is the acceptable amount of air loss allowed within one minute?","options":["2 psi","3 psi","4 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"3 psi"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel is within the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This:","options":["Is a minor defect","Is a major defect","Passes the inspection","Is a broken or defective part"],"correctAnswer":"Passes the inspection"},{"Question":"What should you do before you exit the vehicle or get underneath it?","options":["Start the vehicle","Secure the vehicle","Grab your safety equipment","Turn off the vehicle"],"correctAnswer":"Secure the vehicle"},{"Question":"If the compressor takes longer than two minutes to build air from 85 psi to 100 psi, it would be considered a major defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When inspecting foundation brake components, the driver is expected to be able to identify brake components that are damaged, missing or malfunctioning.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"The size of an air brake chamber is based on the area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What does the air compressor do?","options":["The air compressor draws power from the battery to power the vehicle","The air compressor builds air for the trailer only","The air compressor draws air in and forces it into a smaller space increasing air pressure","The air compressor removes moisture from the air brake system"],"correctAnswer":"The air compressor draws air in and forces it into a smaller space increasing air pressure"},{"Question":"What happens when the trailer lines are not connected properly?","options":["Spring brakes may not release","The towing vehicle may lose air","Service brakes will not function properly","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"How often is it recommended that the air tanks be drained?","options":["At the beginning of every trip","At the end of every trip","Every day","Once a week"],"correctAnswer":"Every day"},{"Question":"Damaged or worn air lines are not a concern until they have an obvious leak.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"The engine must be running when testing the air-loss rate.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Where are air brake chambers located?","options":["At each wheel","At the drive wheels only","At the trailer wheels only","At both the drive and trailer wheels"],"correctAnswer":"At each wheel"},{"Question":"To ensure balanced braking, slack adjusters on each side of an axel should:","options":["Be the same effective lengths","Have no more than 1 inch difference","Be attached using different holes","Both B and C"],"correctAnswer":"Be the same effective lengths"},{"Question":"What can cause damage or deterioration to brake hoses and tubes?","options":["Wear and cuts","Wear, cuts, and heat damage","Wear, cuts, abrasions, and heat damage","Abrasions and heat damage"],"correctAnswer":"Wear, cuts, abrasions, and heat damage"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the safety valve?","options":["Starts building air pressure at 100 psi","Stops building air pressure at 140 psi","Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting","Ensures the trucks safety features are working correctly"],"correctAnswer":"Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting"},{"Question":"A spring brake control valve is usually yellow?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the tractor protection valve?","options":["Prevents total air loss from the trailer if the trailer breaks away","Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away","Holds the supply line and emergency line in place not allowing them to break away","Prevents over pressure in the system allowing excess air to escape"],"correctAnswer":"Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away"},{"Question":"In Manitoba, who can perform brake adjustments on manual slack adjusters so the pushrod is less than the adjusted limit?","options":["A licensed driver with an A endorsement or a certified technician","A licensed driver with an S endorsement","The owner for the vehicle","A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"],"correctAnswer":"A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"},{"Question":"When the brakes are applied, a brake malfunction is indicated by the brake lining not contacting the drum.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"In what order should air tanks be drained?","options":["Wet, primary, secondary","Primary, secondary, wet","Primary, wet, secondary","All at the same time"],"correctAnswer":"Wet, primary, secondary"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not exceed:","options":["90 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"145 psi"},{"Question":"When the pushrod stroke exceeds the adjustment limit of the brake chamber, the brake:","options":["Is out of adjustment","Is in adjustment","Needs to be replaced","Has a minor defect"],"correctAnswer":"Is out of adjustment"},{"Question":"Actual cut-in pressure for the governor should never be less than 90 PSI?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"At what pressure do the spring brakes normally start to apply because there is no longer enough pressure to keep them released?","options":["20 psi","40 psi","60 psi","85 psi"],"correctAnswer":"60 psi"},{"Question":"An inspection of a vehicle\u2019s brake drums and rotors includes checking for the following defect:","options":["Cracked or broken brake drums","Cracked or broken rotors","Both A and B","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Both A and B"},{"Question":"Older air systems may operate with lower pressure settings.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When the brakes are applied, a brake malfunction is indicated by the brake lining not contacting the drum.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"The vehicle must be secured by the spring brakes or by wheel chocks before leaving the driver\u2019s seat or going under the vehicle.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When testing the compressor, if there is a trailer attached, the trailer supply valve must be closed.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When testing the tractor protection system, the trailer supply valve must close before the pressure drops below:","options":["20 psi","55 psi","60 psi","100 psi"],"correctAnswer":"20 psi"},{"Question":"The size of an air brake chamber is based on the area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the safety valve?","options":["Starts building air pressure at 100 psi","Stops building air pressure at 140 psi","Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting","Ensures the trucks safety features are working correctly"],"correctAnswer":"Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting"},{"Question":"Inspecting the air compressor includes checking for which defects?","options":["Loose air compressor drive belt pulley","Loose, cut or frayed air compressor drive belt","Insecure air compressor mounting, bracket or fasteners","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"When testing brake performance (tug tests), it would be considered a major defect if:","options":["The spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle in place","The service brakes fail to stop the vehicle","Only if the tractor spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle","Both A and B"],"correctAnswer":"Both A and B"},{"Question":"What does the air compressor do?","options":["The air compressor draws power from the battery to power the vehicle","The air compressor builds air for the trailer only","The air compressor draws air in and forces it into a smaller space increasing air pressure","The air compressor removes moisture from the air brake system"],"correctAnswer":"The air compressor draws air in and forces it into a smaller space increasing air pressure"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed when testing the air-loss rate of the brake system on a tractor and trailer?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","6 psi","10 psi"],"correctAnswer":"4 psi"},{"Question":"If air loss exceeds the maximum allowable limit specified for your vehicle, it would be considered a major defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Your spring brakes should be used when parking or in an emergency when your service brakes fail?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When grease or oil is present on the brake lining:","options":["The brake lining is properly lubricated","Abnormal brake behaviour will result","The brake lining has been over-lubricated","The driver can continue to drive the vehicle as it will not cause any issues with brake function"],"correctAnswer":"Abnormal brake behaviour will result"},{"Question":"Why would a brake chamber need to be \'caged\'?","options":["To move the vehicle in an emergency","To allow for proper braking","To measure your pushrod travel","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To move the vehicle in an emergency"},{"Question":"Why are automatic slack adjusters used?","options":["They make inspections and adjustments unnecessary","As a backup to a manual slack adjuster","To avoid the need to regularly perform manual re-adjustments","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To avoid the need to regularly perform manual re-adjustments"},{"Question":"What is a reliable method for inspecting your brake adjustment?","options":["Measuring the applied pushrod stroke","Checking the slack adjustment","Checking the condition of the brake drum","Measuring the brake chamber size"],"correctAnswer":"Measuring the applied pushrod stroke"},{"Question":"Brake lining is defective when it is:","options":["Cracked","Missing","Loose","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Spring brakes use air to apply the brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Why should the gladhands be stored properly when not in use?","options":["To keep the seals from cracking","To make them easier to find next time they\u2019re needed","To keep them clean and in good condition","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To keep them clean and in good condition"},{"Question":"What can cause damage to the foundation brake components?","options":["Debris","Component failure","Deterioration","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"How can air brake chamber air leaks usually be detected?","options":["Visually","Audibly","By checking pushrod travel distance","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Audibly"},{"Question":"When testing the low air-pressure warning device, the engine can be stopped or running but the ignition must be on.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When checking the air pressure buildup rate (compressor operation), what should the engine be idling between?","options":["200 - 500 rpm","500 - 800 rpm","600 - 900 rpm","900 - 1200 rpm"],"correctAnswer":"600 - 900 rpm"},{"Question":"Inspecting the brake components includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum","Damaged, missing or malfunctioning foundation brake components","Cracked, loose, missing or contaminated brake lining, improper drum contact or lining thickness that is less than required","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"For the brakes to work, the brake-shoe lining must be greased and pressed against the brake drum when the brakes are applied.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"At what pressure do the spring brakes normally start to apply because there is no longer enough pressure to keep them released?","options":["20 psi","40 psi","60 psi","85 psi"],"correctAnswer":"60 psi"},{"Question":"Wheels, dust shields, and other parts of the vehicle have no impact on your view of the brake drums and rotors.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Inspecting a vehicle\u2019s air lines includes checking for the following defects:","options":["Audible air leak","Damaged or worn air lines","Improper fittings used to connect or repair air lines","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"If you double your vehicle weight and double your speed, what does your stopping distance increase by?","options":["Four times","Six times","Eight times","Ten times"],"correctAnswer":"Eight times"},{"Question":"What should the air pressure be when performing a brake adjustment inspection at each wheel?","options":["Between 80 - 90 psi","Between 90 - 100 psi","Between 100 - 110 psi","At maximum pressure"],"correctAnswer":"Between 90 - 100 psi"},{"Question":"Inspecting a vehicle\u2019s air brake chambers includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Audible air leaks","Cracks and non-manufactured holes","Brakes with different air brake chamber sizes on each end of a steering axle","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"A brake chamber that includes both service brake and spring brake sections is called a:","options":["Brake chamber","Spring brake chamber","DD3 brake chamber","Service brake chamber"],"correctAnswer":"Spring brake chamber"},{"Question":"Damaged or worn air lines are not a concern until they have an obvious leak.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Actual cut-in pressure of the governor should never be less than:","options":["55 psi","80 psi","100 psi","120 psi"],"correctAnswer":"100 psi"},{"Question":"The safety valve will open to allow excess air pressure to escape at a level no higher than?","options":["140 psi","145 psi","150 psi","155 psi"],"correctAnswer":"150 psi"},{"Question":"When inspecting foundation brake components, the driver is expected to be able to identify brake components that are damaged, missing or malfunctioning.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What are the three different types of foundation brake systems?","options":["\'S\' cam brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes","ABS brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes","ABS brakes, \'S\' cam brakes, and wedge brakes","\'S\' cam brakes, ABS brakes, and disc brakes"],"correctAnswer":"\'S\' cam brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes"},{"Question":"What is a reliable method for inspecting your brake adjustment?","options":["Measuring the applied pushrod stroke","Checking the slack adjustment","Checking the condition of the brake drum","Measuring the brake chamber size"],"correctAnswer":"Measuring the applied pushrod stroke"},{"Question":"Air compressors can be inspected with the engine running or stopped.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Where are air brake chambers located?","options":["At each wheel","At the drive wheels only","At the trailer wheels only","At both the drive and trailer wheels"],"correctAnswer":"At each wheel"},{"Question":"The safety valve will open to allow excess air pressure to escape at a level no higher than?","options":["140 psi","145 psi","150 psi","155 psi"],"correctAnswer":"150 psi"},{"Question":"When conducting an inspection of the air brake system, be sure to:","options":["Park the vehicle on level ground","Park the vehicle away from traffic","Turn the engine off","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Why would a brake chamber need to be \'caged\'?","options":["To move the vehicle in an emergency","To allow for proper braking","To measure your pushrod travel","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To move the vehicle in an emergency"},{"Question":"Wheels, dust shields, and other parts of the vehicle have no impact on your view of the brake drums and rotors.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What can indicate that an air tank or mounting bracket is not secure?","options":["Unusual movement","An air leak","A fluid leak","A deflated airbag"],"correctAnswer":"Unusual movement"},{"Question":"Operating a vehicle with defects or failing to conduct the required inspections can result in:","options":["Charges against the driver and/or operator","Detainment or impoundment of the vehicle","Fines","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"When testing the tractor protection system, the trailer supply valve must close before the pressure drops below:","options":["20 psi","55 psi","60 psi","100 psi"],"correctAnswer":"20 psi"},{"Question":"What can cause damage or deterioration to brake hoses and tubes?","options":["Wear and cuts","Wear, cuts, and heat damage","Wear, cuts, abrasions, and heat damage","Abrasions and heat damage"],"correctAnswer":"Wear, cuts, abrasions, and heat damage"},{"Question":"When damage extends into the reinforcing or inner layer, the air line is defective.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"If the low air-pressure warning device activates below 55 psi, this would be considered a minor defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When testing the air-loss rate of the brake system, the brake application must be held for:","options":["30 seconds","One minute","Two minutes","Three minutes"],"correctAnswer":"One minute"},{"Question":"Why are automatic slack adjusters used?","options":["They make inspections and adjustments unnecessary","As a backup to a manual slack adjuster","To avoid the need to regularly perform manual re-adjustments","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To avoid the need to regularly perform manual re-adjustments"},{"Question":"Older air systems may operate with lower pressure settings.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"The air pressure must build from 85 psi to 100 psi in _______?","options":["30 seconds","One minute","Two minutes","Three minutes"],"correctAnswer":"Two minutes"},{"Question":"The engine must be running when testing the air-loss rate.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What does the air compressor do?","options":["The air compressor draws power from the battery to power the vehicle","The air compressor builds air for the trailer only","The air compressor draws air in and forces it into a smaller space increasing air pressure","The air compressor removes moisture from the air brake system"],"correctAnswer":"The air compressor draws air in and forces it into a smaller space increasing air pressure"},{"Question":"What can indicate that an air tank or mounting bracket is not secure?","options":["Unusual movement","An air leak","A fluid leak","A deflated airbag"],"correctAnswer":"Unusual movement"},{"Question":"Inspecting a vehicle\u2019s air lines includes checking for the following defects:","options":["Audible air leak","Damaged or worn air lines","Improper fittings used to connect or repair air lines","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Older air systems may operate with lower pressure settings.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"The vehicle must be secured by the spring brakes or by wheel chocks before leaving the driver\u2019s seat or going under the vehicle.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"At what pressure do the spring brakes normally start to apply because there is no longer enough pressure to keep them released?","options":["20 psi","40 psi","60 psi","85 psi"],"correctAnswer":"60 psi"},{"Question":"Damaged or worn air lines are not a concern until they have an obvious leak.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"The Highway Traffic Act and Regulations prohibit the operation of a vehicle with a brake that is out of adjustment.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Inspecting the air compressor includes checking for which defects?","options":["Loose air compressor drive belt pulley","Loose, cut or frayed air compressor drive belt","Insecure air compressor mounting, bracket or fasteners","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What is the size of an air brake chamber based on?","options":["The type of chamber","The area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches","The pushrod travel distance","The make and model of the vehicle"],"correctAnswer":"The area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches"},{"Question":"Why are automatic slack adjusters used?","options":["They make inspections and adjustments unnecessary","As a backup to a manual slack adjuster","To avoid the need to regularly perform manual re-adjustments","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To avoid the need to regularly perform manual re-adjustments"},{"Question":"What safety equipment is recommended while conducting an air brake inspection?","options":["Fire extinguisher, safety glasses, and  protective footwear","Safety glasses, protective headgear, and protective footwear","Protective headgear, ear plugs, and safety glasses","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Safety glasses, protective headgear, and protective footwear"},{"Question":"A spring brake control valve is usually yellow?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Vehicles with air brakes must comply with The Highway Traffic Act and Regulations. If a vehicle does not comply, both the driver and the operator may be charged.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When testing the tractor protection system, the trailer supply valve must close before the pressure drops below:","options":["20 psi","55 psi","60 psi","100 psi"],"correctAnswer":"20 psi"},{"Question":"Actual cut-in pressure for the governor should never be less than 90 PSI?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"For the brakes to work, the brake-shoe lining must be greased and pressed against the brake drum when the brakes are applied.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Who is responsible for ensuring air brakes are correctly adjusted?","options":["The employer","The manufacturer","The last person driving the vehicle","The current driver"],"correctAnswer":"The current driver"},{"Question":"The first air tank that air enters is called the supply (wet tank).","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What should you do before you exit the vehicle or get underneath it?","options":["Start the vehicle","Secure the vehicle","Grab your safety equipment","Turn off the vehicle"],"correctAnswer":"Secure the vehicle"},{"Question":"When checking the buildup rate (compressor operation) the engine should be building air pressure from _____ psi to ____ psi within two minutes:","options":["45 - 65","65 - 85","85 - 100","100 - 125"],"correctAnswer":"85 - 100"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not be lower than:","options":["60 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"120 psi"},{"Question":"What should the air pressure be when performing a brake adjustment inspection at each wheel?","options":["Between 80 - 90 psi","Between 90 - 100 psi","Between 100 - 110 psi","At maximum pressure"],"correctAnswer":"Between 90 - 100 psi"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle\u2019s air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel exceeds the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This is:","options":["A minor defect","A major defect","Within the acceptable adjustment limit","Something to keep track of"],"correctAnswer":"A major defect"},{"Question":"Who is responsible for ensuring air brakes are correctly adjusted?","options":["The employer","The manufacturer","The last person driving the vehicle","The current driver"],"correctAnswer":"The current driver"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not exceed:","options":["90 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"145 psi"},{"Question":"Why would a brake chamber need to be \'caged\'?","options":["To move the vehicle in an emergency","To allow for proper braking","To measure your pushrod travel","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To move the vehicle in an emergency"},{"Question":"Air brake chambers from different manufacturers may look different even if they are the same size.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Inspecting a vehicle\u2019s air brake chambers includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Audible air leaks","Cracks and non-manufactured holes","Brakes with different air brake chamber sizes on each end of a steering axle","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What is the size of an air brake chamber based on?","options":["The type of chamber","The area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches","The pushrod travel distance","The make and model of the vehicle"],"correctAnswer":"The area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches"},{"Question":"The air pressure must build from 85 psi to 100 psi in _______?","options":["30 seconds","One minute","Two minutes","Three minutes"],"correctAnswer":"Two minutes"},{"Question":"When inspecting foundation brake components, the driver is expected to be able to identify brake components that are damaged, missing or malfunctioning.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Wheels, dust shields, and other parts of the vehicle have no impact on your view of the brake drums and rotors.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Inspecting the air compressor includes checking for which defects?","options":["Loose air compressor drive belt pulley","Loose, cut or frayed air compressor drive belt","Insecure air compressor mounting, bracket or fasteners","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Actual cut-in pressure of the governor should never be less than:","options":["55 psi","80 psi","100 psi","120 psi"],"correctAnswer":"100 psi"},{"Question":"Spring brakes use air to apply the brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"At what level must the low pressure warning device activate?","options":["At or above 60 psi","Between 40 - 50 psi","At or above 85 psi","At or above 55 psi"],"correctAnswer":"At or above 55 psi"},{"Question":"How would you know if the anti-lock braking system had a malfunction?","options":["The brakes won\'t function at all","The brakes will function intermittently","Only the trailer hand valve functions","The ABS malfunction warning light illuminates"],"correctAnswer":"The ABS malfunction warning light illuminates"},{"Question":"Inspecting the brake components includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum","Damaged, missing or malfunctioning foundation brake components","Cracked, loose, missing or contaminated brake lining, improper drum contact or lining thickness that is less than required","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"If air exhausts from the service line, it means that the trailer supply valve is defective.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Why should the gladhands be stored properly when not in use?","options":["To keep the seals from cracking","To make them easier to find next time they\u2019re needed","To keep them clean and in good condition","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To keep them clean and in good condition"},{"Question":"What do anti-lock braking systems (ABS) do?","options":["Help maintain steering control during emergency braking","Help prevent wheel lock","Do not shorten the stopping distance","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Spring brakes use air to apply the brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When checking the buildup rate (compressor operation) the engine should be building air pressure from _____ psi to ____ psi within two minutes:","options":["45 - 65","65 - 85","85 - 100","100 - 125"],"correctAnswer":"85 - 100"},{"Question":"Damaged or worn air lines are not a concern until they have an obvious leak.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle\u2019s air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel exceeds the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This is:","options":["A minor defect","A major defect","Within the acceptable adjustment limit","Something to keep track of"],"correctAnswer":"A major defect"},{"Question":"What can cause damage or deterioration to brake hoses and tubes?","options":["Wear and cuts","Wear, cuts, and heat damage","Wear, cuts, abrasions, and heat damage","Abrasions and heat damage"],"correctAnswer":"Wear, cuts, abrasions, and heat damage"},{"Question":"For the brakes to work, the brake-shoe lining must be greased and pressed against the brake drum when the brakes are applied.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"The brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum is an example of:","options":["A foundation brake component defect","An issue with the brake chamber","An incorrectly measured pushrod","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"A foundation brake component defect"},{"Question":"Failure of the spring brakes to hold the vehicle stationary indicates defective service brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"How can air brake chamber air leaks usually be detected?","options":["Visually","Audibly","By checking pushrod travel distance","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Audibly"},{"Question":"A brake chamber that includes both service brake and spring brake sections is called a:","options":["Brake chamber","Spring brake chamber","DD3 brake chamber","Service brake chamber"],"correctAnswer":"Spring brake chamber"},{"Question":"If the low air-pressure warning device activates below 55 psi, this would be considered a minor defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel is within the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This:","options":["Is a minor defect","Is a major defect","Passes the inspection","Is a broken or defective part"],"correctAnswer":"Passes the inspection"},{"Question":"When damage extends into the reinforcing or inner layer, the air line is defective.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What is a reliable method for inspecting your brake adjustment?","options":["Measuring the applied pushrod stroke","Checking the slack adjustment","Checking the condition of the brake drum","Measuring the brake chamber size"],"correctAnswer":"Measuring the applied pushrod stroke"},{"Question":"What should the air pressure be when performing a brake adjustment inspection at each wheel?","options":["Between 80 - 90 psi","Between 90 - 100 psi","Between 100 - 110 psi","At maximum pressure"],"correctAnswer":"Between 90 - 100 psi"},{"Question":"As brakes heat up, you may experience a reduction in their effectiveness. This is known as:","options":["ABS brakes","Anti-lock braking","Brake fade","Combination braking"],"correctAnswer":"Brake fade"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the safety valve?","options":["Starts building air pressure at 100 psi","Stops building air pressure at 140 psi","Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting","Ensures the trucks safety features are working correctly"],"correctAnswer":"Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting"},{"Question":"Testing the performance of your brakes requires performing separate tests of each braking system.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Where are air brake chambers located?","options":["At each wheel","At the drive wheels only","At the trailer wheels only","At both the drive and trailer wheels"],"correctAnswer":"At each wheel"},{"Question":"Older air systems may operate with lower pressure settings.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When inspecting foundation brake components, the driver is expected to be able to identify brake components that are damaged, missing or malfunctioning.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What happens if a single brake malfunctions?","options":["It puts more pressure on the other brakes","It causes the other brakes to quickly overheat","It could cause the other brakes to fail","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"If the governor fails to signal the compressor to cut-out what allows the excess air pressure to escape?","options":["The air dryer","A one way check valve","The low pressure warning system","A safety valve"],"correctAnswer":"A safety valve"},{"Question":"When checking the buildup rate (compressor operation) the engine should be building air pressure from _____ psi to ____ psi within two minutes:","options":["45 - 65","65 - 85","85 - 100","100 - 125"],"correctAnswer":"85 - 100"},{"Question":"When the brakes are applied, a brake malfunction is indicated by the brake lining not contacting the drum.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Operating a vehicle with defects or failing to conduct the required inspections can result in:","options":["Charges against the driver and/or operator","Detainment or impoundment of the vehicle","Fines","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Vehicles with air brakes must comply with The Highway Traffic Act and Regulations. If a vehicle does not comply, both the driver and the operator may be charged.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not be lower than:","options":["60 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"120 psi"},{"Question":"When testing the compressor, if there is a trailer attached, the trailer supply valve must be closed.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When the pushrod stroke exceeds the adjustment limit of the brake chamber, the brake:","options":["Is out of adjustment","Is in adjustment","Needs to be replaced","Has a minor defect"],"correctAnswer":"Is out of adjustment"},{"Question":"Inspecting a vehicle\u2019s air brake chambers includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Audible air leaks","Cracks and non-manufactured holes","Brakes with different air brake chamber sizes on each end of a steering axle","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Wheels, dust shields, and other parts of the vehicle have no impact on your view of the brake drums and rotors.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When testing brake performance (tug tests), it would be considered a major defect if:","options":["The spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle in place","The service brakes fail to stop the vehicle","Only if the tractor spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle","Both A and B"],"correctAnswer":"Both A and B"},{"Question":"What does the air compressor do?","options":["The air compressor draws power from the battery to power the vehicle","The air compressor builds air for the trailer only","The air compressor draws air in and forces it into a smaller space increasing air pressure","The air compressor removes moisture from the air brake system"],"correctAnswer":"The air compressor draws air in and forces it into a smaller space increasing air pressure"},{"Question":"If the compressor takes longer than two minutes to build air from 85 psi to 100 psi, it would be considered a major defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Your spring brakes should be used when parking or in an emergency when your service brakes fail?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not exceed:","options":["90 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"145 psi"},{"Question":"Why should the gladhands be stored properly when not in use?","options":["To keep the seals from cracking","To make them easier to find next time they\u2019re needed","To keep them clean and in good condition","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To keep them clean and in good condition"},{"Question":"What does the air compressor do?","options":["The air compressor draws power from the battery to power the vehicle","The air compressor builds air for the trailer only","The air compressor draws air in and forces it into a smaller space increasing air pressure","The air compressor removes moisture from the air brake system"],"correctAnswer":"The air compressor draws air in and forces it into a smaller space increasing air pressure"},{"Question":"To ensure balanced braking, slack adjusters on each side of an axel should:","options":["Be the same effective lengths","Have no more than 1 inch difference","Be attached using different holes","Both B and C"],"correctAnswer":"Be the same effective lengths"},{"Question":"At what pressure do the spring brakes normally start to apply because there is no longer enough pressure to keep them released?","options":["20 psi","40 psi","60 psi","85 psi"],"correctAnswer":"60 psi"},{"Question":"If air loss exceeds the maximum allowable limit specified for your vehicle, it would be considered a major defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When testing the compressor, if there is a trailer attached, the trailer supply valve must be closed.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Your spring brakes should be used when parking or in an emergency when your service brakes fail?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the governor?","options":["The governor causes the compressor to start and stop pumping air (cut-in and cut-out)","The governor controls the amount of moisture the air dryer removes from the system","Once air flows through the supply tank, the governor prevents it from returning","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"The governor causes the compressor to start and stop pumping air (cut-in and cut-out)"},{"Question":"At what level must the low pressure warning device activate?","options":["At or above 60 psi","Between 40 - 50 psi","At or above 85 psi","At or above 55 psi"],"correctAnswer":"At or above 55 psi"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel is within the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This:","options":["Is a minor defect","Is a major defect","Passes the inspection","Is a broken or defective part"],"correctAnswer":"Passes the inspection"},{"Question":"How can air brake chamber air leaks usually be detected?","options":["Visually","Audibly","By checking pushrod travel distance","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Audibly"},{"Question":"The brake on each end of an axel should have a different sized air brake chamber to ensure brake forces are balanced.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What is a reliable method for inspecting your brake adjustment?","options":["Measuring the applied pushrod stroke","Checking the slack adjustment","Checking the condition of the brake drum","Measuring the brake chamber size"],"correctAnswer":"Measuring the applied pushrod stroke"},{"Question":"A brake chamber that includes both service brake and spring brake sections is called a:","options":["Brake chamber","Spring brake chamber","DD3 brake chamber","Service brake chamber"],"correctAnswer":"Spring brake chamber"},{"Question":"If the low air-pressure warning device activates below 55 psi, this would be considered a minor defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"How would you know if the anti-lock braking system had a malfunction?","options":["The brakes won\'t function at all","The brakes will function intermittently","Only the trailer hand valve functions","The ABS malfunction warning light illuminates"],"correctAnswer":"The ABS malfunction warning light illuminates"},{"Question":"The Highway Traffic Act and Regulations prohibit the operation of a vehicle with a brake that is out of adjustment.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed in one minute on a tractor with two or more trailers?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","5 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"6 psi"},{"Question":"When checking the air pressure buildup rate (compressor operation), what should the engine be idling between?","options":["200 - 500 rpm","500 - 800 rpm","600 - 900 rpm","900 - 1200 rpm"],"correctAnswer":"600 - 900 rpm"},{"Question":"How often is it recommended that the air tanks be drained?","options":["At the beginning of every trip","At the end of every trip","Every day","Once a week"],"correctAnswer":"Every day"},{"Question":"For the brakes to work, the brake-shoe lining must be greased and pressed against the brake drum when the brakes are applied.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When checking the air pressure buildup rate (compressor operation), what should the engine be idling between?","options":["200 - 500 rpm","500 - 800 rpm","600 - 900 rpm","900 - 1200 rpm"],"correctAnswer":"600 - 900 rpm"},{"Question":"On a straight truck, tractor, or bus air loss test, what is the acceptable amount of air loss allowed within one minute?","options":["2 psi","3 psi","4 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"3 psi"},{"Question":"Where are air brake chambers located?","options":["At each wheel","At the drive wheels only","At the trailer wheels only","At both the drive and trailer wheels"],"correctAnswer":"At each wheel"},{"Question":"Your spring brakes should be used when parking or in an emergency when your service brakes fail?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When testing the air-loss rate of the brake system, the brake pedal must be fully applied.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When testing brake performance (tug tests), it would be considered a major defect if:","options":["The spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle in place","The service brakes fail to stop the vehicle","Only if the tractor spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle","Both A and B"],"correctAnswer":"Both A and B"},{"Question":"How often is it recommended that the air tanks be drained?","options":["At the beginning of every trip","At the end of every trip","Every day","Once a week"],"correctAnswer":"Every day"},{"Question":"The brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum is an example of:","options":["A foundation brake component defect","An issue with the brake chamber","An incorrectly measured pushrod","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"A foundation brake component defect"},{"Question":"If air exhausts from the service line, it means that the trailer supply valve is defective.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"The vehicle must be secured by the spring brakes or by wheel chocks before leaving the driver\u2019s seat or going under the vehicle.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"How would you know if the anti-lock braking system had a malfunction?","options":["The brakes won\'t function at all","The brakes will function intermittently","Only the trailer hand valve functions","The ABS malfunction warning light illuminates"],"correctAnswer":"The ABS malfunction warning light illuminates"},{"Question":"Older air systems may operate with lower pressure settings.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"In order to make a service brake application?","options":["Pull the yellow button","Pull the red button","Push the brake pedal","Push the red and yellow buttons"],"correctAnswer":"Push the brake pedal"},{"Question":"What happens when the trailer lines are not connected properly?","options":["Spring brakes may not release","The towing vehicle may lose air","Service brakes will not function properly","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Inspecting a vehicle\u2019s air lines includes checking for the following defects:","options":["Audible air leak","Damaged or worn air lines","Improper fittings used to connect or repair air lines","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed in one minute on a tractor with two or more trailers?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","5 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"6 psi"},{"Question":"What are the three different types of foundation brake systems?","options":["\'S\' cam brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes","ABS brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes","ABS brakes, \'S\' cam brakes, and wedge brakes","\'S\' cam brakes, ABS brakes, and disc brakes"],"correctAnswer":"\'S\' cam brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes"},{"Question":"If any single brake malfunctions, what affect will it have on the other brakes?","options":["None","The malfunctioning brake will overheat causing damage","They will overheat quickly and possibly fail","The braking power will be slightly reduced"],"correctAnswer":"They will overheat quickly and possibly fail"},{"Question":"Why should the gladhands be stored properly when not in use?","options":["To keep the seals from cracking","To make them easier to find next time they\u2019re needed","To keep them clean and in good condition","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To keep them clean and in good condition"},{"Question":"Inspecting the vehicle\u2019s air lines includes checking for the following defects:","options":["Audible air leak","Damage or worn air lines","Improper fittings used to connect or repair an air line","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"A spring brake control valve is usually yellow?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Actual cut-in pressure of the governor should never be less than:","options":["55 psi","80 psi","100 psi","120 psi"],"correctAnswer":"100 psi"},{"Question":"Automatic slack adjusters, if working properly, require regular re-adjustment.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"In what order should air tanks be drained?","options":["Wet, primary, secondary","Primary, secondary, wet","Primary, wet, secondary","All at the same time"],"correctAnswer":"Wet, primary, secondary"},{"Question":"What controls an air brake system\u2019s pressure range (cut-in and cut-out settings)?","options":["The governor","The compressor","The engine","The turbo-charger"],"correctAnswer":"The governor"},{"Question":"What can cause damage to the foundation brake components?","options":["Debris","Component failure","Deterioration","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Spring brakes use air to apply the brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"The size of an air brake chamber is based on the area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel is within the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This:","options":["Is a minor defect","Is a major defect","Passes the inspection","Is a broken or defective part"],"correctAnswer":"Passes the inspection"},{"Question":"Inspecting a vehicle\u2019s air lines includes checking for the following defects:","options":["Audible air leak","Damaged or worn air lines","Improper fittings used to connect or repair air lines","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What can indicate that an air tank or mounting bracket is not secure?","options":["Unusual movement","An air leak","A fluid leak","A deflated airbag"],"correctAnswer":"Unusual movement"},{"Question":"Damaged or worn air lines are not a concern until they have an obvious leak.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What happens if a single brake malfunctions?","options":["It puts more pressure on the other brakes","It causes the other brakes to quickly overheat","It could cause the other brakes to fail","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Who is responsible for ensuring air brakes are correctly adjusted?","options":["The employer","The manufacturer","The last person driving the vehicle","The current driver"],"correctAnswer":"The current driver"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the safety valve?","options":["Starts building air pressure at 100 psi","Stops building air pressure at 140 psi","Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting","Ensures the trucks safety features are working correctly"],"correctAnswer":"Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting"},{"Question":"Wheels, dust shields, and other parts of the vehicle have no impact on your view of the brake drums and rotors.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed in one minute on a tractor with two or more trailers?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","5 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"6 psi"},{"Question":"To ensure balanced braking, slack adjusters on each side of an axel should:","options":["Be the same effective lengths","Have no more than 1 inch difference","Be attached using different holes","Both B and C"],"correctAnswer":"Be the same effective lengths"},{"Question":"What should the air pressure be when performing a brake adjustment inspection at each wheel?","options":["Between 80 - 90 psi","Between 90 - 100 psi","Between 100 - 110 psi","At maximum pressure"],"correctAnswer":"Between 90 - 100 psi"},{"Question":"When the pushrod stroke exceeds the adjustment limit of the brake chamber, the brake:","options":["Is out of adjustment","Is in adjustment","Needs to be replaced","Has a minor defect"],"correctAnswer":"Is out of adjustment"},{"Question":"When testing brake performance (tug tests), it would be considered a major defect if:","options":["The spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle in place","The service brakes fail to stop the vehicle","Only if the tractor spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle","Both A and B"],"correctAnswer":"Both A and B"},{"Question":"At what pressure do the spring brakes normally start to apply because there is no longer enough pressure to keep them released?","options":["20 psi","40 psi","60 psi","85 psi"],"correctAnswer":"60 psi"},{"Question":"At what level must the low pressure warning device activate?","options":["At or above 60 psi","Between 40 - 50 psi","At or above 85 psi","At or above 55 psi"],"correctAnswer":"At or above 55 psi"},{"Question":"The engine must be running when testing the air-loss rate.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What controls an air brake system\u2019s pressure range (cut-in and cut-out settings)?","options":["The governor","The compressor","The engine","The turbo-charger"],"correctAnswer":"The governor"},{"Question":"When should the supply tank be drained?","options":["First","Last","In whatever order is most convenient for the driver","The supply tank should never be drained"],"correctAnswer":"First"},{"Question":"As brakes heat up, you may experience a reduction in their effectiveness. This is known as:","options":["ABS brakes","Anti-lock braking","Brake fade","Combination braking"],"correctAnswer":"Brake fade"},{"Question":"A sudden increase in the amount of moisture or oil drained from any air-tank:","options":["Means the system is working correctly","Indicates the governor is faulty","Must be reported and repaired","Indicates an engine oil leak"],"correctAnswer":"Must be reported and repaired"},{"Question":"Inspecting the air compressor includes checking for which defects?","options":["Loose air compressor drive belt pulley","Loose, cut or frayed air compressor drive belt","Insecure air compressor mounting, bracket or fasteners","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"To ensure balanced braking, slack adjusters on each side of an axel should:","options":["Be the same effective lengths","Have no more than 1 inch difference","Be attached using different holes","Both B and C"],"correctAnswer":"Be the same effective lengths"},{"Question":"When damage extends into the reinforcing or inner layer, the air line is defective.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the tractor protection valve?","options":["Prevents total air loss from the trailer if the trailer breaks away","Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away","Holds the supply line and emergency line in place not allowing them to break away","Prevents over pressure in the system allowing excess air to escape"],"correctAnswer":"Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away"},{"Question":"When grease or oil is present on the brake lining:","options":["The brake lining is properly lubricated","Abnormal brake behaviour will result","The brake lining has been over-lubricated","The driver can continue to drive the vehicle as it will not cause any issues with brake function"],"correctAnswer":"Abnormal brake behaviour will result"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel is within the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This:","options":["Is a minor defect","Is a major defect","Passes the inspection","Is a broken or defective part"],"correctAnswer":"Passes the inspection"},{"Question":"Where are air brake chambers located?","options":["At each wheel","At the drive wheels only","At the trailer wheels only","At both the drive and trailer wheels"],"correctAnswer":"At each wheel"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed in one minute on a tractor with two or more trailers?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","5 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"6 psi"},{"Question":"The vehicle must be secured by the spring brakes or by wheel chocks before leaving the driver\u2019s seat or going under the vehicle.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"For the brakes to work, the brake-shoe lining must be greased and pressed against the brake drum when the brakes are applied.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not be lower than:","options":["60 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"120 psi"},{"Question":"The brake on each end of an axel should have a different sized air brake chamber to ensure brake forces are balanced.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the safety valve?","options":["Starts building air pressure at 100 psi","Stops building air pressure at 140 psi","Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting","Ensures the trucks safety features are working correctly"],"correctAnswer":"Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting"},{"Question":"Damaged or worn air lines are not a concern until they have an obvious leak.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When the brakes are applied, a brake malfunction is indicated by the brake lining not contacting the drum.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When damage extends into the reinforcing or inner layer, the air line is defective.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Where are air brake chambers located?","options":["At each wheel","At the drive wheels only","At the trailer wheels only","At both the drive and trailer wheels"],"correctAnswer":"At each wheel"},{"Question":"At what level must the low pressure warning device activate?","options":["At or above 60 psi","Between 40 - 50 psi","At or above 85 psi","At or above 55 psi"],"correctAnswer":"At or above 55 psi"},{"Question":"Why would a brake chamber need to be \'caged\'?","options":["To move the vehicle in an emergency","To allow for proper braking","To measure your pushrod travel","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To move the vehicle in an emergency"},{"Question":"In Manitoba, who can perform brake adjustments on manual slack adjusters so the pushrod is less than the adjusted limit?","options":["A licensed driver with an A endorsement or a certified technician","A licensed driver with an S endorsement","The owner for the vehicle","A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"],"correctAnswer":"A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"},{"Question":"Air compressors can be inspected with the engine running or stopped.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed when testing the air-loss rate of the brake system on a tractor and trailer?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","6 psi","10 psi"],"correctAnswer":"4 psi"},{"Question":"If the governor fails to signal the compressor to cut-out what allows the excess air pressure to escape?","options":["The air dryer","A one way check valve","The low pressure warning system","A safety valve"],"correctAnswer":"A safety valve"},{"Question":"When should the supply tank be drained?","options":["First","Last","In whatever order is most convenient for the driver","The supply tank should never be drained"],"correctAnswer":"First"},{"Question":"The engine must be running when testing the air-loss rate.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Automatic slack adjusters, if working properly, require regular re-adjustment.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Inspecting the air compressor includes checking for which defects?","options":["Loose air compressor drive belt pulley","Loose, cut or frayed air compressor drive belt","Insecure air compressor mounting, bracket or fasteners","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"A brake chamber that includes both service brake and spring brake sections is called a:","options":["Brake chamber","Spring brake chamber","DD3 brake chamber","Service brake chamber"],"correctAnswer":"Spring brake chamber"},{"Question":"Your spring brakes should be used when parking or in an emergency when your service brakes fail?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"The brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum is an example of:","options":["A foundation brake component defect","An issue with the brake chamber","An incorrectly measured pushrod","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"A foundation brake component defect"},{"Question":"A sudden increase in the amount of moisture or oil drained from any air-tank:","options":["Means the system is working correctly","Indicates the governor is faulty","Must be reported and repaired","Indicates an engine oil leak"],"correctAnswer":"Must be reported and repaired"},{"Question":"There is often a noticeable change in the behaviour of brakes with drums or rotors that are defective, cracked or broken.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"A sudden increase in the amount of moisture or oil drained from any air-tank:","options":["Means the system is working correctly","Indicates the governor is faulty","Must be reported and repaired","Indicates an engine oil leak"],"correctAnswer":"Must be reported and repaired"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not exceed:","options":["90 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"145 psi"},{"Question":"In order to make a service brake application?","options":["Pull the yellow button","Pull the red button","Push the brake pedal","Push the red and yellow buttons"],"correctAnswer":"Push the brake pedal"},{"Question":"The Highway Traffic Act and Regulations prohibit the operation of a vehicle with a brake that is out of adjustment.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"For the brakes to work, the brake-shoe lining must be greased and pressed against the brake drum when the brakes are applied.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When inspecting foundation brake components, the driver is expected to be able to identify brake components that are damaged, missing or malfunctioning.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When testing the low air-pressure warning device, the engine can be stopped or running but the ignition must be on.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle\u2019s air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel exceeds the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This is:","options":["A minor defect","A major defect","Within the acceptable adjustment limit","Something to keep track of"],"correctAnswer":"A major defect"},{"Question":"If the compressor takes longer than two minutes to build air from 85 psi to 100 psi, it would be considered a major defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Why should the gladhands be stored properly when not in use?","options":["To keep the seals from cracking","To make them easier to find next time they\u2019re needed","To keep them clean and in good condition","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To keep them clean and in good condition"},{"Question":"If you double your vehicle weight and double your speed, what does your stopping distance increase by?","options":["Four times","Six times","Eight times","Ten times"],"correctAnswer":"Eight times"},{"Question":"What are the three different types of foundation brake systems?","options":["\'S\' cam brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes","ABS brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes","ABS brakes, \'S\' cam brakes, and wedge brakes","\'S\' cam brakes, ABS brakes, and disc brakes"],"correctAnswer":"\'S\' cam brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes"},{"Question":"When testing the air-loss rate of the brake system, the brake application must be held for:","options":["30 seconds","One minute","Two minutes","Three minutes"],"correctAnswer":"One minute"},{"Question":"On a straight truck, tractor, or bus air loss test, what is the acceptable amount of air loss allowed within one minute?","options":["2 psi","3 psi","4 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"3 psi"},{"Question":"What should you do before you exit the vehicle or get underneath it?","options":["Start the vehicle","Secure the vehicle","Grab your safety equipment","Turn off the vehicle"],"correctAnswer":"Secure the vehicle"},{"Question":"Where are air brake chambers located?","options":["At each wheel","At the drive wheels only","At the trailer wheels only","At both the drive and trailer wheels"],"correctAnswer":"At each wheel"},{"Question":"What can indicate that an air tank or mounting bracket is not secure?","options":["Unusual movement","An air leak","A fluid leak","A deflated airbag"],"correctAnswer":"Unusual movement"},{"Question":"Wheels, dust shields, and other parts of the vehicle have no impact on your view of the brake drums and rotors.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What happens if a single brake malfunctions?","options":["It puts more pressure on the other brakes","It causes the other brakes to quickly overheat","It could cause the other brakes to fail","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"If air pressure drops below the normal cut-in setting what should the driver do?","options":["Continue driving until the spring brakes apply","Make several full brake applications","Nothing","Bring the vehicle to a safe stop as soon as possible"],"correctAnswer":"Bring the vehicle to a safe stop as soon as possible"},{"Question":"If any single brake malfunctions, what affect will it have on the other brakes?","options":["None","The malfunctioning brake will overheat causing damage","They will overheat quickly and possibly fail","The braking power will be slightly reduced"],"correctAnswer":"They will overheat quickly and possibly fail"},{"Question":"At what pressure do the spring brakes normally start to apply because there is no longer enough pressure to keep them released?","options":["20 psi","40 psi","60 psi","85 psi"],"correctAnswer":"60 psi"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed when testing the air-loss rate of the brake system on a tractor and trailer?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","6 psi","10 psi"],"correctAnswer":"4 psi"},{"Question":"Testing the performance of your brakes requires performing separate tests of each braking system.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What can cause damage to the foundation brake components?","options":["Debris","Component failure","Deterioration","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Operating a vehicle with defects or failing to conduct the required inspections can result in:","options":["Charges against the driver and/or operator","Detainment or impoundment of the vehicle","Fines","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What safety equipment is recommended while conducting an air brake inspection?","options":["Fire extinguisher, safety glasses, and  protective footwear","Safety glasses, protective headgear, and protective footwear","Protective headgear, ear plugs, and safety glasses","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Safety glasses, protective headgear, and protective footwear"},{"Question":"When testing the air-loss rate of the brake system, the brake pedal must be fully applied.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"The engine must be running when testing the air-loss rate.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"How can air brake chamber air leaks usually be detected?","options":["Visually","Audibly","By checking pushrod travel distance","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Audibly"},{"Question":"When should the supply tank be drained?","options":["First","Last","In whatever order is most convenient for the driver","The supply tank should never be drained"],"correctAnswer":"First"},{"Question":"There is often a noticeable change in the behaviour of brakes with drums or rotors that are defective, cracked or broken.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"If the compressor takes longer than two minutes to build air from 85 psi to 100 psi, it would be considered a major defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"The brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum is an example of:","options":["A foundation brake component defect","An issue with the brake chamber","An incorrectly measured pushrod","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"A foundation brake component defect"},{"Question":"In what order should air tanks be drained?","options":["Wet, primary, secondary","Primary, secondary, wet","Primary, wet, secondary","All at the same time"],"correctAnswer":"Wet, primary, secondary"},{"Question":"What does the air compressor do?","options":["The air compressor draws power from the battery to power the vehicle","The air compressor builds air for the trailer only","The air compressor draws air in and forces it into a smaller space increasing air pressure","The air compressor removes moisture from the air brake system"],"correctAnswer":"The air compressor draws air in and forces it into a smaller space increasing air pressure"},{"Question":"What happens if a single brake malfunctions?","options":["It puts more pressure on the other brakes","It causes the other brakes to quickly overheat","It could cause the other brakes to fail","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"The size of an air brake chamber is based on the area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When the pushrod stroke exceeds the adjustment limit of the brake chamber, the brake:","options":["Is out of adjustment","Is in adjustment","Needs to be replaced","Has a minor defect"],"correctAnswer":"Is out of adjustment"},{"Question":"If the low air-pressure warning device activates below 55 psi, this would be considered a minor defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Air compressors can be inspected with the engine running or stopped.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"A brake chamber that includes both service brake and spring brake sections is called a:","options":["Brake chamber","Spring brake chamber","DD3 brake chamber","Service brake chamber"],"correctAnswer":"Spring brake chamber"},{"Question":"When testing the low air-pressure warning device, the engine can be stopped or running but the ignition must be on.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"In order to make a service brake application?","options":["Pull the yellow button","Pull the red button","Push the brake pedal","Push the red and yellow buttons"],"correctAnswer":"Push the brake pedal"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not be lower than:","options":["60 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"120 psi"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed in one minute on a tractor with two or more trailers?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","5 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"6 psi"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel is within the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This:","options":["Is a minor defect","Is a major defect","Passes the inspection","Is a broken or defective part"],"correctAnswer":"Passes the inspection"},{"Question":"What is a reliable method for inspecting your brake adjustment?","options":["Measuring the applied pushrod stroke","Checking the slack adjustment","Checking the condition of the brake drum","Measuring the brake chamber size"],"correctAnswer":"Measuring the applied pushrod stroke"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the tractor protection valve?","options":["Prevents total air loss from the trailer if the trailer breaks away","Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away","Holds the supply line and emergency line in place not allowing them to break away","Prevents over pressure in the system allowing excess air to escape"],"correctAnswer":"Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away"},{"Question":"Why would a brake chamber need to be \'caged\'?","options":["To move the vehicle in an emergency","To allow for proper braking","To measure your pushrod travel","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To move the vehicle in an emergency"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed when testing the air-loss rate of the brake system on a tractor and trailer?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","6 psi","10 psi"],"correctAnswer":"4 psi"},{"Question":"What do anti-lock braking systems (ABS) do?","options":["Help maintain steering control during emergency braking","Help prevent wheel lock","Do not shorten the stopping distance","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"How would you know if the anti-lock braking system had a malfunction?","options":["The brakes won\'t function at all","The brakes will function intermittently","Only the trailer hand valve functions","The ABS malfunction warning light illuminates"],"correctAnswer":"The ABS malfunction warning light illuminates"},{"Question":"For the brakes to work, the brake-shoe lining must be greased and pressed against the brake drum when the brakes are applied.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When the brakes are applied, a brake malfunction is indicated by the brake lining not contacting the drum.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"If the governor fails to signal the compressor to cut-out what allows the excess air pressure to escape?","options":["The air dryer","A one way check valve","The low pressure warning system","A safety valve"],"correctAnswer":"A safety valve"},{"Question":"Wheels, dust shields, and other parts of the vehicle have no impact on your view of the brake drums and rotors.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When conducting an inspection of the air brake system, be sure to:","options":["Park the vehicle on level ground","Park the vehicle away from traffic","Turn the engine off","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Spring brakes use air to apply the brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Inspecting a vehicle\u2019s air brake chambers includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Audible air leaks","Cracks and non-manufactured holes","Brakes with different air brake chamber sizes on each end of a steering axle","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not be lower than:","options":["60 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"120 psi"},{"Question":"On a straight truck, tractor, or bus air loss test, what is the acceptable amount of air loss allowed within one minute?","options":["2 psi","3 psi","4 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"3 psi"},{"Question":"As brakes heat up, you may experience a reduction in their effectiveness. This is known as:","options":["ABS brakes","Anti-lock braking","Brake fade","Combination braking"],"correctAnswer":"Brake fade"},{"Question":"The air pressure must build from 85 psi to 100 psi in _______?","options":["30 seconds","One minute","Two minutes","Three minutes"],"correctAnswer":"Two minutes"},{"Question":"Brake lining is defective when it is:","options":["Cracked","Missing","Loose","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Spring brakes use air to apply the brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Inspecting the brake components includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum","Damaged, missing or malfunctioning foundation brake components","Cracked, loose, missing or contaminated brake lining, improper drum contact or lining thickness that is less than required","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"A brake chamber that includes both service brake and spring brake sections is called a:","options":["Brake chamber","Spring brake chamber","DD3 brake chamber","Service brake chamber"],"correctAnswer":"Spring brake chamber"},{"Question":"The safety valve will open to allow excess air pressure to escape at a level no higher than?","options":["140 psi","145 psi","150 psi","155 psi"],"correctAnswer":"150 psi"},{"Question":"When should the supply tank be drained?","options":["First","Last","In whatever order is most convenient for the driver","The supply tank should never be drained"],"correctAnswer":"First"},{"Question":"Inspecting the vehicle\u2019s air lines includes checking for the following defects:","options":["Audible air leak","Damage or worn air lines","Improper fittings used to connect or repair an air line","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What should you do before you exit the vehicle or get underneath it?","options":["Start the vehicle","Secure the vehicle","Grab your safety equipment","Turn off the vehicle"],"correctAnswer":"Secure the vehicle"},{"Question":"Failure of the spring brakes to hold the vehicle stationary indicates defective service brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"The Highway Traffic Act and Regulations prohibit the operation of a vehicle with a brake that is out of adjustment.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"In Manitoba, who can perform brake adjustments on manual slack adjusters so the pushrod is less than the adjusted limit?","options":["A licensed driver with an A endorsement or a certified technician","A licensed driver with an S endorsement","The owner for the vehicle","A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"],"correctAnswer":"A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"},{"Question":"When grease or oil is present on the brake lining:","options":["The brake lining is properly lubricated","Abnormal brake behaviour will result","The brake lining has been over-lubricated","The driver can continue to drive the vehicle as it will not cause any issues with brake function"],"correctAnswer":"Abnormal brake behaviour will result"},{"Question":"What is the size of an air brake chamber based on?","options":["The type of chamber","The area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches","The pushrod travel distance","The make and model of the vehicle"],"correctAnswer":"The area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches"},{"Question":"A sudden increase in the amount of moisture or oil drained from any air-tank:","options":["Means the system is working correctly","Indicates the governor is faulty","Must be reported and repaired","Indicates an engine oil leak"],"correctAnswer":"Must be reported and repaired"},{"Question":"How can air brake chamber air leaks usually be detected?","options":["Visually","Audibly","By checking pushrod travel distance","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Audibly"},{"Question":"The first air tank that air enters is called the supply (wet tank).","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When testing brake performance (tug tests), it would be considered a major defect if:","options":["The spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle in place","The service brakes fail to stop the vehicle","Only if the tractor spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle","Both A and B"],"correctAnswer":"Both A and B"},{"Question":"A brake chamber that includes both service brake and spring brake sections is called a:","options":["Brake chamber","Spring brake chamber","DD3 brake chamber","Service brake chamber"],"correctAnswer":"Spring brake chamber"},{"Question":"When testing the tractor protection system, the trailer supply valve must close before the pressure drops below:","options":["20 psi","55 psi","60 psi","100 psi"],"correctAnswer":"20 psi"},{"Question":"What can indicate that an air tank or mounting bracket is not secure?","options":["Unusual movement","An air leak","A fluid leak","A deflated airbag"],"correctAnswer":"Unusual movement"},{"Question":"The vehicle must be secured by the spring brakes or by wheel chocks before leaving the driver\u2019s seat or going under the vehicle.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Brake lining is defective when it is:","options":["Cracked","Missing","Loose","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Automatic slack adjusters, if working properly, require regular re-adjustment.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"The brake on each end of an axel should have a different sized air brake chamber to ensure brake forces are balanced.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When testing the air-loss rate of the brake system, the brake pedal must be fully applied.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When the pushrod stroke exceeds the adjustment limit of the brake chamber, the brake:","options":["Is out of adjustment","Is in adjustment","Needs to be replaced","Has a minor defect"],"correctAnswer":"Is out of adjustment"},{"Question":"Actual cut-in pressure for the governor should never be less than 90 PSI?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When damage extends into the reinforcing or inner layer, the air line is defective.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When inspecting foundation brake components, the driver is expected to be able to identify brake components that are damaged, missing or malfunctioning.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"If air loss exceeds the maximum allowable limit specified for your vehicle, it would be considered a major defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Vehicles with air brakes must comply with The Highway Traffic Act and Regulations. If a vehicle does not comply, both the driver and the operator may be charged.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When checking the buildup rate (compressor operation) the engine should be building air pressure from _____ psi to ____ psi within two minutes:","options":["45 - 65","65 - 85","85 - 100","100 - 125"],"correctAnswer":"85 - 100"},{"Question":"A sudden increase in the amount of moisture or oil drained from any air-tank:","options":["Means the system is working correctly","Indicates the governor is faulty","Must be reported and repaired","Indicates an engine oil leak"],"correctAnswer":"Must be reported and repaired"},{"Question":"At what pressure do the spring brakes normally start to apply because there is no longer enough pressure to keep them released?","options":["20 psi","40 psi","60 psi","85 psi"],"correctAnswer":"60 psi"},{"Question":"What should you do before you exit the vehicle or get underneath it?","options":["Start the vehicle","Secure the vehicle","Grab your safety equipment","Turn off the vehicle"],"correctAnswer":"Secure the vehicle"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed when testing the air-loss rate of the brake system on a tractor and trailer?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","6 psi","10 psi"],"correctAnswer":"4 psi"},{"Question":"Failure of the spring brakes to hold the vehicle stationary indicates defective service brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"There is often a noticeable change in the behaviour of brakes with drums or rotors that are defective, cracked or broken.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed in one minute on a tractor with two or more trailers?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","5 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"6 psi"},{"Question":"Actual cut-in pressure for the governor should never be less than 90 PSI?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Operating a vehicle with defects or failing to conduct the required inspections can result in:","options":["Charges against the driver and/or operator","Detainment or impoundment of the vehicle","Fines","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"In order to make a service brake application?","options":["Pull the yellow button","Pull the red button","Push the brake pedal","Push the red and yellow buttons"],"correctAnswer":"Push the brake pedal"},{"Question":"Older air systems may operate with lower pressure settings.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Spring brakes use air to apply the brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"How often is it recommended that the air tanks be drained?","options":["At the beginning of every trip","At the end of every trip","Every day","Once a week"],"correctAnswer":"Every day"},{"Question":"As brakes heat up, you may experience a reduction in their effectiveness. This is known as:","options":["ABS brakes","Anti-lock braking","Brake fade","Combination braking"],"correctAnswer":"Brake fade"},{"Question":"Testing the performance of your brakes requires performing separate tests of each braking system.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"The vehicle must be secured by the spring brakes or by wheel chocks before leaving the driver\u2019s seat or going under the vehicle.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"The Highway Traffic Act and Regulations prohibit the operation of a vehicle with a brake that is out of adjustment.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"A spring brake control valve is usually yellow?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When the brakes are applied, a brake malfunction is indicated by the brake lining not contacting the drum.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"If air exhausts from the service line, it means that the trailer supply valve is defective.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What does the air compressor do?","options":["The air compressor draws power from the battery to power the vehicle","The air compressor builds air for the trailer only","The air compressor draws air in and forces it into a smaller space increasing air pressure","The air compressor removes moisture from the air brake system"],"correctAnswer":"The air compressor draws air in and forces it into a smaller space increasing air pressure"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the governor?","options":["The governor causes the compressor to start and stop pumping air (cut-in and cut-out)","The governor controls the amount of moisture the air dryer removes from the system","Once air flows through the supply tank, the governor prevents it from returning","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"The governor causes the compressor to start and stop pumping air (cut-in and cut-out)"},{"Question":"To ensure balanced braking, slack adjusters on each side of an axel should:","options":["Be the same effective lengths","Have no more than 1 inch difference","Be attached using different holes","Both B and C"],"correctAnswer":"Be the same effective lengths"},{"Question":"If any single brake malfunctions, what affect will it have on the other brakes?","options":["None","The malfunctioning brake will overheat causing damage","They will overheat quickly and possibly fail","The braking power will be slightly reduced"],"correctAnswer":"They will overheat quickly and possibly fail"},{"Question":"In Manitoba, who can perform brake adjustments on manual slack adjusters so the pushrod is less than the adjusted limit?","options":["A licensed driver with an A endorsement or a certified technician","A licensed driver with an S endorsement","The owner for the vehicle","A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"],"correctAnswer":"A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"},{"Question":"Why would a brake chamber need to be \'caged\'?","options":["To move the vehicle in an emergency","To allow for proper braking","To measure your pushrod travel","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To move the vehicle in an emergency"},{"Question":"Who is responsible for ensuring air brakes are correctly adjusted?","options":["The employer","The manufacturer","The last person driving the vehicle","The current driver"],"correctAnswer":"The current driver"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the safety valve?","options":["Starts building air pressure at 100 psi","Stops building air pressure at 140 psi","Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting","Ensures the trucks safety features are working correctly"],"correctAnswer":"Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting"},{"Question":"Actual cut-in pressure of the governor should never be less than:","options":["55 psi","80 psi","100 psi","120 psi"],"correctAnswer":"100 psi"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not be lower than:","options":["60 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"120 psi"},{"Question":"When testing the tractor protection system, the trailer supply valve must close before the pressure drops below:","options":["20 psi","55 psi","60 psi","100 psi"],"correctAnswer":"20 psi"},{"Question":"On a straight truck, tractor, or bus air loss test, what is the acceptable amount of air loss allowed within one minute?","options":["2 psi","3 psi","4 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"3 psi"},{"Question":"Failure of the spring brakes to hold the vehicle stationary indicates defective service brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When checking the buildup rate (compressor operation) the engine should be building air pressure from _____ psi to ____ psi within two minutes:","options":["45 - 65","65 - 85","85 - 100","100 - 125"],"correctAnswer":"85 - 100"},{"Question":"Older air systems may operate with lower pressure settings.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What is a reliable method for inspecting your brake adjustment?","options":["Measuring the applied pushrod stroke","Checking the slack adjustment","Checking the condition of the brake drum","Measuring the brake chamber size"],"correctAnswer":"Measuring the applied pushrod stroke"},{"Question":"The size of an air brake chamber is based on the area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"The vehicle must be secured by the spring brakes or by wheel chocks before leaving the driver\u2019s seat or going under the vehicle.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"The engine must be running when testing the air-loss rate.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When the pushrod stroke exceeds the adjustment limit of the brake chamber, the brake:","options":["Is out of adjustment","Is in adjustment","Needs to be replaced","Has a minor defect"],"correctAnswer":"Is out of adjustment"},{"Question":"Damaged or worn air lines are not a concern until they have an obvious leak.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"If the compressor takes longer than two minutes to build air from 85 psi to 100 psi, it would be considered a major defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Inspecting the vehicle\u2019s air lines includes checking for the following defects:","options":["Audible air leak","Damage or worn air lines","Improper fittings used to connect or repair an air line","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"The brake on each end of an axel should have a different sized air brake chamber to ensure brake forces are balanced.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle\u2019s air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel exceeds the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This is:","options":["A minor defect","A major defect","Within the acceptable adjustment limit","Something to keep track of"],"correctAnswer":"A major defect"},{"Question":"Wheels, dust shields, and other parts of the vehicle have no impact on your view of the brake drums and rotors.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"On a straight truck, tractor, or bus air loss test, what is the acceptable amount of air loss allowed within one minute?","options":["2 psi","3 psi","4 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"3 psi"},{"Question":"When testing the air-loss rate of the brake system, the brake pedal must be fully applied.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What should the air pressure be when performing a brake adjustment inspection at each wheel?","options":["Between 80 - 90 psi","Between 90 - 100 psi","Between 100 - 110 psi","At maximum pressure"],"correctAnswer":"Between 90 - 100 psi"},{"Question":"Testing the performance of your brakes requires performing separate tests of each braking system.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What safety equipment is recommended while conducting an air brake inspection?","options":["Fire extinguisher, safety glasses, and  protective footwear","Safety glasses, protective headgear, and protective footwear","Protective headgear, ear plugs, and safety glasses","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Safety glasses, protective headgear, and protective footwear"},{"Question":"What can indicate that an air tank or mounting bracket is not secure?","options":["Unusual movement","An air leak","A fluid leak","A deflated airbag"],"correctAnswer":"Unusual movement"},{"Question":"Vehicles with air brakes must comply with The Highway Traffic Act and Regulations. If a vehicle does not comply, both the driver and the operator may be charged.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"As brakes heat up, you may experience a reduction in their effectiveness. This is known as:","options":["ABS brakes","Anti-lock braking","Brake fade","Combination braking"],"correctAnswer":"Brake fade"},{"Question":"For the brakes to work, the brake-shoe lining must be greased and pressed against the brake drum when the brakes are applied.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"If air exhausts from the service line, it means that the trailer supply valve is defective.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Operating a vehicle with defects or failing to conduct the required inspections can result in:","options":["Charges against the driver and/or operator","Detainment or impoundment of the vehicle","Fines","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What is the size of an air brake chamber based on?","options":["The type of chamber","The area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches","The pushrod travel distance","The make and model of the vehicle"],"correctAnswer":"The area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches"},{"Question":"When testing the air-loss rate of the brake system, the brake application must be held for:","options":["30 seconds","One minute","Two minutes","Three minutes"],"correctAnswer":"One minute"},{"Question":"The first air tank that air enters is called the supply (wet tank).","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"How often is it recommended that the air tanks be drained?","options":["At the beginning of every trip","At the end of every trip","Every day","Once a week"],"correctAnswer":"Every day"},{"Question":"Air brake chambers from different manufacturers may look different even if they are the same size.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Inspecting the vehicle\u2019s air lines includes checking for the following defects:","options":["Audible air leak","Damage or worn air lines","Improper fittings used to connect or repair an air line","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"The brake on each end of an axel should have a different sized air brake chamber to ensure brake forces are balanced.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed when testing the air-loss rate of the brake system on a tractor and trailer?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","6 psi","10 psi"],"correctAnswer":"4 psi"},{"Question":"What happens when the trailer lines are not connected properly?","options":["Spring brakes may not release","The towing vehicle may lose air","Service brakes will not function properly","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"When conducting an inspection of the air brake system, be sure to:","options":["Park the vehicle on level ground","Park the vehicle away from traffic","Turn the engine off","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"In order to make a service brake application?","options":["Pull the yellow button","Pull the red button","Push the brake pedal","Push the red and yellow buttons"],"correctAnswer":"Push the brake pedal"},{"Question":"To ensure balanced braking, slack adjusters on each side of an axel should:","options":["Be the same effective lengths","Have no more than 1 inch difference","Be attached using different holes","Both B and C"],"correctAnswer":"Be the same effective lengths"},{"Question":"There is often a noticeable change in the behaviour of brakes with drums or rotors that are defective, cracked or broken.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When grease or oil is present on the brake lining:","options":["The brake lining is properly lubricated","Abnormal brake behaviour will result","The brake lining has been over-lubricated","The driver can continue to drive the vehicle as it will not cause any issues with brake function"],"correctAnswer":"Abnormal brake behaviour will result"},{"Question":"If the compressor takes longer than two minutes to build air from 85 psi to 100 psi, it would be considered a major defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"If the governor fails to signal the compressor to cut-out what allows the excess air pressure to escape?","options":["The air dryer","A one way check valve","The low pressure warning system","A safety valve"],"correctAnswer":"A safety valve"},{"Question":"If air loss exceeds the maximum allowable limit specified for your vehicle, it would be considered a major defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What is the size of an air brake chamber based on?","options":["The type of chamber","The area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches","The pushrod travel distance","The make and model of the vehicle"],"correctAnswer":"The area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches"},{"Question":"A brake chamber that includes both service brake and spring brake sections is called a:","options":["Brake chamber","Spring brake chamber","DD3 brake chamber","Service brake chamber"],"correctAnswer":"Spring brake chamber"},{"Question":"An inspection of a vehicle\u2019s brake drums and rotors includes checking for the following defect:","options":["Cracked or broken brake drums","Cracked or broken rotors","Both A and B","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Both A and B"},{"Question":"Inspecting a vehicle\u2019s air brake chambers includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Audible air leaks","Cracks and non-manufactured holes","Brakes with different air brake chamber sizes on each end of a steering axle","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Older air systems may operate with lower pressure settings.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What is a reliable method for inspecting your brake adjustment?","options":["Measuring the applied pushrod stroke","Checking the slack adjustment","Checking the condition of the brake drum","Measuring the brake chamber size"],"correctAnswer":"Measuring the applied pushrod stroke"},{"Question":"Testing the performance of your brakes requires performing separate tests of each braking system.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Failure of the spring brakes to hold the vehicle stationary indicates defective service brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not exceed:","options":["90 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"145 psi"},{"Question":"What controls an air brake system\u2019s pressure range (cut-in and cut-out settings)?","options":["The governor","The compressor","The engine","The turbo-charger"],"correctAnswer":"The governor"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel is within the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This:","options":["Is a minor defect","Is a major defect","Passes the inspection","Is a broken or defective part"],"correctAnswer":"Passes the inspection"},{"Question":"What does ABS stand for?","options":["Automatic Brake Stop","Automatic Braking System","Anti-lock Brake System","Accelerated Braking System"],"correctAnswer":"Anti-lock Brake System"},{"Question":"If air loss exceeds the maximum allowable limit specified for your vehicle, it would be considered a major defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"As brakes heat up, you may experience a reduction in their effectiveness. This is known as:","options":["ABS brakes","Anti-lock braking","Brake fade","Combination braking"],"correctAnswer":"Brake fade"},{"Question":"The size of an air brake chamber is based on the area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Why should the gladhands be stored properly when not in use?","options":["To keep the seals from cracking","To make them easier to find next time they\u2019re needed","To keep them clean and in good condition","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To keep them clean and in good condition"},{"Question":"An inspection of a vehicle\u2019s brake drums and rotors includes checking for the following defect:","options":["Cracked or broken brake drums","Cracked or broken rotors","Both A and B","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Both A and B"},{"Question":"In Manitoba, who can perform brake adjustments on manual slack adjusters so the pushrod is less than the adjusted limit?","options":["A licensed driver with an A endorsement or a certified technician","A licensed driver with an S endorsement","The owner for the vehicle","A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"],"correctAnswer":"A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"},{"Question":"What is a reliable method for inspecting your brake adjustment?","options":["Measuring the applied pushrod stroke","Checking the slack adjustment","Checking the condition of the brake drum","Measuring the brake chamber size"],"correctAnswer":"Measuring the applied pushrod stroke"},{"Question":"When the pushrod stroke exceeds the adjustment limit of the brake chamber, the brake:","options":["Is out of adjustment","Is in adjustment","Needs to be replaced","Has a minor defect"],"correctAnswer":"Is out of adjustment"},{"Question":"When conducting an inspection of the air brake system, be sure to:","options":["Park the vehicle on level ground","Park the vehicle away from traffic","Turn the engine off","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Failure of the spring brakes to hold the vehicle stationary indicates defective service brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed when testing the air-loss rate of the brake system on a tractor and trailer?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","6 psi","10 psi"],"correctAnswer":"4 psi"},{"Question":"There is often a noticeable change in the behaviour of brakes with drums or rotors that are defective, cracked or broken.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What should the air pressure be when performing a brake adjustment inspection at each wheel?","options":["Between 80 - 90 psi","Between 90 - 100 psi","Between 100 - 110 psi","At maximum pressure"],"correctAnswer":"Between 90 - 100 psi"},{"Question":"At what pressure do the spring brakes normally start to apply because there is no longer enough pressure to keep them released?","options":["20 psi","40 psi","60 psi","85 psi"],"correctAnswer":"60 psi"},{"Question":"If the low air-pressure warning device activates below 55 psi, this would be considered a minor defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"How often is it recommended that the air tanks be drained?","options":["At the beginning of every trip","At the end of every trip","Every day","Once a week"],"correctAnswer":"Every day"},{"Question":"Brake lining is defective when it is:","options":["Cracked","Missing","Loose","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Who is responsible for ensuring air brakes are correctly adjusted?","options":["The employer","The manufacturer","The last person driving the vehicle","The current driver"],"correctAnswer":"The current driver"},{"Question":"Spring brakes use air to apply the brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"The air pressure must build from 85 psi to 100 psi in _______?","options":["30 seconds","One minute","Two minutes","Three minutes"],"correctAnswer":"Two minutes"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not exceed:","options":["90 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"145 psi"},{"Question":"Actual cut-in pressure of the governor should never be less than:","options":["55 psi","80 psi","100 psi","120 psi"],"correctAnswer":"100 psi"},{"Question":"Automatic slack adjusters, if working properly, require regular re-adjustment.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"An inspection of a vehicle\u2019s brake drums and rotors includes checking for the following defect:","options":["Cracked or broken brake drums","Cracked or broken rotors","Both A and B","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Both A and B"},{"Question":"What does the air compressor do?","options":["The air compressor draws power from the battery to power the vehicle","The air compressor builds air for the trailer only","The air compressor draws air in and forces it into a smaller space increasing air pressure","The air compressor removes moisture from the air brake system"],"correctAnswer":"The air compressor draws air in and forces it into a smaller space increasing air pressure"},{"Question":"The size of an air brake chamber is based on the area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Air brake chambers from different manufacturers may look different even if they are the same size.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When testing the air-loss rate of the brake system, the brake application must be held for:","options":["30 seconds","One minute","Two minutes","Three minutes"],"correctAnswer":"One minute"},{"Question":"How often is it recommended that the air tanks be drained?","options":["At the beginning of every trip","At the end of every trip","Every day","Once a week"],"correctAnswer":"Every day"},{"Question":"What does ABS stand for?","options":["Automatic Brake Stop","Automatic Braking System","Anti-lock Brake System","Accelerated Braking System"],"correctAnswer":"Anti-lock Brake System"},{"Question":"Air compressors can be inspected with the engine running or stopped.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Inspecting a vehicle\u2019s air lines includes checking for the following defects:","options":["Audible air leak","Damaged or worn air lines","Improper fittings used to connect or repair air lines","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Older air systems may operate with lower pressure settings.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the safety valve?","options":["Starts building air pressure at 100 psi","Stops building air pressure at 140 psi","Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting","Ensures the trucks safety features are working correctly"],"correctAnswer":"Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting"},{"Question":"When testing brake performance (tug tests), it would be considered a major defect if:","options":["The spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle in place","The service brakes fail to stop the vehicle","Only if the tractor spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle","Both A and B"],"correctAnswer":"Both A and B"},{"Question":"The first air tank that air enters is called the supply (wet tank).","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What should the air pressure be when performing a brake adjustment inspection at each wheel?","options":["Between 80 - 90 psi","Between 90 - 100 psi","Between 100 - 110 psi","At maximum pressure"],"correctAnswer":"Between 90 - 100 psi"},{"Question":"In what order should air tanks be drained?","options":["Wet, primary, secondary","Primary, secondary, wet","Primary, wet, secondary","All at the same time"],"correctAnswer":"Wet, primary, secondary"},{"Question":"When should the supply tank be drained?","options":["First","Last","In whatever order is most convenient for the driver","The supply tank should never be drained"],"correctAnswer":"First"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel is within the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This:","options":["Is a minor defect","Is a major defect","Passes the inspection","Is a broken or defective part"],"correctAnswer":"Passes the inspection"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the safety valve?","options":["Starts building air pressure at 100 psi","Stops building air pressure at 140 psi","Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting","Ensures the trucks safety features are working correctly"],"correctAnswer":"Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting"},{"Question":"Damaged or worn air lines are not a concern until they have an obvious leak.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What do anti-lock braking systems (ABS) do?","options":["Help maintain steering control during emergency braking","Help prevent wheel lock","Do not shorten the stopping distance","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Air brake chambers from different manufacturers may look different even if they are the same size.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"As brakes heat up, you may experience a reduction in their effectiveness. This is known as:","options":["ABS brakes","Anti-lock braking","Brake fade","Combination braking"],"correctAnswer":"Brake fade"},{"Question":"What are the three different types of foundation brake systems?","options":["\'S\' cam brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes","ABS brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes","ABS brakes, \'S\' cam brakes, and wedge brakes","\'S\' cam brakes, ABS brakes, and disc brakes"],"correctAnswer":"\'S\' cam brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the tractor protection valve?","options":["Prevents total air loss from the trailer if the trailer breaks away","Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away","Holds the supply line and emergency line in place not allowing them to break away","Prevents over pressure in the system allowing excess air to escape"],"correctAnswer":"Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away"},{"Question":"The first air tank that air enters is called the supply (wet tank).","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What does ABS stand for?","options":["Automatic Brake Stop","Automatic Braking System","Anti-lock Brake System","Accelerated Braking System"],"correctAnswer":"Anti-lock Brake System"},{"Question":"If any single brake malfunctions, what affect will it have on the other brakes?","options":["None","The malfunctioning brake will overheat causing damage","They will overheat quickly and possibly fail","The braking power will be slightly reduced"],"correctAnswer":"They will overheat quickly and possibly fail"},{"Question":"When grease or oil is present on the brake lining:","options":["The brake lining is properly lubricated","Abnormal brake behaviour will result","The brake lining has been over-lubricated","The driver can continue to drive the vehicle as it will not cause any issues with brake function"],"correctAnswer":"Abnormal brake behaviour will result"},{"Question":"If the compressor takes longer than two minutes to build air from 85 psi to 100 psi, it would be considered a major defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Inspecting the brake components includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum","Damaged, missing or malfunctioning foundation brake components","Cracked, loose, missing or contaminated brake lining, improper drum contact or lining thickness that is less than required","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Testing the performance of your brakes requires performing separate tests of each braking system.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What happens if a single brake malfunctions?","options":["It puts more pressure on the other brakes","It causes the other brakes to quickly overheat","It could cause the other brakes to fail","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"For the brakes to work, the brake-shoe lining must be greased and pressed against the brake drum when the brakes are applied.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"There is often a noticeable change in the behaviour of brakes with drums or rotors that are defective, cracked or broken.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"The brake on each end of an axel should have a different sized air brake chamber to ensure brake forces are balanced.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"The engine must be running when testing the air-loss rate.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"The air pressure must build from 85 psi to 100 psi in _______?","options":["30 seconds","One minute","Two minutes","Three minutes"],"correctAnswer":"Two minutes"},{"Question":"Inspecting the brake components includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum","Damaged, missing or malfunctioning foundation brake components","Cracked, loose, missing or contaminated brake lining, improper drum contact or lining thickness that is less than required","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What happens when the trailer lines are not connected properly?","options":["Spring brakes may not release","The towing vehicle may lose air","Service brakes will not function properly","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Testing the performance of your brakes requires performing separate tests of each braking system.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"How often is it recommended that the air tanks be drained?","options":["At the beginning of every trip","At the end of every trip","Every day","Once a week"],"correctAnswer":"Every day"},{"Question":"When conducting an inspection of the air brake system, be sure to:","options":["Park the vehicle on level ground","Park the vehicle away from traffic","Turn the engine off","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Why are automatic slack adjusters used?","options":["They make inspections and adjustments unnecessary","As a backup to a manual slack adjuster","To avoid the need to regularly perform manual re-adjustments","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To avoid the need to regularly perform manual re-adjustments"},{"Question":"When testing the air-loss rate of the brake system, the brake pedal must be fully applied.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Brake lining is defective when it is:","options":["Cracked","Missing","Loose","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle\u2019s air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel exceeds the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This is:","options":["A minor defect","A major defect","Within the acceptable adjustment limit","Something to keep track of"],"correctAnswer":"A major defect"},{"Question":"What controls an air brake system\u2019s pressure range (cut-in and cut-out settings)?","options":["The governor","The compressor","The engine","The turbo-charger"],"correctAnswer":"The governor"},{"Question":"What should the air pressure be when performing a brake adjustment inspection at each wheel?","options":["Between 80 - 90 psi","Between 90 - 100 psi","Between 100 - 110 psi","At maximum pressure"],"correctAnswer":"Between 90 - 100 psi"},{"Question":"At what pressure do the spring brakes normally start to apply because there is no longer enough pressure to keep them released?","options":["20 psi","40 psi","60 psi","85 psi"],"correctAnswer":"60 psi"},{"Question":"The Highway Traffic Act and Regulations prohibit the operation of a vehicle with a brake that is out of adjustment.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel is within the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This:","options":["Is a minor defect","Is a major defect","Passes the inspection","Is a broken or defective part"],"correctAnswer":"Passes the inspection"},{"Question":"The brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum is an example of:","options":["A foundation brake component defect","An issue with the brake chamber","An incorrectly measured pushrod","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"A foundation brake component defect"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the tractor protection valve?","options":["Prevents total air loss from the trailer if the trailer breaks away","Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away","Holds the supply line and emergency line in place not allowing them to break away","Prevents over pressure in the system allowing excess air to escape"],"correctAnswer":"Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away"},{"Question":"Your spring brakes should be used when parking or in an emergency when your service brakes fail?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What can indicate that an air tank or mounting bracket is not secure?","options":["Unusual movement","An air leak","A fluid leak","A deflated airbag"],"correctAnswer":"Unusual movement"},{"Question":"What should the air pressure be when performing a brake adjustment inspection at each wheel?","options":["Between 80 - 90 psi","Between 90 - 100 psi","Between 100 - 110 psi","At maximum pressure"],"correctAnswer":"Between 90 - 100 psi"},{"Question":"When the pushrod stroke exceeds the adjustment limit of the brake chamber, the brake:","options":["Is out of adjustment","Is in adjustment","Needs to be replaced","Has a minor defect"],"correctAnswer":"Is out of adjustment"},{"Question":"What should you do before you exit the vehicle or get underneath it?","options":["Start the vehicle","Secure the vehicle","Grab your safety equipment","Turn off the vehicle"],"correctAnswer":"Secure the vehicle"},{"Question":"The brake on each end of an axel should have a different sized air brake chamber to ensure brake forces are balanced.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When testing the air-loss rate of the brake system, the brake pedal must be fully applied.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed when testing the air-loss rate of the brake system on a tractor and trailer?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","6 psi","10 psi"],"correctAnswer":"4 psi"},{"Question":"In what order should air tanks be drained?","options":["Wet, primary, secondary","Primary, secondary, wet","Primary, wet, secondary","All at the same time"],"correctAnswer":"Wet, primary, secondary"},{"Question":"Where are air brake chambers located?","options":["At each wheel","At the drive wheels only","At the trailer wheels only","At both the drive and trailer wheels"],"correctAnswer":"At each wheel"},{"Question":"When testing brake performance (tug tests), it would be considered a major defect if:","options":["The spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle in place","The service brakes fail to stop the vehicle","Only if the tractor spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle","Both A and B"],"correctAnswer":"Both A and B"},{"Question":"When the brakes are applied, a brake malfunction is indicated by the brake lining not contacting the drum.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not be lower than:","options":["60 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"120 psi"},{"Question":"Inspecting the air compressor includes checking for which defects?","options":["Loose air compressor drive belt pulley","Loose, cut or frayed air compressor drive belt","Insecure air compressor mounting, bracket or fasteners","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"When inspecting foundation brake components, the driver is expected to be able to identify brake components that are damaged, missing or malfunctioning.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What can indicate that an air tank or mounting bracket is not secure?","options":["Unusual movement","An air leak","A fluid leak","A deflated airbag"],"correctAnswer":"Unusual movement"},{"Question":"The safety valve will open to allow excess air pressure to escape at a level no higher than?","options":["140 psi","145 psi","150 psi","155 psi"],"correctAnswer":"150 psi"},{"Question":"Older air systems may operate with lower pressure settings.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"For the brakes to work, the brake-shoe lining must be greased and pressed against the brake drum when the brakes are applied.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What can cause damage to the foundation brake components?","options":["Debris","Component failure","Deterioration","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"The Highway Traffic Act and Regulations prohibit the operation of a vehicle with a brake that is out of adjustment.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"If air exhausts from the service line, it means that the trailer supply valve is defective.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Testing the performance of your brakes requires performing separate tests of each braking system.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Inspecting a vehicle\u2019s air brake chambers includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Audible air leaks","Cracks and non-manufactured holes","Brakes with different air brake chamber sizes on each end of a steering axle","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"When the pushrod stroke exceeds the adjustment limit of the brake chamber, the brake:","options":["Is out of adjustment","Is in adjustment","Needs to be replaced","Has a minor defect"],"correctAnswer":"Is out of adjustment"},{"Question":"The safety valve will open to allow excess air pressure to escape at a level no higher than?","options":["140 psi","145 psi","150 psi","155 psi"],"correctAnswer":"150 psi"},{"Question":"At what level must the low pressure warning device activate?","options":["At or above 60 psi","Between 40 - 50 psi","At or above 85 psi","At or above 55 psi"],"correctAnswer":"At or above 55 psi"},{"Question":"If you double your vehicle weight and double your speed, what does your stopping distance increase by?","options":["Four times","Six times","Eight times","Ten times"],"correctAnswer":"Eight times"},{"Question":"When grease or oil is present on the brake lining:","options":["The brake lining is properly lubricated","Abnormal brake behaviour will result","The brake lining has been over-lubricated","The driver can continue to drive the vehicle as it will not cause any issues with brake function"],"correctAnswer":"Abnormal brake behaviour will result"},{"Question":"What should you do before you exit the vehicle or get underneath it?","options":["Start the vehicle","Secure the vehicle","Grab your safety equipment","Turn off the vehicle"],"correctAnswer":"Secure the vehicle"},{"Question":"What can cause damage to the foundation brake components?","options":["Debris","Component failure","Deterioration","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"As brakes heat up, you may experience a reduction in their effectiveness. This is known as:","options":["ABS brakes","Anti-lock braking","Brake fade","Combination braking"],"correctAnswer":"Brake fade"},{"Question":"What safety equipment is recommended while conducting an air brake inspection?","options":["Fire extinguisher, safety glasses, and  protective footwear","Safety glasses, protective headgear, and protective footwear","Protective headgear, ear plugs, and safety glasses","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Safety glasses, protective headgear, and protective footwear"},{"Question":"Why should the gladhands be stored properly when not in use?","options":["To keep the seals from cracking","To make them easier to find next time they\u2019re needed","To keep them clean and in good condition","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To keep them clean and in good condition"},{"Question":"What can indicate that an air tank or mounting bracket is not secure?","options":["Unusual movement","An air leak","A fluid leak","A deflated airbag"],"correctAnswer":"Unusual movement"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed in one minute on a tractor with two or more trailers?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","5 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"6 psi"},{"Question":"For the brakes to work, the brake-shoe lining must be greased and pressed against the brake drum when the brakes are applied.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When testing the air-loss rate of the brake system, the brake application must be held for:","options":["30 seconds","One minute","Two minutes","Three minutes"],"correctAnswer":"One minute"},{"Question":"The size of an air brake chamber is based on the area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Failure of the spring brakes to hold the vehicle stationary indicates defective service brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What is a reliable method for inspecting your brake adjustment?","options":["Measuring the applied pushrod stroke","Checking the slack adjustment","Checking the condition of the brake drum","Measuring the brake chamber size"],"correctAnswer":"Measuring the applied pushrod stroke"},{"Question":"Why would a brake chamber need to be \'caged\'?","options":["To move the vehicle in an emergency","To allow for proper braking","To measure your pushrod travel","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To move the vehicle in an emergency"},{"Question":"Wheels, dust shields, and other parts of the vehicle have no impact on your view of the brake drums and rotors.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Inspecting a vehicle\u2019s air lines includes checking for the following defects:","options":["Audible air leak","Damaged or worn air lines","Improper fittings used to connect or repair air lines","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"The brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum is an example of:","options":["A foundation brake component defect","An issue with the brake chamber","An incorrectly measured pushrod","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"A foundation brake component defect"},{"Question":"Older air systems may operate with lower pressure settings.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"How would you know if the anti-lock braking system had a malfunction?","options":["The brakes won\'t function at all","The brakes will function intermittently","Only the trailer hand valve functions","The ABS malfunction warning light illuminates"],"correctAnswer":"The ABS malfunction warning light illuminates"},{"Question":"When testing the air-loss rate of the brake system, the brake application must be held for:","options":["30 seconds","One minute","Two minutes","Three minutes"],"correctAnswer":"One minute"},{"Question":"On a straight truck, tractor, or bus air loss test, what is the acceptable amount of air loss allowed within one minute?","options":["2 psi","3 psi","4 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"3 psi"},{"Question":"The vehicle must be secured by the spring brakes or by wheel chocks before leaving the driver\u2019s seat or going under the vehicle.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the safety valve?","options":["Starts building air pressure at 100 psi","Stops building air pressure at 140 psi","Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting","Ensures the trucks safety features are working correctly"],"correctAnswer":"Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting"},{"Question":"A sudden increase in the amount of moisture or oil drained from any air-tank:","options":["Means the system is working correctly","Indicates the governor is faulty","Must be reported and repaired","Indicates an engine oil leak"],"correctAnswer":"Must be reported and repaired"},{"Question":"To ensure balanced braking, slack adjusters on each side of an axel should:","options":["Be the same effective lengths","Have no more than 1 inch difference","Be attached using different holes","Both B and C"],"correctAnswer":"Be the same effective lengths"},{"Question":"What are the three different types of foundation brake systems?","options":["\'S\' cam brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes","ABS brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes","ABS brakes, \'S\' cam brakes, and wedge brakes","\'S\' cam brakes, ABS brakes, and disc brakes"],"correctAnswer":"\'S\' cam brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes"},{"Question":"How can air brake chamber air leaks usually be detected?","options":["Visually","Audibly","By checking pushrod travel distance","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Audibly"},{"Question":"What is the size of an air brake chamber based on?","options":["The type of chamber","The area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches","The pushrod travel distance","The make and model of the vehicle"],"correctAnswer":"The area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches"},{"Question":"Inspecting the air compressor includes checking for which defects?","options":["Loose air compressor drive belt pulley","Loose, cut or frayed air compressor drive belt","Insecure air compressor mounting, bracket or fasteners","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Inspecting a vehicle\u2019s air brake chambers includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Audible air leaks","Cracks and non-manufactured holes","Brakes with different air brake chamber sizes on each end of a steering axle","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"A spring brake control valve is usually yellow?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"At what level must the low pressure warning device activate?","options":["At or above 60 psi","Between 40 - 50 psi","At or above 85 psi","At or above 55 psi"],"correctAnswer":"At or above 55 psi"},{"Question":"When inspecting foundation brake components, the driver is expected to be able to identify brake components that are damaged, missing or malfunctioning.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Air brake chambers from different manufacturers may look different even if they are the same size.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not be lower than:","options":["60 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"120 psi"},{"Question":"Damaged or worn air lines are not a concern until they have an obvious leak.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"For the brakes to work, the brake-shoe lining must be greased and pressed against the brake drum when the brakes are applied.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When checking the buildup rate (compressor operation) the engine should be building air pressure from _____ psi to ____ psi within two minutes:","options":["45 - 65","65 - 85","85 - 100","100 - 125"],"correctAnswer":"85 - 100"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the safety valve?","options":["Starts building air pressure at 100 psi","Stops building air pressure at 140 psi","Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting","Ensures the trucks safety features are working correctly"],"correctAnswer":"Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting"},{"Question":"A brake chamber that includes both service brake and spring brake sections is called a:","options":["Brake chamber","Spring brake chamber","DD3 brake chamber","Service brake chamber"],"correctAnswer":"Spring brake chamber"},{"Question":"When testing the tractor protection system, the trailer supply valve must close before the pressure drops below:","options":["20 psi","55 psi","60 psi","100 psi"],"correctAnswer":"20 psi"},{"Question":"When testing the low air-pressure warning device, the engine can be stopped or running but the ignition must be on.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Inspecting the brake components includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum","Damaged, missing or malfunctioning foundation brake components","Cracked, loose, missing or contaminated brake lining, improper drum contact or lining thickness that is less than required","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What are the three different types of foundation brake systems?","options":["\'S\' cam brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes","ABS brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes","ABS brakes, \'S\' cam brakes, and wedge brakes","\'S\' cam brakes, ABS brakes, and disc brakes"],"correctAnswer":"\'S\' cam brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes"},{"Question":"A sudden increase in the amount of moisture or oil drained from any air-tank:","options":["Means the system is working correctly","Indicates the governor is faulty","Must be reported and repaired","Indicates an engine oil leak"],"correctAnswer":"Must be reported and repaired"},{"Question":"When checking the air pressure buildup rate (compressor operation), what should the engine be idling between?","options":["200 - 500 rpm","500 - 800 rpm","600 - 900 rpm","900 - 1200 rpm"],"correctAnswer":"600 - 900 rpm"},{"Question":"What do anti-lock braking systems (ABS) do?","options":["Help maintain steering control during emergency braking","Help prevent wheel lock","Do not shorten the stopping distance","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"When conducting an inspection of the air brake system, be sure to:","options":["Park the vehicle on level ground","Park the vehicle away from traffic","Turn the engine off","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"The brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum is an example of:","options":["A foundation brake component defect","An issue with the brake chamber","An incorrectly measured pushrod","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"A foundation brake component defect"},{"Question":"Actual cut-in pressure of the governor should never be less than:","options":["55 psi","80 psi","100 psi","120 psi"],"correctAnswer":"100 psi"},{"Question":"Inspecting a vehicle\u2019s air brake chambers includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Audible air leaks","Cracks and non-manufactured holes","Brakes with different air brake chamber sizes on each end of a steering axle","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What does ABS stand for?","options":["Automatic Brake Stop","Automatic Braking System","Anti-lock Brake System","Accelerated Braking System"],"correctAnswer":"Anti-lock Brake System"},{"Question":"Older air systems may operate with lower pressure settings.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"In what order should air tanks be drained?","options":["Wet, primary, secondary","Primary, secondary, wet","Primary, wet, secondary","All at the same time"],"correctAnswer":"Wet, primary, secondary"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel is within the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This:","options":["Is a minor defect","Is a major defect","Passes the inspection","Is a broken or defective part"],"correctAnswer":"Passes the inspection"},{"Question":"When should the supply tank be drained?","options":["First","Last","In whatever order is most convenient for the driver","The supply tank should never be drained"],"correctAnswer":"First"},{"Question":"What controls an air brake system\u2019s pressure range (cut-in and cut-out settings)?","options":["The governor","The compressor","The engine","The turbo-charger"],"correctAnswer":"The governor"},{"Question":"What safety equipment is recommended while conducting an air brake inspection?","options":["Fire extinguisher, safety glasses, and  protective footwear","Safety glasses, protective headgear, and protective footwear","Protective headgear, ear plugs, and safety glasses","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Safety glasses, protective headgear, and protective footwear"},{"Question":"When the brakes are applied, a brake malfunction is indicated by the brake lining not contacting the drum.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When testing the air-loss rate of the brake system, the brake application must be held for:","options":["30 seconds","One minute","Two minutes","Three minutes"],"correctAnswer":"One minute"},{"Question":"What can cause damage or deterioration to brake hoses and tubes?","options":["Wear and cuts","Wear, cuts, and heat damage","Wear, cuts, abrasions, and heat damage","Abrasions and heat damage"],"correctAnswer":"Wear, cuts, abrasions, and heat damage"},{"Question":"When testing the compressor, if there is a trailer attached, the trailer supply valve must be closed.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"A sudden increase in the amount of moisture or oil drained from any air-tank:","options":["Means the system is working correctly","Indicates the governor is faulty","Must be reported and repaired","Indicates an engine oil leak"],"correctAnswer":"Must be reported and repaired"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not exceed:","options":["90 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"145 psi"},{"Question":"Inspecting a vehicle\u2019s air brake chambers includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Audible air leaks","Cracks and non-manufactured holes","Brakes with different air brake chamber sizes on each end of a steering axle","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"When checking the buildup rate (compressor operation) the engine should be building air pressure from _____ psi to ____ psi within two minutes:","options":["45 - 65","65 - 85","85 - 100","100 - 125"],"correctAnswer":"85 - 100"},{"Question":"What should the air pressure be when performing a brake adjustment inspection at each wheel?","options":["Between 80 - 90 psi","Between 90 - 100 psi","Between 100 - 110 psi","At maximum pressure"],"correctAnswer":"Between 90 - 100 psi"},{"Question":"As brakes heat up, you may experience a reduction in their effectiveness. This is known as:","options":["ABS brakes","Anti-lock braking","Brake fade","Combination braking"],"correctAnswer":"Brake fade"},{"Question":"In what order should air tanks be drained?","options":["Wet, primary, secondary","Primary, secondary, wet","Primary, wet, secondary","All at the same time"],"correctAnswer":"Wet, primary, secondary"},{"Question":"If air loss exceeds the maximum allowable limit specified for your vehicle, it would be considered a major defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When grease or oil is present on the brake lining:","options":["The brake lining is properly lubricated","Abnormal brake behaviour will result","The brake lining has been over-lubricated","The driver can continue to drive the vehicle as it will not cause any issues with brake function"],"correctAnswer":"Abnormal brake behaviour will result"},{"Question":"Testing the performance of your brakes requires performing separate tests of each braking system.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"The vehicle must be secured by the spring brakes or by wheel chocks before leaving the driver\u2019s seat or going under the vehicle.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What is a reliable method for inspecting your brake adjustment?","options":["Measuring the applied pushrod stroke","Checking the slack adjustment","Checking the condition of the brake drum","Measuring the brake chamber size"],"correctAnswer":"Measuring the applied pushrod stroke"},{"Question":"When testing the compressor, if there is a trailer attached, the trailer supply valve must be closed.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"A brake chamber that includes both service brake and spring brake sections is called a:","options":["Brake chamber","Spring brake chamber","DD3 brake chamber","Service brake chamber"],"correctAnswer":"Spring brake chamber"},{"Question":"When inspecting foundation brake components, the driver is expected to be able to identify brake components that are damaged, missing or malfunctioning.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Inspecting the air compressor includes checking for which defects?","options":["Loose air compressor drive belt pulley","Loose, cut or frayed air compressor drive belt","Insecure air compressor mounting, bracket or fasteners","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"How often is it recommended that the air tanks be drained?","options":["At the beginning of every trip","At the end of every trip","Every day","Once a week"],"correctAnswer":"Every day"},{"Question":"The vehicle must be secured by the spring brakes or by wheel chocks before leaving the driver\u2019s seat or going under the vehicle.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What safety equipment is recommended while conducting an air brake inspection?","options":["Fire extinguisher, safety glasses, and  protective footwear","Safety glasses, protective headgear, and protective footwear","Protective headgear, ear plugs, and safety glasses","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Safety glasses, protective headgear, and protective footwear"},{"Question":"In order to make a service brake application?","options":["Pull the yellow button","Pull the red button","Push the brake pedal","Push the red and yellow buttons"],"correctAnswer":"Push the brake pedal"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not exceed:","options":["90 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"145 psi"},{"Question":"Wheels, dust shields, and other parts of the vehicle have no impact on your view of the brake drums and rotors.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"The safety valve will open to allow excess air pressure to escape at a level no higher than?","options":["140 psi","145 psi","150 psi","155 psi"],"correctAnswer":"150 psi"},{"Question":"As brakes heat up, you may experience a reduction in their effectiveness. This is known as:","options":["ABS brakes","Anti-lock braking","Brake fade","Combination braking"],"correctAnswer":"Brake fade"},{"Question":"The engine must be running when testing the air-loss rate.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Inspecting the brake components includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum","Damaged, missing or malfunctioning foundation brake components","Cracked, loose, missing or contaminated brake lining, improper drum contact or lining thickness that is less than required","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What should you do before you exit the vehicle or get underneath it?","options":["Start the vehicle","Secure the vehicle","Grab your safety equipment","Turn off the vehicle"],"correctAnswer":"Secure the vehicle"},{"Question":"Why should the gladhands be stored properly when not in use?","options":["To keep the seals from cracking","To make them easier to find next time they\u2019re needed","To keep them clean and in good condition","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To keep them clean and in good condition"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle\u2019s air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel exceeds the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This is:","options":["A minor defect","A major defect","Within the acceptable adjustment limit","Something to keep track of"],"correctAnswer":"A major defect"},{"Question":"When should the supply tank be drained?","options":["First","Last","In whatever order is most convenient for the driver","The supply tank should never be drained"],"correctAnswer":"First"},{"Question":"What is the size of an air brake chamber based on?","options":["The type of chamber","The area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches","The pushrod travel distance","The make and model of the vehicle"],"correctAnswer":"The area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches"},{"Question":"What do anti-lock braking systems (ABS) do?","options":["Help maintain steering control during emergency braking","Help prevent wheel lock","Do not shorten the stopping distance","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"The safety valve will open to allow excess air pressure to escape at a level no higher than?","options":["140 psi","145 psi","150 psi","155 psi"],"correctAnswer":"150 psi"},{"Question":"Who is responsible for ensuring air brakes are correctly adjusted?","options":["The employer","The manufacturer","The last person driving the vehicle","The current driver"],"correctAnswer":"The current driver"},{"Question":"If you double your vehicle weight and double your speed, what does your stopping distance increase by?","options":["Four times","Six times","Eight times","Ten times"],"correctAnswer":"Eight times"},{"Question":"When testing brake performance (tug tests), it would be considered a major defect if:","options":["The spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle in place","The service brakes fail to stop the vehicle","Only if the tractor spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle","Both A and B"],"correctAnswer":"Both A and B"},{"Question":"When testing the tractor protection system, the trailer supply valve must close before the pressure drops below:","options":["20 psi","55 psi","60 psi","100 psi"],"correctAnswer":"20 psi"},{"Question":"When testing the low air-pressure warning device, the engine can be stopped or running but the ignition must be on.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What should you do before you exit the vehicle or get underneath it?","options":["Start the vehicle","Secure the vehicle","Grab your safety equipment","Turn off the vehicle"],"correctAnswer":"Secure the vehicle"},{"Question":"What controls an air brake system\u2019s pressure range (cut-in and cut-out settings)?","options":["The governor","The compressor","The engine","The turbo-charger"],"correctAnswer":"The governor"},{"Question":"Automatic slack adjusters, if working properly, require regular re-adjustment.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"If the low air-pressure warning device activates below 55 psi, this would be considered a minor defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"How would you know if the anti-lock braking system had a malfunction?","options":["The brakes won\'t function at all","The brakes will function intermittently","Only the trailer hand valve functions","The ABS malfunction warning light illuminates"],"correctAnswer":"The ABS malfunction warning light illuminates"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the tractor protection valve?","options":["Prevents total air loss from the trailer if the trailer breaks away","Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away","Holds the supply line and emergency line in place not allowing them to break away","Prevents over pressure in the system allowing excess air to escape"],"correctAnswer":"Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away"},{"Question":"Air brake chambers from different manufacturers may look different even if they are the same size.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"How often is it recommended that the air tanks be drained?","options":["At the beginning of every trip","At the end of every trip","Every day","Once a week"],"correctAnswer":"Every day"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle\u2019s air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel exceeds the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This is:","options":["A minor defect","A major defect","Within the acceptable adjustment limit","Something to keep track of"],"correctAnswer":"A major defect"},{"Question":"Testing the performance of your brakes requires performing separate tests of each braking system.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What happens if a single brake malfunctions?","options":["It puts more pressure on the other brakes","It causes the other brakes to quickly overheat","It could cause the other brakes to fail","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"The Highway Traffic Act and Regulations prohibit the operation of a vehicle with a brake that is out of adjustment.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What can indicate that an air tank or mounting bracket is not secure?","options":["Unusual movement","An air leak","A fluid leak","A deflated airbag"],"correctAnswer":"Unusual movement"},{"Question":"When conducting an inspection of the air brake system, be sure to:","options":["Park the vehicle on level ground","Park the vehicle away from traffic","Turn the engine off","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Inspecting the vehicle\u2019s air lines includes checking for the following defects:","options":["Audible air leak","Damage or worn air lines","Improper fittings used to connect or repair an air line","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Older air systems may operate with lower pressure settings.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"If air pressure drops below the normal cut-in setting what should the driver do?","options":["Continue driving until the spring brakes apply","Make several full brake applications","Nothing","Bring the vehicle to a safe stop as soon as possible"],"correctAnswer":"Bring the vehicle to a safe stop as soon as possible"},{"Question":"If you double your vehicle weight and double your speed, what does your stopping distance increase by?","options":["Four times","Six times","Eight times","Ten times"],"correctAnswer":"Eight times"},{"Question":"What can indicate that an air tank or mounting bracket is not secure?","options":["Unusual movement","An air leak","A fluid leak","A deflated airbag"],"correctAnswer":"Unusual movement"},{"Question":"Actual cut-in pressure of the governor should never be less than:","options":["55 psi","80 psi","100 psi","120 psi"],"correctAnswer":"100 psi"},{"Question":"The brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum is an example of:","options":["A foundation brake component defect","An issue with the brake chamber","An incorrectly measured pushrod","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"A foundation brake component defect"},{"Question":"A sudden increase in the amount of moisture or oil drained from any air-tank:","options":["Means the system is working correctly","Indicates the governor is faulty","Must be reported and repaired","Indicates an engine oil leak"],"correctAnswer":"Must be reported and repaired"},{"Question":"When the brakes are applied, a brake malfunction is indicated by the brake lining not contacting the drum.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What is the size of an air brake chamber based on?","options":["The type of chamber","The area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches","The pushrod travel distance","The make and model of the vehicle"],"correctAnswer":"The area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches"},{"Question":"When grease or oil is present on the brake lining:","options":["The brake lining is properly lubricated","Abnormal brake behaviour will result","The brake lining has been over-lubricated","The driver can continue to drive the vehicle as it will not cause any issues with brake function"],"correctAnswer":"Abnormal brake behaviour will result"},{"Question":"Actual cut-in pressure for the governor should never be less than 90 PSI?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When conducting an inspection of the air brake system, be sure to:","options":["Park the vehicle on level ground","Park the vehicle away from traffic","Turn the engine off","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"A brake chamber that includes both service brake and spring brake sections is called a:","options":["Brake chamber","Spring brake chamber","DD3 brake chamber","Service brake chamber"],"correctAnswer":"Spring brake chamber"},{"Question":"What does the air compressor do?","options":["The air compressor draws power from the battery to power the vehicle","The air compressor builds air for the trailer only","The air compressor draws air in and forces it into a smaller space increasing air pressure","The air compressor removes moisture from the air brake system"],"correctAnswer":"The air compressor draws air in and forces it into a smaller space increasing air pressure"},{"Question":"Spring brakes use air to apply the brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"As brakes heat up, you may experience a reduction in their effectiveness. This is known as:","options":["ABS brakes","Anti-lock braking","Brake fade","Combination braking"],"correctAnswer":"Brake fade"},{"Question":"Who is responsible for ensuring air brakes are correctly adjusted?","options":["The employer","The manufacturer","The last person driving the vehicle","The current driver"],"correctAnswer":"The current driver"},{"Question":"What do anti-lock braking systems (ABS) do?","options":["Help maintain steering control during emergency braking","Help prevent wheel lock","Do not shorten the stopping distance","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Inspecting a vehicle\u2019s air lines includes checking for the following defects:","options":["Audible air leak","Damaged or worn air lines","Improper fittings used to connect or repair air lines","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What is a reliable method for inspecting your brake adjustment?","options":["Measuring the applied pushrod stroke","Checking the slack adjustment","Checking the condition of the brake drum","Measuring the brake chamber size"],"correctAnswer":"Measuring the applied pushrod stroke"},{"Question":"If air exhausts from the service line, it means that the trailer supply valve is defective.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When checking the buildup rate (compressor operation) the engine should be building air pressure from _____ psi to ____ psi within two minutes:","options":["45 - 65","65 - 85","85 - 100","100 - 125"],"correctAnswer":"85 - 100"},{"Question":"The vehicle must be secured by the spring brakes or by wheel chocks before leaving the driver\u2019s seat or going under the vehicle.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not be lower than:","options":["60 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"120 psi"},{"Question":"When testing brake performance (tug tests), it would be considered a major defect if:","options":["The spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle in place","The service brakes fail to stop the vehicle","Only if the tractor spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle","Both A and B"],"correctAnswer":"Both A and B"},{"Question":"When testing the compressor, if there is a trailer attached, the trailer supply valve must be closed.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When the pushrod stroke exceeds the adjustment limit of the brake chamber, the brake:","options":["Is out of adjustment","Is in adjustment","Needs to be replaced","Has a minor defect"],"correctAnswer":"Is out of adjustment"},{"Question":"When the brakes are applied, a brake malfunction is indicated by the brake lining not contacting the drum.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Why would a brake chamber need to be \'caged\'?","options":["To move the vehicle in an emergency","To allow for proper braking","To measure your pushrod travel","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To move the vehicle in an emergency"},{"Question":"Testing the performance of your brakes requires performing separate tests of each braking system.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"The first air tank that air enters is called the supply (wet tank).","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Vehicles with air brakes must comply with The Highway Traffic Act and Regulations. If a vehicle does not comply, both the driver and the operator may be charged.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Air brake chambers from different manufacturers may look different even if they are the same size.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"A sudden increase in the amount of moisture or oil drained from any air-tank:","options":["Means the system is working correctly","Indicates the governor is faulty","Must be reported and repaired","Indicates an engine oil leak"],"correctAnswer":"Must be reported and repaired"},{"Question":"What safety equipment is recommended while conducting an air brake inspection?","options":["Fire extinguisher, safety glasses, and  protective footwear","Safety glasses, protective headgear, and protective footwear","Protective headgear, ear plugs, and safety glasses","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Safety glasses, protective headgear, and protective footwear"},{"Question":"When conducting an inspection of the air brake system, be sure to:","options":["Park the vehicle on level ground","Park the vehicle away from traffic","Turn the engine off","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"When testing the low air-pressure warning device, the engine can be stopped or running but the ignition must be on.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel is within the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This:","options":["Is a minor defect","Is a major defect","Passes the inspection","Is a broken or defective part"],"correctAnswer":"Passes the inspection"},{"Question":"At what pressure do the spring brakes normally start to apply because there is no longer enough pressure to keep them released?","options":["20 psi","40 psi","60 psi","85 psi"],"correctAnswer":"60 psi"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not be lower than:","options":["60 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"120 psi"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the governor?","options":["The governor causes the compressor to start and stop pumping air (cut-in and cut-out)","The governor controls the amount of moisture the air dryer removes from the system","Once air flows through the supply tank, the governor prevents it from returning","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"The governor causes the compressor to start and stop pumping air (cut-in and cut-out)"},{"Question":"A spring brake control valve is usually yellow?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What can cause damage or deterioration to brake hoses and tubes?","options":["Wear and cuts","Wear, cuts, and heat damage","Wear, cuts, abrasions, and heat damage","Abrasions and heat damage"],"correctAnswer":"Wear, cuts, abrasions, and heat damage"},{"Question":"Failure of the spring brakes to hold the vehicle stationary indicates defective service brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"In Manitoba, who can perform brake adjustments on manual slack adjusters so the pushrod is less than the adjusted limit?","options":["A licensed driver with an A endorsement or a certified technician","A licensed driver with an S endorsement","The owner for the vehicle","A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"],"correctAnswer":"A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"},{"Question":"The first air tank that air enters is called the supply (wet tank).","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What safety equipment is recommended while conducting an air brake inspection?","options":["Fire extinguisher, safety glasses, and  protective footwear","Safety glasses, protective headgear, and protective footwear","Protective headgear, ear plugs, and safety glasses","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Safety glasses, protective headgear, and protective footwear"},{"Question":"When checking the buildup rate (compressor operation) the engine should be building air pressure from _____ psi to ____ psi within two minutes:","options":["45 - 65","65 - 85","85 - 100","100 - 125"],"correctAnswer":"85 - 100"},{"Question":"There is often a noticeable change in the behaviour of brakes with drums or rotors that are defective, cracked or broken.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Brake lining is defective when it is:","options":["Cracked","Missing","Loose","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"If you double your vehicle weight and double your speed, what does your stopping distance increase by?","options":["Four times","Six times","Eight times","Ten times"],"correctAnswer":"Eight times"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the safety valve?","options":["Starts building air pressure at 100 psi","Stops building air pressure at 140 psi","Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting","Ensures the trucks safety features are working correctly"],"correctAnswer":"Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting"},{"Question":"What can indicate that an air tank or mounting bracket is not secure?","options":["Unusual movement","An air leak","A fluid leak","A deflated airbag"],"correctAnswer":"Unusual movement"},{"Question":"Why should the gladhands be stored properly when not in use?","options":["To keep the seals from cracking","To make them easier to find next time they\u2019re needed","To keep them clean and in good condition","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To keep them clean and in good condition"},{"Question":"An inspection of a vehicle\u2019s brake drums and rotors includes checking for the following defect:","options":["Cracked or broken brake drums","Cracked or broken rotors","Both A and B","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Both A and B"},{"Question":"The brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum is an example of:","options":["A foundation brake component defect","An issue with the brake chamber","An incorrectly measured pushrod","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"A foundation brake component defect"},{"Question":"Operating a vehicle with defects or failing to conduct the required inspections can result in:","options":["Charges against the driver and/or operator","Detainment or impoundment of the vehicle","Fines","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What can cause damage to the foundation brake components?","options":["Debris","Component failure","Deterioration","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"If the compressor takes longer than two minutes to build air from 85 psi to 100 psi, it would be considered a major defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What can indicate that an air tank or mounting bracket is not secure?","options":["Unusual movement","An air leak","A fluid leak","A deflated airbag"],"correctAnswer":"Unusual movement"},{"Question":"Air brake chambers from different manufacturers may look different even if they are the same size.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When inspecting foundation brake components, the driver is expected to be able to identify brake components that are damaged, missing or malfunctioning.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed when testing the air-loss rate of the brake system on a tractor and trailer?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","6 psi","10 psi"],"correctAnswer":"4 psi"},{"Question":"Inspecting a vehicle\u2019s air brake chambers includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Audible air leaks","Cracks and non-manufactured holes","Brakes with different air brake chamber sizes on each end of a steering axle","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Older air systems may operate with lower pressure settings.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Operating a vehicle with defects or failing to conduct the required inspections can result in:","options":["Charges against the driver and/or operator","Detainment or impoundment of the vehicle","Fines","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not be lower than:","options":["60 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"120 psi"},{"Question":"Damaged or worn air lines are not a concern until they have an obvious leak.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"How often is it recommended that the air tanks be drained?","options":["At the beginning of every trip","At the end of every trip","Every day","Once a week"],"correctAnswer":"Every day"},{"Question":"If the governor fails to signal the compressor to cut-out what allows the excess air pressure to escape?","options":["The air dryer","A one way check valve","The low pressure warning system","A safety valve"],"correctAnswer":"A safety valve"},{"Question":"If air exhausts from the service line, it means that the trailer supply valve is defective.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Your spring brakes should be used when parking or in an emergency when your service brakes fail?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What does the air compressor do?","options":["The air compressor draws power from the battery to power the vehicle","The air compressor builds air for the trailer only","The air compressor draws air in and forces it into a smaller space increasing air pressure","The air compressor removes moisture from the air brake system"],"correctAnswer":"The air compressor draws air in and forces it into a smaller space increasing air pressure"},{"Question":"When should the supply tank be drained?","options":["First","Last","In whatever order is most convenient for the driver","The supply tank should never be drained"],"correctAnswer":"First"},{"Question":"Inspecting the brake components includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum","Damaged, missing or malfunctioning foundation brake components","Cracked, loose, missing or contaminated brake lining, improper drum contact or lining thickness that is less than required","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Actual cut-in pressure of the governor should never be less than:","options":["55 psi","80 psi","100 psi","120 psi"],"correctAnswer":"100 psi"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle\u2019s air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel exceeds the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This is:","options":["A minor defect","A major defect","Within the acceptable adjustment limit","Something to keep track of"],"correctAnswer":"A major defect"},{"Question":"There is often a noticeable change in the behaviour of brakes with drums or rotors that are defective, cracked or broken.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"The Highway Traffic Act and Regulations prohibit the operation of a vehicle with a brake that is out of adjustment.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When testing the compressor, if there is a trailer attached, the trailer supply valve must be closed.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"How often is it recommended that the air tanks be drained?","options":["At the beginning of every trip","At the end of every trip","Every day","Once a week"],"correctAnswer":"Every day"},{"Question":"Damaged or worn air lines are not a concern until they have an obvious leak.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What happens if a single brake malfunctions?","options":["It puts more pressure on the other brakes","It causes the other brakes to quickly overheat","It could cause the other brakes to fail","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Inspecting the brake components includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum","Damaged, missing or malfunctioning foundation brake components","Cracked, loose, missing or contaminated brake lining, improper drum contact or lining thickness that is less than required","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Why should the gladhands be stored properly when not in use?","options":["To keep the seals from cracking","To make them easier to find next time they\u2019re needed","To keep them clean and in good condition","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To keep them clean and in good condition"},{"Question":"Failure of the spring brakes to hold the vehicle stationary indicates defective service brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Why would a brake chamber need to be \'caged\'?","options":["To move the vehicle in an emergency","To allow for proper braking","To measure your pushrod travel","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To move the vehicle in an emergency"},{"Question":"Wheels, dust shields, and other parts of the vehicle have no impact on your view of the brake drums and rotors.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When checking the air pressure buildup rate (compressor operation), what should the engine be idling between?","options":["200 - 500 rpm","500 - 800 rpm","600 - 900 rpm","900 - 1200 rpm"],"correctAnswer":"600 - 900 rpm"},{"Question":"What safety equipment is recommended while conducting an air brake inspection?","options":["Fire extinguisher, safety glasses, and  protective footwear","Safety glasses, protective headgear, and protective footwear","Protective headgear, ear plugs, and safety glasses","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Safety glasses, protective headgear, and protective footwear"},{"Question":"How would you know if the anti-lock braking system had a malfunction?","options":["The brakes won\'t function at all","The brakes will function intermittently","Only the trailer hand valve functions","The ABS malfunction warning light illuminates"],"correctAnswer":"The ABS malfunction warning light illuminates"},{"Question":"Inspecting a vehicle\u2019s air lines includes checking for the following defects:","options":["Audible air leak","Damaged or worn air lines","Improper fittings used to connect or repair air lines","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"When damage extends into the reinforcing or inner layer, the air line is defective.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"If air loss exceeds the maximum allowable limit specified for your vehicle, it would be considered a major defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When inspecting foundation brake components, the driver is expected to be able to identify brake components that are damaged, missing or malfunctioning.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"On a straight truck, tractor, or bus air loss test, what is the acceptable amount of air loss allowed within one minute?","options":["2 psi","3 psi","4 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"3 psi"},{"Question":"When checking the buildup rate (compressor operation) the engine should be building air pressure from _____ psi to ____ psi within two minutes:","options":["45 - 65","65 - 85","85 - 100","100 - 125"],"correctAnswer":"85 - 100"},{"Question":"In what order should air tanks be drained?","options":["Wet, primary, secondary","Primary, secondary, wet","Primary, wet, secondary","All at the same time"],"correctAnswer":"Wet, primary, secondary"},{"Question":"What are the three different types of foundation brake systems?","options":["\'S\' cam brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes","ABS brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes","ABS brakes, \'S\' cam brakes, and wedge brakes","\'S\' cam brakes, ABS brakes, and disc brakes"],"correctAnswer":"\'S\' cam brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes"},{"Question":"Inspecting the air compressor includes checking for which defects?","options":["Loose air compressor drive belt pulley","Loose, cut or frayed air compressor drive belt","Insecure air compressor mounting, bracket or fasteners","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What does the air compressor do?","options":["The air compressor draws power from the battery to power the vehicle","The air compressor builds air for the trailer only","The air compressor draws air in and forces it into a smaller space increasing air pressure","The air compressor removes moisture from the air brake system"],"correctAnswer":"The air compressor draws air in and forces it into a smaller space increasing air pressure"},{"Question":"Testing the performance of your brakes requires performing separate tests of each braking system.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What is a reliable method for inspecting your brake adjustment?","options":["Measuring the applied pushrod stroke","Checking the slack adjustment","Checking the condition of the brake drum","Measuring the brake chamber size"],"correctAnswer":"Measuring the applied pushrod stroke"},{"Question":"Air brake chambers from different manufacturers may look different even if they are the same size.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"If the compressor takes longer than two minutes to build air from 85 psi to 100 psi, it would be considered a major defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed when testing the air-loss rate of the brake system on a tractor and trailer?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","6 psi","10 psi"],"correctAnswer":"4 psi"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel is within the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This:","options":["Is a minor defect","Is a major defect","Passes the inspection","Is a broken or defective part"],"correctAnswer":"Passes the inspection"},{"Question":"Operating a vehicle with defects or failing to conduct the required inspections can result in:","options":["Charges against the driver and/or operator","Detainment or impoundment of the vehicle","Fines","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"The size of an air brake chamber is based on the area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"If you double your vehicle weight and double your speed, what does your stopping distance increase by?","options":["Four times","Six times","Eight times","Ten times"],"correctAnswer":"Eight times"},{"Question":"When inspecting foundation brake components, the driver is expected to be able to identify brake components that are damaged, missing or malfunctioning.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"There is often a noticeable change in the behaviour of brakes with drums or rotors that are defective, cracked or broken.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When should the supply tank be drained?","options":["First","Last","In whatever order is most convenient for the driver","The supply tank should never be drained"],"correctAnswer":"First"},{"Question":"When the pushrod stroke exceeds the adjustment limit of the brake chamber, the brake:","options":["Is out of adjustment","Is in adjustment","Needs to be replaced","Has a minor defect"],"correctAnswer":"Is out of adjustment"},{"Question":"Inspecting a vehicle\u2019s air lines includes checking for the following defects:","options":["Audible air leak","Damaged or worn air lines","Improper fittings used to connect or repair air lines","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"How often is it recommended that the air tanks be drained?","options":["At the beginning of every trip","At the end of every trip","Every day","Once a week"],"correctAnswer":"Every day"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the safety valve?","options":["Starts building air pressure at 100 psi","Stops building air pressure at 140 psi","Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting","Ensures the trucks safety features are working correctly"],"correctAnswer":"Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting"},{"Question":"What is the size of an air brake chamber based on?","options":["The type of chamber","The area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches","The pushrod travel distance","The make and model of the vehicle"],"correctAnswer":"The area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches"},{"Question":"When checking the buildup rate (compressor operation) the engine should be building air pressure from _____ psi to ____ psi within two minutes:","options":["45 - 65","65 - 85","85 - 100","100 - 125"],"correctAnswer":"85 - 100"},{"Question":"The brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum is an example of:","options":["A foundation brake component defect","An issue with the brake chamber","An incorrectly measured pushrod","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"A foundation brake component defect"},{"Question":"A spring brake control valve is usually yellow?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Inspecting a vehicle\u2019s air lines includes checking for the following defects:","options":["Audible air leak","Damaged or worn air lines","Improper fittings used to connect or repair air lines","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What happens if a single brake malfunctions?","options":["It puts more pressure on the other brakes","It causes the other brakes to quickly overheat","It could cause the other brakes to fail","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"The size of an air brake chamber is based on the area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"There is often a noticeable change in the behaviour of brakes with drums or rotors that are defective, cracked or broken.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"A brake chamber that includes both service brake and spring brake sections is called a:","options":["Brake chamber","Spring brake chamber","DD3 brake chamber","Service brake chamber"],"correctAnswer":"Spring brake chamber"},{"Question":"When testing the tractor protection system, the trailer supply valve must close before the pressure drops below:","options":["20 psi","55 psi","60 psi","100 psi"],"correctAnswer":"20 psi"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the governor?","options":["The governor causes the compressor to start and stop pumping air (cut-in and cut-out)","The governor controls the amount of moisture the air dryer removes from the system","Once air flows through the supply tank, the governor prevents it from returning","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"The governor causes the compressor to start and stop pumping air (cut-in and cut-out)"},{"Question":"Air compressors can be inspected with the engine running or stopped.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"On a straight truck, tractor, or bus air loss test, what is the acceptable amount of air loss allowed within one minute?","options":["2 psi","3 psi","4 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"3 psi"},{"Question":"Testing the performance of your brakes requires performing separate tests of each braking system.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"If air exhausts from the service line, it means that the trailer supply valve is defective.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Operating a vehicle with defects or failing to conduct the required inspections can result in:","options":["Charges against the driver and/or operator","Detainment or impoundment of the vehicle","Fines","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"The vehicle must be secured by the spring brakes or by wheel chocks before leaving the driver\u2019s seat or going under the vehicle.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"If any single brake malfunctions, what affect will it have on the other brakes?","options":["None","The malfunctioning brake will overheat causing damage","They will overheat quickly and possibly fail","The braking power will be slightly reduced"],"correctAnswer":"They will overheat quickly and possibly fail"},{"Question":"What do anti-lock braking systems (ABS) do?","options":["Help maintain steering control during emergency braking","Help prevent wheel lock","Do not shorten the stopping distance","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"When inspecting foundation brake components, the driver is expected to be able to identify brake components that are damaged, missing or malfunctioning.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"If air loss exceeds the maximum allowable limit specified for your vehicle, it would be considered a major defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Vehicles with air brakes must comply with The Highway Traffic Act and Regulations. If a vehicle does not comply, both the driver and the operator may be charged.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel is within the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This:","options":["Is a minor defect","Is a major defect","Passes the inspection","Is a broken or defective part"],"correctAnswer":"Passes the inspection"},{"Question":"What is a reliable method for inspecting your brake adjustment?","options":["Measuring the applied pushrod stroke","Checking the slack adjustment","Checking the condition of the brake drum","Measuring the brake chamber size"],"correctAnswer":"Measuring the applied pushrod stroke"},{"Question":"When should the supply tank be drained?","options":["First","Last","In whatever order is most convenient for the driver","The supply tank should never be drained"],"correctAnswer":"First"},{"Question":"On a straight truck, tractor, or bus air loss test, what is the acceptable amount of air loss allowed within one minute?","options":["2 psi","3 psi","4 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"3 psi"},{"Question":"For the brakes to work, the brake-shoe lining must be greased and pressed against the brake drum when the brakes are applied.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Air compressors can be inspected with the engine running or stopped.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"In order to make a service brake application?","options":["Pull the yellow button","Pull the red button","Push the brake pedal","Push the red and yellow buttons"],"correctAnswer":"Push the brake pedal"},{"Question":"How often is it recommended that the air tanks be drained?","options":["At the beginning of every trip","At the end of every trip","Every day","Once a week"],"correctAnswer":"Every day"},{"Question":"What are the three different types of foundation brake systems?","options":["\'S\' cam brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes","ABS brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes","ABS brakes, \'S\' cam brakes, and wedge brakes","\'S\' cam brakes, ABS brakes, and disc brakes"],"correctAnswer":"\'S\' cam brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle\u2019s air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel exceeds the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This is:","options":["A minor defect","A major defect","Within the acceptable adjustment limit","Something to keep track of"],"correctAnswer":"A major defect"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not exceed:","options":["90 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"145 psi"},{"Question":"An inspection of a vehicle\u2019s brake drums and rotors includes checking for the following defect:","options":["Cracked or broken brake drums","Cracked or broken rotors","Both A and B","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Both A and B"},{"Question":"Testing the performance of your brakes requires performing separate tests of each braking system.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"There is often a noticeable change in the behaviour of brakes with drums or rotors that are defective, cracked or broken.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Inspecting the brake components includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum","Damaged, missing or malfunctioning foundation brake components","Cracked, loose, missing or contaminated brake lining, improper drum contact or lining thickness that is less than required","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Inspecting a vehicle\u2019s air brake chambers includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Audible air leaks","Cracks and non-manufactured holes","Brakes with different air brake chamber sizes on each end of a steering axle","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"The first air tank that air enters is called the supply (wet tank).","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"As brakes heat up, you may experience a reduction in their effectiveness. This is known as:","options":["ABS brakes","Anti-lock braking","Brake fade","Combination braking"],"correctAnswer":"Brake fade"},{"Question":"To ensure balanced braking, slack adjusters on each side of an axel should:","options":["Be the same effective lengths","Have no more than 1 inch difference","Be attached using different holes","Both B and C"],"correctAnswer":"Be the same effective lengths"},{"Question":"A brake chamber that includes both service brake and spring brake sections is called a:","options":["Brake chamber","Spring brake chamber","DD3 brake chamber","Service brake chamber"],"correctAnswer":"Spring brake chamber"},{"Question":"Why are automatic slack adjusters used?","options":["They make inspections and adjustments unnecessary","As a backup to a manual slack adjuster","To avoid the need to regularly perform manual re-adjustments","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To avoid the need to regularly perform manual re-adjustments"},{"Question":"If air exhausts from the service line, it means that the trailer supply valve is defective.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"The engine must be running when testing the air-loss rate.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Automatic slack adjusters, if working properly, require regular re-adjustment.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"The first air tank that air enters is called the supply (wet tank).","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed in one minute on a tractor with two or more trailers?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","5 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"6 psi"},{"Question":"What do anti-lock braking systems (ABS) do?","options":["Help maintain steering control during emergency braking","Help prevent wheel lock","Do not shorten the stopping distance","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What should the air pressure be when performing a brake adjustment inspection at each wheel?","options":["Between 80 - 90 psi","Between 90 - 100 psi","Between 100 - 110 psi","At maximum pressure"],"correctAnswer":"Between 90 - 100 psi"},{"Question":"In Manitoba, who can perform brake adjustments on manual slack adjusters so the pushrod is less than the adjusted limit?","options":["A licensed driver with an A endorsement or a certified technician","A licensed driver with an S endorsement","The owner for the vehicle","A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"],"correctAnswer":"A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"},{"Question":"An inspection of a vehicle\u2019s brake drums and rotors includes checking for the following defect:","options":["Cracked or broken brake drums","Cracked or broken rotors","Both A and B","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Both A and B"},{"Question":"What is a reliable method for inspecting your brake adjustment?","options":["Measuring the applied pushrod stroke","Checking the slack adjustment","Checking the condition of the brake drum","Measuring the brake chamber size"],"correctAnswer":"Measuring the applied pushrod stroke"},{"Question":"Wheels, dust shields, and other parts of the vehicle have no impact on your view of the brake drums and rotors.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not exceed:","options":["90 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"145 psi"},{"Question":"Inspecting the brake components includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum","Damaged, missing or malfunctioning foundation brake components","Cracked, loose, missing or contaminated brake lining, improper drum contact or lining thickness that is less than required","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Vehicles with air brakes must comply with The Highway Traffic Act and Regulations. If a vehicle does not comply, both the driver and the operator may be charged.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Actual cut-in pressure for the governor should never be less than 90 PSI?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When conducting an inspection of the air brake system, be sure to:","options":["Park the vehicle on level ground","Park the vehicle away from traffic","Turn the engine off","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Why would a brake chamber need to be \'caged\'?","options":["To move the vehicle in an emergency","To allow for proper braking","To measure your pushrod travel","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To move the vehicle in an emergency"},{"Question":"The brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum is an example of:","options":["A foundation brake component defect","An issue with the brake chamber","An incorrectly measured pushrod","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"A foundation brake component defect"},{"Question":"Air brake chambers from different manufacturers may look different even if they are the same size.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"The safety valve will open to allow excess air pressure to escape at a level no higher than?","options":["140 psi","145 psi","150 psi","155 psi"],"correctAnswer":"150 psi"},{"Question":"Inspecting the vehicle\u2019s air lines includes checking for the following defects:","options":["Audible air leak","Damage or worn air lines","Improper fittings used to connect or repair an air line","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"When checking the buildup rate (compressor operation) the engine should be building air pressure from _____ psi to ____ psi within two minutes:","options":["45 - 65","65 - 85","85 - 100","100 - 125"],"correctAnswer":"85 - 100"},{"Question":"What should the air pressure be when performing a brake adjustment inspection at each wheel?","options":["Between 80 - 90 psi","Between 90 - 100 psi","Between 100 - 110 psi","At maximum pressure"],"correctAnswer":"Between 90 - 100 psi"},{"Question":"At what level must the low pressure warning device activate?","options":["At or above 60 psi","Between 40 - 50 psi","At or above 85 psi","At or above 55 psi"],"correctAnswer":"At or above 55 psi"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle\u2019s air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel exceeds the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This is:","options":["A minor defect","A major defect","Within the acceptable adjustment limit","Something to keep track of"],"correctAnswer":"A major defect"},{"Question":"What should you do before you exit the vehicle or get underneath it?","options":["Start the vehicle","Secure the vehicle","Grab your safety equipment","Turn off the vehicle"],"correctAnswer":"Secure the vehicle"},{"Question":"When the brakes are applied, a brake malfunction is indicated by the brake lining not contacting the drum.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What is a reliable method for inspecting your brake adjustment?","options":["Measuring the applied pushrod stroke","Checking the slack adjustment","Checking the condition of the brake drum","Measuring the brake chamber size"],"correctAnswer":"Measuring the applied pushrod stroke"},{"Question":"Air compressors can be inspected with the engine running or stopped.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What can indicate that an air tank or mounting bracket is not secure?","options":["Unusual movement","An air leak","A fluid leak","A deflated airbag"],"correctAnswer":"Unusual movement"},{"Question":"Damaged or worn air lines are not a concern until they have an obvious leak.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"In order to make a service brake application?","options":["Pull the yellow button","Pull the red button","Push the brake pedal","Push the red and yellow buttons"],"correctAnswer":"Push the brake pedal"},{"Question":"Air brake chambers from different manufacturers may look different even if they are the same size.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not be lower than:","options":["60 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"120 psi"},{"Question":"What controls an air brake system\u2019s pressure range (cut-in and cut-out settings)?","options":["The governor","The compressor","The engine","The turbo-charger"],"correctAnswer":"The governor"},{"Question":"A sudden increase in the amount of moisture or oil drained from any air-tank:","options":["Means the system is working correctly","Indicates the governor is faulty","Must be reported and repaired","Indicates an engine oil leak"],"correctAnswer":"Must be reported and repaired"},{"Question":"Why would a brake chamber need to be \'caged\'?","options":["To move the vehicle in an emergency","To allow for proper braking","To measure your pushrod travel","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To move the vehicle in an emergency"},{"Question":"What can cause damage or deterioration to brake hoses and tubes?","options":["Wear and cuts","Wear, cuts, and heat damage","Wear, cuts, abrasions, and heat damage","Abrasions and heat damage"],"correctAnswer":"Wear, cuts, abrasions, and heat damage"},{"Question":"When testing the compressor, if there is a trailer attached, the trailer supply valve must be closed.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"The brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum is an example of:","options":["A foundation brake component defect","An issue with the brake chamber","An incorrectly measured pushrod","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"A foundation brake component defect"},{"Question":"Where are air brake chambers located?","options":["At each wheel","At the drive wheels only","At the trailer wheels only","At both the drive and trailer wheels"],"correctAnswer":"At each wheel"},{"Question":"If the low air-pressure warning device activates below 55 psi, this would be considered a minor defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Your spring brakes should be used when parking or in an emergency when your service brakes fail?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Inspecting the vehicle\u2019s air lines includes checking for the following defects:","options":["Audible air leak","Damage or worn air lines","Improper fittings used to connect or repair an air line","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"When testing the low air-pressure warning device, the engine can be stopped or running but the ignition must be on.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Who is responsible for ensuring air brakes are correctly adjusted?","options":["The employer","The manufacturer","The last person driving the vehicle","The current driver"],"correctAnswer":"The current driver"},{"Question":"For the brakes to work, the brake-shoe lining must be greased and pressed against the brake drum when the brakes are applied.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"To ensure balanced braking, slack adjusters on each side of an axel should:","options":["Be the same effective lengths","Have no more than 1 inch difference","Be attached using different holes","Both B and C"],"correctAnswer":"Be the same effective lengths"},{"Question":"What are the three different types of foundation brake systems?","options":["\'S\' cam brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes","ABS brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes","ABS brakes, \'S\' cam brakes, and wedge brakes","\'S\' cam brakes, ABS brakes, and disc brakes"],"correctAnswer":"\'S\' cam brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes"},{"Question":"When damage extends into the reinforcing or inner layer, the air line is defective.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When inspecting foundation brake components, the driver is expected to be able to identify brake components that are damaged, missing or malfunctioning.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Actual cut-in pressure for the governor should never be less than 90 PSI?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle\u2019s air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel exceeds the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This is:","options":["A minor defect","A major defect","Within the acceptable adjustment limit","Something to keep track of"],"correctAnswer":"A major defect"},{"Question":"On a straight truck, tractor, or bus air loss test, what is the acceptable amount of air loss allowed within one minute?","options":["2 psi","3 psi","4 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"3 psi"},{"Question":"If air exhausts from the service line, it means that the trailer supply valve is defective.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Automatic slack adjusters, if working properly, require regular re-adjustment.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What do anti-lock braking systems (ABS) do?","options":["Help maintain steering control during emergency braking","Help prevent wheel lock","Do not shorten the stopping distance","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"If any single brake malfunctions, what affect will it have on the other brakes?","options":["None","The malfunctioning brake will overheat causing damage","They will overheat quickly and possibly fail","The braking power will be slightly reduced"],"correctAnswer":"They will overheat quickly and possibly fail"},{"Question":"What can cause damage to the foundation brake components?","options":["Debris","Component failure","Deterioration","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Inspecting a vehicle\u2019s air brake chambers includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Audible air leaks","Cracks and non-manufactured holes","Brakes with different air brake chamber sizes on each end of a steering axle","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What should the air pressure be when performing a brake adjustment inspection at each wheel?","options":["Between 80 - 90 psi","Between 90 - 100 psi","Between 100 - 110 psi","At maximum pressure"],"correctAnswer":"Between 90 - 100 psi"},{"Question":"When testing the low air-pressure warning device, the engine can be stopped or running but the ignition must be on.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Your spring brakes should be used when parking or in an emergency when your service brakes fail?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"If air pressure drops below the normal cut-in setting what should the driver do?","options":["Continue driving until the spring brakes apply","Make several full brake applications","Nothing","Bring the vehicle to a safe stop as soon as possible"],"correctAnswer":"Bring the vehicle to a safe stop as soon as possible"},{"Question":"When the brakes are applied, a brake malfunction is indicated by the brake lining not contacting the drum.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"How often is it recommended that the air tanks be drained?","options":["At the beginning of every trip","At the end of every trip","Every day","Once a week"],"correctAnswer":"Every day"},{"Question":"Why are automatic slack adjusters used?","options":["They make inspections and adjustments unnecessary","As a backup to a manual slack adjuster","To avoid the need to regularly perform manual re-adjustments","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To avoid the need to regularly perform manual re-adjustments"},{"Question":"The first air tank that air enters is called the supply (wet tank).","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What does the air compressor do?","options":["The air compressor draws power from the battery to power the vehicle","The air compressor builds air for the trailer only","The air compressor draws air in and forces it into a smaller space increasing air pressure","The air compressor removes moisture from the air brake system"],"correctAnswer":"The air compressor draws air in and forces it into a smaller space increasing air pressure"},{"Question":"What does ABS stand for?","options":["Automatic Brake Stop","Automatic Braking System","Anti-lock Brake System","Accelerated Braking System"],"correctAnswer":"Anti-lock Brake System"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the tractor protection valve?","options":["Prevents total air loss from the trailer if the trailer breaks away","Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away","Holds the supply line and emergency line in place not allowing them to break away","Prevents over pressure in the system allowing excess air to escape"],"correctAnswer":"Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away"},{"Question":"When testing brake performance (tug tests), it would be considered a major defect if:","options":["The spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle in place","The service brakes fail to stop the vehicle","Only if the tractor spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle","Both A and B"],"correctAnswer":"Both A and B"},{"Question":"When inspecting foundation brake components, the driver is expected to be able to identify brake components that are damaged, missing or malfunctioning.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What happens if a single brake malfunctions?","options":["It puts more pressure on the other brakes","It causes the other brakes to quickly overheat","It could cause the other brakes to fail","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"A sudden increase in the amount of moisture or oil drained from any air-tank:","options":["Means the system is working correctly","Indicates the governor is faulty","Must be reported and repaired","Indicates an engine oil leak"],"correctAnswer":"Must be reported and repaired"},{"Question":"When conducting an inspection of the air brake system, be sure to:","options":["Park the vehicle on level ground","Park the vehicle away from traffic","Turn the engine off","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"To ensure balanced braking, slack adjusters on each side of an axel should:","options":["Be the same effective lengths","Have no more than 1 inch difference","Be attached using different holes","Both B and C"],"correctAnswer":"Be the same effective lengths"},{"Question":"In what order should air tanks be drained?","options":["Wet, primary, secondary","Primary, secondary, wet","Primary, wet, secondary","All at the same time"],"correctAnswer":"Wet, primary, secondary"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not be lower than:","options":["60 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"120 psi"},{"Question":"When conducting an inspection of the air brake system, be sure to:","options":["Park the vehicle on level ground","Park the vehicle away from traffic","Turn the engine off","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"When checking the buildup rate (compressor operation) the engine should be building air pressure from _____ psi to ____ psi within two minutes:","options":["45 - 65","65 - 85","85 - 100","100 - 125"],"correctAnswer":"85 - 100"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the tractor protection valve?","options":["Prevents total air loss from the trailer if the trailer breaks away","Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away","Holds the supply line and emergency line in place not allowing them to break away","Prevents over pressure in the system allowing excess air to escape"],"correctAnswer":"Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away"},{"Question":"In Manitoba, who can perform brake adjustments on manual slack adjusters so the pushrod is less than the adjusted limit?","options":["A licensed driver with an A endorsement or a certified technician","A licensed driver with an S endorsement","The owner for the vehicle","A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"],"correctAnswer":"A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"},{"Question":"The size of an air brake chamber is based on the area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel is within the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This:","options":["Is a minor defect","Is a major defect","Passes the inspection","Is a broken or defective part"],"correctAnswer":"Passes the inspection"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed when testing the air-loss rate of the brake system on a tractor and trailer?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","6 psi","10 psi"],"correctAnswer":"4 psi"},{"Question":"How would you know if the anti-lock braking system had a malfunction?","options":["The brakes won\'t function at all","The brakes will function intermittently","Only the trailer hand valve functions","The ABS malfunction warning light illuminates"],"correctAnswer":"The ABS malfunction warning light illuminates"},{"Question":"What should you do before you exit the vehicle or get underneath it?","options":["Start the vehicle","Secure the vehicle","Grab your safety equipment","Turn off the vehicle"],"correctAnswer":"Secure the vehicle"},{"Question":"If air loss exceeds the maximum allowable limit specified for your vehicle, it would be considered a major defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"A brake chamber that includes both service brake and spring brake sections is called a:","options":["Brake chamber","Spring brake chamber","DD3 brake chamber","Service brake chamber"],"correctAnswer":"Spring brake chamber"},{"Question":"When testing the low air-pressure warning device, the engine can be stopped or running but the ignition must be on.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"An inspection of a vehicle\u2019s brake drums and rotors includes checking for the following defect:","options":["Cracked or broken brake drums","Cracked or broken rotors","Both A and B","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Both A and B"},{"Question":"What should the air pressure be when performing a brake adjustment inspection at each wheel?","options":["Between 80 - 90 psi","Between 90 - 100 psi","Between 100 - 110 psi","At maximum pressure"],"correctAnswer":"Between 90 - 100 psi"},{"Question":"The brake on each end of an axel should have a different sized air brake chamber to ensure brake forces are balanced.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"If the governor fails to signal the compressor to cut-out what allows the excess air pressure to escape?","options":["The air dryer","A one way check valve","The low pressure warning system","A safety valve"],"correctAnswer":"A safety valve"},{"Question":"When testing brake performance (tug tests), it would be considered a major defect if:","options":["The spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle in place","The service brakes fail to stop the vehicle","Only if the tractor spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle","Both A and B"],"correctAnswer":"Both A and B"},{"Question":"What can indicate that an air tank or mounting bracket is not secure?","options":["Unusual movement","An air leak","A fluid leak","A deflated airbag"],"correctAnswer":"Unusual movement"},{"Question":"Wheels, dust shields, and other parts of the vehicle have no impact on your view of the brake drums and rotors.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"A sudden increase in the amount of moisture or oil drained from any air-tank:","options":["Means the system is working correctly","Indicates the governor is faulty","Must be reported and repaired","Indicates an engine oil leak"],"correctAnswer":"Must be reported and repaired"},{"Question":"How would you know if the anti-lock braking system had a malfunction?","options":["The brakes won\'t function at all","The brakes will function intermittently","Only the trailer hand valve functions","The ABS malfunction warning light illuminates"],"correctAnswer":"The ABS malfunction warning light illuminates"},{"Question":"The brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum is an example of:","options":["A foundation brake component defect","An issue with the brake chamber","An incorrectly measured pushrod","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"A foundation brake component defect"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not exceed:","options":["90 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"145 psi"},{"Question":"Inspecting the brake components includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum","Damaged, missing or malfunctioning foundation brake components","Cracked, loose, missing or contaminated brake lining, improper drum contact or lining thickness that is less than required","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"When testing the compressor, if there is a trailer attached, the trailer supply valve must be closed.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What can cause damage to the foundation brake components?","options":["Debris","Component failure","Deterioration","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"The vehicle must be secured by the spring brakes or by wheel chocks before leaving the driver\u2019s seat or going under the vehicle.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"On a straight truck, tractor, or bus air loss test, what is the acceptable amount of air loss allowed within one minute?","options":["2 psi","3 psi","4 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"3 psi"},{"Question":"The size of an air brake chamber is based on the area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Vehicles with air brakes must comply with The Highway Traffic Act and Regulations. If a vehicle does not comply, both the driver and the operator may be charged.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When conducting an inspection of the air brake system, be sure to:","options":["Park the vehicle on level ground","Park the vehicle away from traffic","Turn the engine off","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the governor?","options":["The governor causes the compressor to start and stop pumping air (cut-in and cut-out)","The governor controls the amount of moisture the air dryer removes from the system","Once air flows through the supply tank, the governor prevents it from returning","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"The governor causes the compressor to start and stop pumping air (cut-in and cut-out)"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel is within the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This:","options":["Is a minor defect","Is a major defect","Passes the inspection","Is a broken or defective part"],"correctAnswer":"Passes the inspection"},{"Question":"Who is responsible for ensuring air brakes are correctly adjusted?","options":["The employer","The manufacturer","The last person driving the vehicle","The current driver"],"correctAnswer":"The current driver"},{"Question":"When inspecting foundation brake components, the driver is expected to be able to identify brake components that are damaged, missing or malfunctioning.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Failure of the spring brakes to hold the vehicle stationary indicates defective service brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"The engine must be running when testing the air-loss rate.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Where are air brake chambers located?","options":["At each wheel","At the drive wheels only","At the trailer wheels only","At both the drive and trailer wheels"],"correctAnswer":"At each wheel"},{"Question":"What do anti-lock braking systems (ABS) do?","options":["Help maintain steering control during emergency braking","Help prevent wheel lock","Do not shorten the stopping distance","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the safety valve?","options":["Starts building air pressure at 100 psi","Stops building air pressure at 140 psi","Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting","Ensures the trucks safety features are working correctly"],"correctAnswer":"Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting"},{"Question":"Operating a vehicle with defects or failing to conduct the required inspections can result in:","options":["Charges against the driver and/or operator","Detainment or impoundment of the vehicle","Fines","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed when testing the air-loss rate of the brake system on a tractor and trailer?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","6 psi","10 psi"],"correctAnswer":"4 psi"},{"Question":"What is the size of an air brake chamber based on?","options":["The type of chamber","The area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches","The pushrod travel distance","The make and model of the vehicle"],"correctAnswer":"The area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches"},{"Question":"How often is it recommended that the air tanks be drained?","options":["At the beginning of every trip","At the end of every trip","Every day","Once a week"],"correctAnswer":"Every day"},{"Question":"The brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum is an example of:","options":["A foundation brake component defect","An issue with the brake chamber","An incorrectly measured pushrod","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"A foundation brake component defect"},{"Question":"There is often a noticeable change in the behaviour of brakes with drums or rotors that are defective, cracked or broken.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"If the governor fails to signal the compressor to cut-out what allows the excess air pressure to escape?","options":["The air dryer","A one way check valve","The low pressure warning system","A safety valve"],"correctAnswer":"A safety valve"},{"Question":"When grease or oil is present on the brake lining:","options":["The brake lining is properly lubricated","Abnormal brake behaviour will result","The brake lining has been over-lubricated","The driver can continue to drive the vehicle as it will not cause any issues with brake function"],"correctAnswer":"Abnormal brake behaviour will result"},{"Question":"When testing the compressor, if there is a trailer attached, the trailer supply valve must be closed.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"The size of an air brake chamber is based on the area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"The brake on each end of an axel should have a different sized air brake chamber to ensure brake forces are balanced.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Failure of the spring brakes to hold the vehicle stationary indicates defective service brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"If air loss exceeds the maximum allowable limit specified for your vehicle, it would be considered a major defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Inspecting the brake components includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum","Damaged, missing or malfunctioning foundation brake components","Cracked, loose, missing or contaminated brake lining, improper drum contact or lining thickness that is less than required","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel is within the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This:","options":["Is a minor defect","Is a major defect","Passes the inspection","Is a broken or defective part"],"correctAnswer":"Passes the inspection"},{"Question":"What does ABS stand for?","options":["Automatic Brake Stop","Automatic Braking System","Anti-lock Brake System","Accelerated Braking System"],"correctAnswer":"Anti-lock Brake System"},{"Question":"On a straight truck, tractor, or bus air loss test, what is the acceptable amount of air loss allowed within one minute?","options":["2 psi","3 psi","4 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"3 psi"},{"Question":"What can cause damage or deterioration to brake hoses and tubes?","options":["Wear and cuts","Wear, cuts, and heat damage","Wear, cuts, abrasions, and heat damage","Abrasions and heat damage"],"correctAnswer":"Wear, cuts, abrasions, and heat damage"},{"Question":"The engine must be running when testing the air-loss rate.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Older air systems may operate with lower pressure settings.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"If air pressure drops below the normal cut-in setting what should the driver do?","options":["Continue driving until the spring brakes apply","Make several full brake applications","Nothing","Bring the vehicle to a safe stop as soon as possible"],"correctAnswer":"Bring the vehicle to a safe stop as soon as possible"},{"Question":"What is a reliable method for inspecting your brake adjustment?","options":["Measuring the applied pushrod stroke","Checking the slack adjustment","Checking the condition of the brake drum","Measuring the brake chamber size"],"correctAnswer":"Measuring the applied pushrod stroke"},{"Question":"Inspecting the air compressor includes checking for which defects?","options":["Loose air compressor drive belt pulley","Loose, cut or frayed air compressor drive belt","Insecure air compressor mounting, bracket or fasteners","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Failure of the spring brakes to hold the vehicle stationary indicates defective service brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"On a straight truck, tractor, or bus air loss test, what is the acceptable amount of air loss allowed within one minute?","options":["2 psi","3 psi","4 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"3 psi"},{"Question":"What should you do before you exit the vehicle or get underneath it?","options":["Start the vehicle","Secure the vehicle","Grab your safety equipment","Turn off the vehicle"],"correctAnswer":"Secure the vehicle"},{"Question":"When inspecting foundation brake components, the driver is expected to be able to identify brake components that are damaged, missing or malfunctioning.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"As brakes heat up, you may experience a reduction in their effectiveness. This is known as:","options":["ABS brakes","Anti-lock braking","Brake fade","Combination braking"],"correctAnswer":"Brake fade"},{"Question":"Inspecting the vehicle\u2019s air lines includes checking for the following defects:","options":["Audible air leak","Damage or worn air lines","Improper fittings used to connect or repair an air line","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What does ABS stand for?","options":["Automatic Brake Stop","Automatic Braking System","Anti-lock Brake System","Accelerated Braking System"],"correctAnswer":"Anti-lock Brake System"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the governor?","options":["The governor causes the compressor to start and stop pumping air (cut-in and cut-out)","The governor controls the amount of moisture the air dryer removes from the system","Once air flows through the supply tank, the governor prevents it from returning","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"The governor causes the compressor to start and stop pumping air (cut-in and cut-out)"},{"Question":"What safety equipment is recommended while conducting an air brake inspection?","options":["Fire extinguisher, safety glasses, and  protective footwear","Safety glasses, protective headgear, and protective footwear","Protective headgear, ear plugs, and safety glasses","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Safety glasses, protective headgear, and protective footwear"},{"Question":"Actual cut-in pressure of the governor should never be less than:","options":["55 psi","80 psi","100 psi","120 psi"],"correctAnswer":"100 psi"},{"Question":"Damaged or worn air lines are not a concern until they have an obvious leak.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What happens if a single brake malfunctions?","options":["It puts more pressure on the other brakes","It causes the other brakes to quickly overheat","It could cause the other brakes to fail","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"If the low air-pressure warning device activates below 55 psi, this would be considered a minor defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Automatic slack adjusters, if working properly, require regular re-adjustment.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"The Highway Traffic Act and Regulations prohibit the operation of a vehicle with a brake that is out of adjustment.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"If the governor fails to signal the compressor to cut-out what allows the excess air pressure to escape?","options":["The air dryer","A one way check valve","The low pressure warning system","A safety valve"],"correctAnswer":"A safety valve"},{"Question":"Brake lining is defective when it is:","options":["Cracked","Missing","Loose","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"If the governor fails to signal the compressor to cut-out what allows the excess air pressure to escape?","options":["The air dryer","A one way check valve","The low pressure warning system","A safety valve"],"correctAnswer":"A safety valve"},{"Question":"Who is responsible for ensuring air brakes are correctly adjusted?","options":["The employer","The manufacturer","The last person driving the vehicle","The current driver"],"correctAnswer":"The current driver"},{"Question":"What can cause damage or deterioration to brake hoses and tubes?","options":["Wear and cuts","Wear, cuts, and heat damage","Wear, cuts, abrasions, and heat damage","Abrasions and heat damage"],"correctAnswer":"Wear, cuts, abrasions, and heat damage"},{"Question":"Actual cut-in pressure for the governor should never be less than 90 PSI?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When checking the buildup rate (compressor operation) the engine should be building air pressure from _____ psi to ____ psi within two minutes:","options":["45 - 65","65 - 85","85 - 100","100 - 125"],"correctAnswer":"85 - 100"},{"Question":"Spring brakes use air to apply the brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"The brake on each end of an axel should have a different sized air brake chamber to ensure brake forces are balanced.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Wheels, dust shields, and other parts of the vehicle have no impact on your view of the brake drums and rotors.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Inspecting the vehicle\u2019s air lines includes checking for the following defects:","options":["Audible air leak","Damage or worn air lines","Improper fittings used to connect or repair an air line","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Where are air brake chambers located?","options":["At each wheel","At the drive wheels only","At the trailer wheels only","At both the drive and trailer wheels"],"correctAnswer":"At each wheel"},{"Question":"What can indicate that an air tank or mounting bracket is not secure?","options":["Unusual movement","An air leak","A fluid leak","A deflated airbag"],"correctAnswer":"Unusual movement"},{"Question":"Inspecting a vehicle\u2019s air brake chambers includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Audible air leaks","Cracks and non-manufactured holes","Brakes with different air brake chamber sizes on each end of a steering axle","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"The size of an air brake chamber is based on the area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"There is often a noticeable change in the behaviour of brakes with drums or rotors that are defective, cracked or broken.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When checking the air pressure buildup rate (compressor operation), what should the engine be idling between?","options":["200 - 500 rpm","500 - 800 rpm","600 - 900 rpm","900 - 1200 rpm"],"correctAnswer":"600 - 900 rpm"},{"Question":"An inspection of a vehicle\u2019s brake drums and rotors includes checking for the following defect:","options":["Cracked or broken brake drums","Cracked or broken rotors","Both A and B","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Both A and B"},{"Question":"Your spring brakes should be used when parking or in an emergency when your service brakes fail?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When the brakes are applied, a brake malfunction is indicated by the brake lining not contacting the drum.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"How can air brake chamber air leaks usually be detected?","options":["Visually","Audibly","By checking pushrod travel distance","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Audibly"},{"Question":"How would you know if the anti-lock braking system had a malfunction?","options":["The brakes won\'t function at all","The brakes will function intermittently","Only the trailer hand valve functions","The ABS malfunction warning light illuminates"],"correctAnswer":"The ABS malfunction warning light illuminates"},{"Question":"If air pressure drops below the normal cut-in setting what should the driver do?","options":["Continue driving until the spring brakes apply","Make several full brake applications","Nothing","Bring the vehicle to a safe stop as soon as possible"],"correctAnswer":"Bring the vehicle to a safe stop as soon as possible"},{"Question":"When testing the low air-pressure warning device, the engine can be stopped or running but the ignition must be on.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"How often is it recommended that the air tanks be drained?","options":["At the beginning of every trip","At the end of every trip","Every day","Once a week"],"correctAnswer":"Every day"},{"Question":"Air compressors can be inspected with the engine running or stopped.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When testing brake performance (tug tests), it would be considered a major defect if:","options":["The spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle in place","The service brakes fail to stop the vehicle","Only if the tractor spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle","Both A and B"],"correctAnswer":"Both A and B"},{"Question":"Why are automatic slack adjusters used?","options":["They make inspections and adjustments unnecessary","As a backup to a manual slack adjuster","To avoid the need to regularly perform manual re-adjustments","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To avoid the need to regularly perform manual re-adjustments"},{"Question":"The brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum is an example of:","options":["A foundation brake component defect","An issue with the brake chamber","An incorrectly measured pushrod","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"A foundation brake component defect"},{"Question":"Inspecting the brake components includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum","Damaged, missing or malfunctioning foundation brake components","Cracked, loose, missing or contaminated brake lining, improper drum contact or lining thickness that is less than required","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"When the pushrod stroke exceeds the adjustment limit of the brake chamber, the brake:","options":["Is out of adjustment","Is in adjustment","Needs to be replaced","Has a minor defect"],"correctAnswer":"Is out of adjustment"},{"Question":"In Manitoba, who can perform brake adjustments on manual slack adjusters so the pushrod is less than the adjusted limit?","options":["A licensed driver with an A endorsement or a certified technician","A licensed driver with an S endorsement","The owner for the vehicle","A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"],"correctAnswer":"A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"},{"Question":"When checking the buildup rate (compressor operation) the engine should be building air pressure from _____ psi to ____ psi within two minutes:","options":["45 - 65","65 - 85","85 - 100","100 - 125"],"correctAnswer":"85 - 100"},{"Question":"Air brake chambers from different manufacturers may look different even if they are the same size.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Failure of the spring brakes to hold the vehicle stationary indicates defective service brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What controls an air brake system\u2019s pressure range (cut-in and cut-out settings)?","options":["The governor","The compressor","The engine","The turbo-charger"],"correctAnswer":"The governor"},{"Question":"Older air systems may operate with lower pressure settings.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"The brake on each end of an axel should have a different sized air brake chamber to ensure brake forces are balanced.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Inspecting a vehicle\u2019s air lines includes checking for the following defects:","options":["Audible air leak","Damaged or worn air lines","Improper fittings used to connect or repair air lines","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"If the governor fails to signal the compressor to cut-out what allows the excess air pressure to escape?","options":["The air dryer","A one way check valve","The low pressure warning system","A safety valve"],"correctAnswer":"A safety valve"},{"Question":"Why would a brake chamber need to be \'caged\'?","options":["To move the vehicle in an emergency","To allow for proper braking","To measure your pushrod travel","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To move the vehicle in an emergency"},{"Question":"How would you know if the anti-lock braking system had a malfunction?","options":["The brakes won\'t function at all","The brakes will function intermittently","Only the trailer hand valve functions","The ABS malfunction warning light illuminates"],"correctAnswer":"The ABS malfunction warning light illuminates"},{"Question":"What can cause damage or deterioration to brake hoses and tubes?","options":["Wear and cuts","Wear, cuts, and heat damage","Wear, cuts, abrasions, and heat damage","Abrasions and heat damage"],"correctAnswer":"Wear, cuts, abrasions, and heat damage"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not be lower than:","options":["60 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"120 psi"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the tractor protection valve?","options":["Prevents total air loss from the trailer if the trailer breaks away","Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away","Holds the supply line and emergency line in place not allowing them to break away","Prevents over pressure in the system allowing excess air to escape"],"correctAnswer":"Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away"},{"Question":"What should you do before you exit the vehicle or get underneath it?","options":["Start the vehicle","Secure the vehicle","Grab your safety equipment","Turn off the vehicle"],"correctAnswer":"Secure the vehicle"},{"Question":"Where are air brake chambers located?","options":["At each wheel","At the drive wheels only","At the trailer wheels only","At both the drive and trailer wheels"],"correctAnswer":"At each wheel"},{"Question":"What does ABS stand for?","options":["Automatic Brake Stop","Automatic Braking System","Anti-lock Brake System","Accelerated Braking System"],"correctAnswer":"Anti-lock Brake System"},{"Question":"At what level must the low pressure warning device activate?","options":["At or above 60 psi","Between 40 - 50 psi","At or above 85 psi","At or above 55 psi"],"correctAnswer":"At or above 55 psi"},{"Question":"What can indicate that an air tank or mounting bracket is not secure?","options":["Unusual movement","An air leak","A fluid leak","A deflated airbag"],"correctAnswer":"Unusual movement"},{"Question":"To ensure balanced braking, slack adjusters on each side of an axel should:","options":["Be the same effective lengths","Have no more than 1 inch difference","Be attached using different holes","Both B and C"],"correctAnswer":"Be the same effective lengths"},{"Question":"What does the air compressor do?","options":["The air compressor draws power from the battery to power the vehicle","The air compressor builds air for the trailer only","The air compressor draws air in and forces it into a smaller space increasing air pressure","The air compressor removes moisture from the air brake system"],"correctAnswer":"The air compressor draws air in and forces it into a smaller space increasing air pressure"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel is within the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This:","options":["Is a minor defect","Is a major defect","Passes the inspection","Is a broken or defective part"],"correctAnswer":"Passes the inspection"},{"Question":"What should the air pressure be when performing a brake adjustment inspection at each wheel?","options":["Between 80 - 90 psi","Between 90 - 100 psi","Between 100 - 110 psi","At maximum pressure"],"correctAnswer":"Between 90 - 100 psi"},{"Question":"When should the supply tank be drained?","options":["First","Last","In whatever order is most convenient for the driver","The supply tank should never be drained"],"correctAnswer":"First"},{"Question":"In Manitoba, who can perform brake adjustments on manual slack adjusters so the pushrod is less than the adjusted limit?","options":["A licensed driver with an A endorsement or a certified technician","A licensed driver with an S endorsement","The owner for the vehicle","A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"],"correctAnswer":"A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"},{"Question":"Inspecting the air compressor includes checking for which defects?","options":["Loose air compressor drive belt pulley","Loose, cut or frayed air compressor drive belt","Insecure air compressor mounting, bracket or fasteners","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"As brakes heat up, you may experience a reduction in their effectiveness. This is known as:","options":["ABS brakes","Anti-lock braking","Brake fade","Combination braking"],"correctAnswer":"Brake fade"},{"Question":"Vehicles with air brakes must comply with The Highway Traffic Act and Regulations. If a vehicle does not comply, both the driver and the operator may be charged.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"The air pressure must build from 85 psi to 100 psi in _______?","options":["30 seconds","One minute","Two minutes","Three minutes"],"correctAnswer":"Two minutes"},{"Question":"Brake lining is defective when it is:","options":["Cracked","Missing","Loose","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"When the brakes are applied, a brake malfunction is indicated by the brake lining not contacting the drum.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"The safety valve will open to allow excess air pressure to escape at a level no higher than?","options":["140 psi","145 psi","150 psi","155 psi"],"correctAnswer":"150 psi"},{"Question":"What is the size of an air brake chamber based on?","options":["The type of chamber","The area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches","The pushrod travel distance","The make and model of the vehicle"],"correctAnswer":"The area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches"},{"Question":"The air pressure must build from 85 psi to 100 psi in _______?","options":["30 seconds","One minute","Two minutes","Three minutes"],"correctAnswer":"Two minutes"},{"Question":"Wheels, dust shields, and other parts of the vehicle have no impact on your view of the brake drums and rotors.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"If air loss exceeds the maximum allowable limit specified for your vehicle, it would be considered a major defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Air brake chambers from different manufacturers may look different even if they are the same size.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What do anti-lock braking systems (ABS) do?","options":["Help maintain steering control during emergency braking","Help prevent wheel lock","Do not shorten the stopping distance","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"On a straight truck, tractor, or bus air loss test, what is the acceptable amount of air loss allowed within one minute?","options":["2 psi","3 psi","4 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"3 psi"},{"Question":"What happens when the trailer lines are not connected properly?","options":["Spring brakes may not release","The towing vehicle may lose air","Service brakes will not function properly","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"How would you know if the anti-lock braking system had a malfunction?","options":["The brakes won\'t function at all","The brakes will function intermittently","Only the trailer hand valve functions","The ABS malfunction warning light illuminates"],"correctAnswer":"The ABS malfunction warning light illuminates"},{"Question":"Failure of the spring brakes to hold the vehicle stationary indicates defective service brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What does ABS stand for?","options":["Automatic Brake Stop","Automatic Braking System","Anti-lock Brake System","Accelerated Braking System"],"correctAnswer":"Anti-lock Brake System"},{"Question":"Actual cut-in pressure of the governor should never be less than:","options":["55 psi","80 psi","100 psi","120 psi"],"correctAnswer":"100 psi"},{"Question":"The brake on each end of an axel should have a different sized air brake chamber to ensure brake forces are balanced.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"A brake chamber that includes both service brake and spring brake sections is called a:","options":["Brake chamber","Spring brake chamber","DD3 brake chamber","Service brake chamber"],"correctAnswer":"Spring brake chamber"},{"Question":"At what level must the low pressure warning device activate?","options":["At or above 60 psi","Between 40 - 50 psi","At or above 85 psi","At or above 55 psi"],"correctAnswer":"At or above 55 psi"},{"Question":"When checking the buildup rate (compressor operation) the engine should be building air pressure from _____ psi to ____ psi within two minutes:","options":["45 - 65","65 - 85","85 - 100","100 - 125"],"correctAnswer":"85 - 100"},{"Question":"What safety equipment is recommended while conducting an air brake inspection?","options":["Fire extinguisher, safety glasses, and  protective footwear","Safety glasses, protective headgear, and protective footwear","Protective headgear, ear plugs, and safety glasses","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Safety glasses, protective headgear, and protective footwear"},{"Question":"If the compressor takes longer than two minutes to build air from 85 psi to 100 psi, it would be considered a major defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When testing the tractor protection system, the trailer supply valve must close before the pressure drops below:","options":["20 psi","55 psi","60 psi","100 psi"],"correctAnswer":"20 psi"},{"Question":"The first air tank that air enters is called the supply (wet tank).","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Inspecting the brake components includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum","Damaged, missing or malfunctioning foundation brake components","Cracked, loose, missing or contaminated brake lining, improper drum contact or lining thickness that is less than required","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed in one minute on a tractor with two or more trailers?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","5 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"6 psi"},{"Question":"Air compressors can be inspected with the engine running or stopped.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Why should the gladhands be stored properly when not in use?","options":["To keep the seals from cracking","To make them easier to find next time they\u2019re needed","To keep them clean and in good condition","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To keep them clean and in good condition"},{"Question":"Automatic slack adjusters, if working properly, require regular re-adjustment.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"For the brakes to work, the brake-shoe lining must be greased and pressed against the brake drum when the brakes are applied.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"At what pressure do the spring brakes normally start to apply because there is no longer enough pressure to keep them released?","options":["20 psi","40 psi","60 psi","85 psi"],"correctAnswer":"60 psi"},{"Question":"When inspecting foundation brake components, the driver is expected to be able to identify brake components that are damaged, missing or malfunctioning.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When testing the air-loss rate of the brake system, the brake pedal must be fully applied.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"At what level must the low pressure warning device activate?","options":["At or above 60 psi","Between 40 - 50 psi","At or above 85 psi","At or above 55 psi"],"correctAnswer":"At or above 55 psi"},{"Question":"The brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum is an example of:","options":["A foundation brake component defect","An issue with the brake chamber","An incorrectly measured pushrod","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"A foundation brake component defect"},{"Question":"Wheels, dust shields, and other parts of the vehicle have no impact on your view of the brake drums and rotors.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"If the low air-pressure warning device activates below 55 psi, this would be considered a minor defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"In Manitoba, who can perform brake adjustments on manual slack adjusters so the pushrod is less than the adjusted limit?","options":["A licensed driver with an A endorsement or a certified technician","A licensed driver with an S endorsement","The owner for the vehicle","A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"],"correctAnswer":"A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"},{"Question":"What are the three different types of foundation brake systems?","options":["\'S\' cam brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes","ABS brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes","ABS brakes, \'S\' cam brakes, and wedge brakes","\'S\' cam brakes, ABS brakes, and disc brakes"],"correctAnswer":"\'S\' cam brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes"},{"Question":"When should the supply tank be drained?","options":["First","Last","In whatever order is most convenient for the driver","The supply tank should never be drained"],"correctAnswer":"First"},{"Question":"What safety equipment is recommended while conducting an air brake inspection?","options":["Fire extinguisher, safety glasses, and  protective footwear","Safety glasses, protective headgear, and protective footwear","Protective headgear, ear plugs, and safety glasses","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Safety glasses, protective headgear, and protective footwear"},{"Question":"An inspection of a vehicle\u2019s brake drums and rotors includes checking for the following defect:","options":["Cracked or broken brake drums","Cracked or broken rotors","Both A and B","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Both A and B"},{"Question":"When checking the buildup rate (compressor operation) the engine should be building air pressure from _____ psi to ____ psi within two minutes:","options":["45 - 65","65 - 85","85 - 100","100 - 125"],"correctAnswer":"85 - 100"},{"Question":"To ensure balanced braking, slack adjusters on each side of an axel should:","options":["Be the same effective lengths","Have no more than 1 inch difference","Be attached using different holes","Both B and C"],"correctAnswer":"Be the same effective lengths"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed in one minute on a tractor with two or more trailers?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","5 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"6 psi"},{"Question":"What should you do before you exit the vehicle or get underneath it?","options":["Start the vehicle","Secure the vehicle","Grab your safety equipment","Turn off the vehicle"],"correctAnswer":"Secure the vehicle"},{"Question":"When testing brake performance (tug tests), it would be considered a major defect if:","options":["The spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle in place","The service brakes fail to stop the vehicle","Only if the tractor spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle","Both A and B"],"correctAnswer":"Both A and B"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the safety valve?","options":["Starts building air pressure at 100 psi","Stops building air pressure at 140 psi","Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting","Ensures the trucks safety features are working correctly"],"correctAnswer":"Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting"},{"Question":"What should the air pressure be when performing a brake adjustment inspection at each wheel?","options":["Between 80 - 90 psi","Between 90 - 100 psi","Between 100 - 110 psi","At maximum pressure"],"correctAnswer":"Between 90 - 100 psi"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the tractor protection valve?","options":["Prevents total air loss from the trailer if the trailer breaks away","Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away","Holds the supply line and emergency line in place not allowing them to break away","Prevents over pressure in the system allowing excess air to escape"],"correctAnswer":"Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away"},{"Question":"When testing the air-loss rate of the brake system, the brake application must be held for:","options":["30 seconds","One minute","Two minutes","Three minutes"],"correctAnswer":"One minute"},{"Question":"When testing the low air-pressure warning device, the engine can be stopped or running but the ignition must be on.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What controls an air brake system\u2019s pressure range (cut-in and cut-out settings)?","options":["The governor","The compressor","The engine","The turbo-charger"],"correctAnswer":"The governor"},{"Question":"What happens when the trailer lines are not connected properly?","options":["Spring brakes may not release","The towing vehicle may lose air","Service brakes will not function properly","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"The brake on each end of an axel should have a different sized air brake chamber to ensure brake forces are balanced.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle\u2019s air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel exceeds the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This is:","options":["A minor defect","A major defect","Within the acceptable adjustment limit","Something to keep track of"],"correctAnswer":"A major defect"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not exceed:","options":["90 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"145 psi"},{"Question":"Testing the performance of your brakes requires performing separate tests of each braking system.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When testing the tractor protection system, the trailer supply valve must close before the pressure drops below:","options":["20 psi","55 psi","60 psi","100 psi"],"correctAnswer":"20 psi"},{"Question":"Damaged or worn air lines are not a concern until they have an obvious leak.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"If air loss exceeds the maximum allowable limit specified for your vehicle, it would be considered a major defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"A spring brake control valve is usually yellow?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"If the governor fails to signal the compressor to cut-out what allows the excess air pressure to escape?","options":["The air dryer","A one way check valve","The low pressure warning system","A safety valve"],"correctAnswer":"A safety valve"},{"Question":"The vehicle must be secured by the spring brakes or by wheel chocks before leaving the driver\u2019s seat or going under the vehicle.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What happens when the trailer lines are not connected properly?","options":["Spring brakes may not release","The towing vehicle may lose air","Service brakes will not function properly","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Inspecting the air compressor includes checking for which defects?","options":["Loose air compressor drive belt pulley","Loose, cut or frayed air compressor drive belt","Insecure air compressor mounting, bracket or fasteners","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"If air loss exceeds the maximum allowable limit specified for your vehicle, it would be considered a major defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the governor?","options":["The governor causes the compressor to start and stop pumping air (cut-in and cut-out)","The governor controls the amount of moisture the air dryer removes from the system","Once air flows through the supply tank, the governor prevents it from returning","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"The governor causes the compressor to start and stop pumping air (cut-in and cut-out)"},{"Question":"As brakes heat up, you may experience a reduction in their effectiveness. This is known as:","options":["ABS brakes","Anti-lock braking","Brake fade","Combination braking"],"correctAnswer":"Brake fade"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed when testing the air-loss rate of the brake system on a tractor and trailer?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","6 psi","10 psi"],"correctAnswer":"4 psi"},{"Question":"A spring brake control valve is usually yellow?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What are the three different types of foundation brake systems?","options":["\'S\' cam brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes","ABS brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes","ABS brakes, \'S\' cam brakes, and wedge brakes","\'S\' cam brakes, ABS brakes, and disc brakes"],"correctAnswer":"\'S\' cam brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes"},{"Question":"When testing the air-loss rate of the brake system, the brake pedal must be fully applied.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel is within the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This:","options":["Is a minor defect","Is a major defect","Passes the inspection","Is a broken or defective part"],"correctAnswer":"Passes the inspection"},{"Question":"The brake on each end of an axel should have a different sized air brake chamber to ensure brake forces are balanced.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Who is responsible for ensuring air brakes are correctly adjusted?","options":["The employer","The manufacturer","The last person driving the vehicle","The current driver"],"correctAnswer":"The current driver"},{"Question":"When testing the air-loss rate of the brake system, the brake application must be held for:","options":["30 seconds","One minute","Two minutes","Three minutes"],"correctAnswer":"One minute"},{"Question":"Inspecting the vehicle\u2019s air lines includes checking for the following defects:","options":["Audible air leak","Damage or worn air lines","Improper fittings used to connect or repair an air line","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Operating a vehicle with defects or failing to conduct the required inspections can result in:","options":["Charges against the driver and/or operator","Detainment or impoundment of the vehicle","Fines","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"For the brakes to work, the brake-shoe lining must be greased and pressed against the brake drum when the brakes are applied.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When conducting an inspection of the air brake system, be sure to:","options":["Park the vehicle on level ground","Park the vehicle away from traffic","Turn the engine off","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"The safety valve will open to allow excess air pressure to escape at a level no higher than?","options":["140 psi","145 psi","150 psi","155 psi"],"correctAnswer":"150 psi"},{"Question":"When the pushrod stroke exceeds the adjustment limit of the brake chamber, the brake:","options":["Is out of adjustment","Is in adjustment","Needs to be replaced","Has a minor defect"],"correctAnswer":"Is out of adjustment"},{"Question":"If the low air-pressure warning device activates below 55 psi, this would be considered a minor defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Failure of the spring brakes to hold the vehicle stationary indicates defective service brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What safety equipment is recommended while conducting an air brake inspection?","options":["Fire extinguisher, safety glasses, and  protective footwear","Safety glasses, protective headgear, and protective footwear","Protective headgear, ear plugs, and safety glasses","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Safety glasses, protective headgear, and protective footwear"},{"Question":"Why should the gladhands be stored properly when not in use?","options":["To keep the seals from cracking","To make them easier to find next time they\u2019re needed","To keep them clean and in good condition","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To keep them clean and in good condition"},{"Question":"Where are air brake chambers located?","options":["At each wheel","At the drive wheels only","At the trailer wheels only","At both the drive and trailer wheels"],"correctAnswer":"At each wheel"},{"Question":"The air pressure must build from 85 psi to 100 psi in _______?","options":["30 seconds","One minute","Two minutes","Three minutes"],"correctAnswer":"Two minutes"},{"Question":"Why are automatic slack adjusters used?","options":["They make inspections and adjustments unnecessary","As a backup to a manual slack adjuster","To avoid the need to regularly perform manual re-adjustments","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To avoid the need to regularly perform manual re-adjustments"},{"Question":"If the governor fails to signal the compressor to cut-out what allows the excess air pressure to escape?","options":["The air dryer","A one way check valve","The low pressure warning system","A safety valve"],"correctAnswer":"A safety valve"},{"Question":"To ensure balanced braking, slack adjusters on each side of an axel should:","options":["Be the same effective lengths","Have no more than 1 inch difference","Be attached using different holes","Both B and C"],"correctAnswer":"Be the same effective lengths"},{"Question":"When testing the low air-pressure warning device, the engine can be stopped or running but the ignition must be on.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"If any single brake malfunctions, what affect will it have on the other brakes?","options":["None","The malfunctioning brake will overheat causing damage","They will overheat quickly and possibly fail","The braking power will be slightly reduced"],"correctAnswer":"They will overheat quickly and possibly fail"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed in one minute on a tractor with two or more trailers?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","5 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"6 psi"},{"Question":"On a straight truck, tractor, or bus air loss test, what is the acceptable amount of air loss allowed within one minute?","options":["2 psi","3 psi","4 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"3 psi"},{"Question":"There is often a noticeable change in the behaviour of brakes with drums or rotors that are defective, cracked or broken.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Brake lining is defective when it is:","options":["Cracked","Missing","Loose","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What is a reliable method for inspecting your brake adjustment?","options":["Measuring the applied pushrod stroke","Checking the slack adjustment","Checking the condition of the brake drum","Measuring the brake chamber size"],"correctAnswer":"Measuring the applied pushrod stroke"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the tractor protection valve?","options":["Prevents total air loss from the trailer if the trailer breaks away","Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away","Holds the supply line and emergency line in place not allowing them to break away","Prevents over pressure in the system allowing excess air to escape"],"correctAnswer":"Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away"},{"Question":"In what order should air tanks be drained?","options":["Wet, primary, secondary","Primary, secondary, wet","Primary, wet, secondary","All at the same time"],"correctAnswer":"Wet, primary, secondary"},{"Question":"Spring brakes use air to apply the brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Why would a brake chamber need to be \'caged\'?","options":["To move the vehicle in an emergency","To allow for proper braking","To measure your pushrod travel","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To move the vehicle in an emergency"},{"Question":"The air pressure must build from 85 psi to 100 psi in _______?","options":["30 seconds","One minute","Two minutes","Three minutes"],"correctAnswer":"Two minutes"},{"Question":"Inspecting the brake components includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum","Damaged, missing or malfunctioning foundation brake components","Cracked, loose, missing or contaminated brake lining, improper drum contact or lining thickness that is less than required","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Actual cut-in pressure of the governor should never be less than:","options":["55 psi","80 psi","100 psi","120 psi"],"correctAnswer":"100 psi"},{"Question":"Spring brakes use air to apply the brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"If air exhausts from the service line, it means that the trailer supply valve is defective.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the safety valve?","options":["Starts building air pressure at 100 psi","Stops building air pressure at 140 psi","Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting","Ensures the trucks safety features are working correctly"],"correctAnswer":"Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting"},{"Question":"Inspecting the vehicle\u2019s air lines includes checking for the following defects:","options":["Audible air leak","Damage or worn air lines","Improper fittings used to connect or repair an air line","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Air compressors can be inspected with the engine running or stopped.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"How often is it recommended that the air tanks be drained?","options":["At the beginning of every trip","At the end of every trip","Every day","Once a week"],"correctAnswer":"Every day"},{"Question":"The first air tank that air enters is called the supply (wet tank).","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Inspecting a vehicle\u2019s air lines includes checking for the following defects:","options":["Audible air leak","Damaged or worn air lines","Improper fittings used to connect or repair air lines","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"When testing the compressor, if there is a trailer attached, the trailer supply valve must be closed.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"In Manitoba, who can perform brake adjustments on manual slack adjusters so the pushrod is less than the adjusted limit?","options":["A licensed driver with an A endorsement or a certified technician","A licensed driver with an S endorsement","The owner for the vehicle","A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"],"correctAnswer":"A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"},{"Question":"When conducting an inspection of the air brake system, be sure to:","options":["Park the vehicle on level ground","Park the vehicle away from traffic","Turn the engine off","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What do anti-lock braking systems (ABS) do?","options":["Help maintain steering control during emergency braking","Help prevent wheel lock","Do not shorten the stopping distance","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Wheels, dust shields, and other parts of the vehicle have no impact on your view of the brake drums and rotors.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What happens if a single brake malfunctions?","options":["It puts more pressure on the other brakes","It causes the other brakes to quickly overheat","It could cause the other brakes to fail","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"The Highway Traffic Act and Regulations prohibit the operation of a vehicle with a brake that is out of adjustment.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Your spring brakes should be used when parking or in an emergency when your service brakes fail?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"In order to make a service brake application?","options":["Pull the yellow button","Pull the red button","Push the brake pedal","Push the red and yellow buttons"],"correctAnswer":"Push the brake pedal"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not exceed:","options":["90 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"145 psi"},{"Question":"The brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum is an example of:","options":["A foundation brake component defect","An issue with the brake chamber","An incorrectly measured pushrod","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"A foundation brake component defect"},{"Question":"If the compressor takes longer than two minutes to build air from 85 psi to 100 psi, it would be considered a major defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed in one minute on a tractor with two or more trailers?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","5 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"6 psi"},{"Question":"If the governor fails to signal the compressor to cut-out what allows the excess air pressure to escape?","options":["The air dryer","A one way check valve","The low pressure warning system","A safety valve"],"correctAnswer":"A safety valve"},{"Question":"What happens when the trailer lines are not connected properly?","options":["Spring brakes may not release","The towing vehicle may lose air","Service brakes will not function properly","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Inspecting a vehicle\u2019s air lines includes checking for the following defects:","options":["Audible air leak","Damaged or worn air lines","Improper fittings used to connect or repair air lines","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Damaged or worn air lines are not a concern until they have an obvious leak.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the governor?","options":["The governor causes the compressor to start and stop pumping air (cut-in and cut-out)","The governor controls the amount of moisture the air dryer removes from the system","Once air flows through the supply tank, the governor prevents it from returning","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"The governor causes the compressor to start and stop pumping air (cut-in and cut-out)"},{"Question":"When conducting an inspection of the air brake system, be sure to:","options":["Park the vehicle on level ground","Park the vehicle away from traffic","Turn the engine off","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"When checking the buildup rate (compressor operation) the engine should be building air pressure from _____ psi to ____ psi within two minutes:","options":["45 - 65","65 - 85","85 - 100","100 - 125"],"correctAnswer":"85 - 100"},{"Question":"Inspecting a vehicle\u2019s air brake chambers includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Audible air leaks","Cracks and non-manufactured holes","Brakes with different air brake chamber sizes on each end of a steering axle","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Brake lining is defective when it is:","options":["Cracked","Missing","Loose","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Inspecting the air compressor includes checking for which defects?","options":["Loose air compressor drive belt pulley","Loose, cut or frayed air compressor drive belt","Insecure air compressor mounting, bracket or fasteners","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"In order to make a service brake application?","options":["Pull the yellow button","Pull the red button","Push the brake pedal","Push the red and yellow buttons"],"correctAnswer":"Push the brake pedal"},{"Question":"If the low air-pressure warning device activates below 55 psi, this would be considered a minor defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When should the supply tank be drained?","options":["First","Last","In whatever order is most convenient for the driver","The supply tank should never be drained"],"correctAnswer":"First"},{"Question":"Spring brakes use air to apply the brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Actual cut-in pressure of the governor should never be less than:","options":["55 psi","80 psi","100 psi","120 psi"],"correctAnswer":"100 psi"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not be lower than:","options":["60 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"120 psi"},{"Question":"There is often a noticeable change in the behaviour of brakes with drums or rotors that are defective, cracked or broken.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When testing the low air-pressure warning device, the engine can be stopped or running but the ignition must be on.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What should the air pressure be when performing a brake adjustment inspection at each wheel?","options":["Between 80 - 90 psi","Between 90 - 100 psi","Between 100 - 110 psi","At maximum pressure"],"correctAnswer":"Between 90 - 100 psi"},{"Question":"When grease or oil is present on the brake lining:","options":["The brake lining is properly lubricated","Abnormal brake behaviour will result","The brake lining has been over-lubricated","The driver can continue to drive the vehicle as it will not cause any issues with brake function"],"correctAnswer":"Abnormal brake behaviour will result"},{"Question":"Why would a brake chamber need to be \'caged\'?","options":["To move the vehicle in an emergency","To allow for proper braking","To measure your pushrod travel","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To move the vehicle in an emergency"},{"Question":"When should the supply tank be drained?","options":["First","Last","In whatever order is most convenient for the driver","The supply tank should never be drained"],"correctAnswer":"First"},{"Question":"When testing brake performance (tug tests), it would be considered a major defect if:","options":["The spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle in place","The service brakes fail to stop the vehicle","Only if the tractor spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle","Both A and B"],"correctAnswer":"Both A and B"},{"Question":"Brake lining is defective when it is:","options":["Cracked","Missing","Loose","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"When the pushrod stroke exceeds the adjustment limit of the brake chamber, the brake:","options":["Is out of adjustment","Is in adjustment","Needs to be replaced","Has a minor defect"],"correctAnswer":"Is out of adjustment"},{"Question":"As brakes heat up, you may experience a reduction in their effectiveness. This is known as:","options":["ABS brakes","Anti-lock braking","Brake fade","Combination braking"],"correctAnswer":"Brake fade"},{"Question":"When testing the air-loss rate of the brake system, the brake application must be held for:","options":["30 seconds","One minute","Two minutes","Three minutes"],"correctAnswer":"One minute"},{"Question":"Inspecting the air compressor includes checking for which defects?","options":["Loose air compressor drive belt pulley","Loose, cut or frayed air compressor drive belt","Insecure air compressor mounting, bracket or fasteners","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Actual cut-in pressure for the governor should never be less than 90 PSI?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"On a straight truck, tractor, or bus air loss test, what is the acceptable amount of air loss allowed within one minute?","options":["2 psi","3 psi","4 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"3 psi"},{"Question":"Who is responsible for ensuring air brakes are correctly adjusted?","options":["The employer","The manufacturer","The last person driving the vehicle","The current driver"],"correctAnswer":"The current driver"},{"Question":"Spring brakes use air to apply the brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When testing the air-loss rate of the brake system, the brake pedal must be fully applied.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"If you double your vehicle weight and double your speed, what does your stopping distance increase by?","options":["Four times","Six times","Eight times","Ten times"],"correctAnswer":"Eight times"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel is within the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This:","options":["Is a minor defect","Is a major defect","Passes the inspection","Is a broken or defective part"],"correctAnswer":"Passes the inspection"},{"Question":"What is a reliable method for inspecting your brake adjustment?","options":["Measuring the applied pushrod stroke","Checking the slack adjustment","Checking the condition of the brake drum","Measuring the brake chamber size"],"correctAnswer":"Measuring the applied pushrod stroke"},{"Question":"To ensure balanced braking, slack adjusters on each side of an axel should:","options":["Be the same effective lengths","Have no more than 1 inch difference","Be attached using different holes","Both B and C"],"correctAnswer":"Be the same effective lengths"},{"Question":"What can indicate that an air tank or mounting bracket is not secure?","options":["Unusual movement","An air leak","A fluid leak","A deflated airbag"],"correctAnswer":"Unusual movement"},{"Question":"At what level must the low pressure warning device activate?","options":["At or above 60 psi","Between 40 - 50 psi","At or above 85 psi","At or above 55 psi"],"correctAnswer":"At or above 55 psi"},{"Question":"Automatic slack adjusters, if working properly, require regular re-adjustment.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Inspecting the air compressor includes checking for which defects?","options":["Loose air compressor drive belt pulley","Loose, cut or frayed air compressor drive belt","Insecure air compressor mounting, bracket or fasteners","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Who is responsible for ensuring air brakes are correctly adjusted?","options":["The employer","The manufacturer","The last person driving the vehicle","The current driver"],"correctAnswer":"The current driver"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not be lower than:","options":["60 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"120 psi"},{"Question":"For the brakes to work, the brake-shoe lining must be greased and pressed against the brake drum when the brakes are applied.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Vehicles with air brakes must comply with The Highway Traffic Act and Regulations. If a vehicle does not comply, both the driver and the operator may be charged.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"If air loss exceeds the maximum allowable limit specified for your vehicle, it would be considered a major defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed in one minute on a tractor with two or more trailers?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","5 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"6 psi"},{"Question":"The Highway Traffic Act and Regulations prohibit the operation of a vehicle with a brake that is out of adjustment.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What does ABS stand for?","options":["Automatic Brake Stop","Automatic Braking System","Anti-lock Brake System","Accelerated Braking System"],"correctAnswer":"Anti-lock Brake System"},{"Question":"What do anti-lock braking systems (ABS) do?","options":["Help maintain steering control during emergency braking","Help prevent wheel lock","Do not shorten the stopping distance","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"On a straight truck, tractor, or bus air loss test, what is the acceptable amount of air loss allowed within one minute?","options":["2 psi","3 psi","4 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"3 psi"},{"Question":"If you double your vehicle weight and double your speed, what does your stopping distance increase by?","options":["Four times","Six times","Eight times","Ten times"],"correctAnswer":"Eight times"},{"Question":"Your spring brakes should be used when parking or in an emergency when your service brakes fail?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not exceed:","options":["90 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"145 psi"},{"Question":"A brake chamber that includes both service brake and spring brake sections is called a:","options":["Brake chamber","Spring brake chamber","DD3 brake chamber","Service brake chamber"],"correctAnswer":"Spring brake chamber"},{"Question":"When testing the compressor, if there is a trailer attached, the trailer supply valve must be closed.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the governor?","options":["The governor causes the compressor to start and stop pumping air (cut-in and cut-out)","The governor controls the amount of moisture the air dryer removes from the system","Once air flows through the supply tank, the governor prevents it from returning","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"The governor causes the compressor to start and stop pumping air (cut-in and cut-out)"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed in one minute on a tractor with two or more trailers?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","5 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"6 psi"},{"Question":"If the governor fails to signal the compressor to cut-out what allows the excess air pressure to escape?","options":["The air dryer","A one way check valve","The low pressure warning system","A safety valve"],"correctAnswer":"A safety valve"},{"Question":"Operating a vehicle with defects or failing to conduct the required inspections can result in:","options":["Charges against the driver and/or operator","Detainment or impoundment of the vehicle","Fines","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not be lower than:","options":["60 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"120 psi"},{"Question":"Automatic slack adjusters, if working properly, require regular re-adjustment.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When testing brake performance (tug tests), it would be considered a major defect if:","options":["The spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle in place","The service brakes fail to stop the vehicle","Only if the tractor spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle","Both A and B"],"correctAnswer":"Both A and B"},{"Question":"A spring brake control valve is usually yellow?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed when testing the air-loss rate of the brake system on a tractor and trailer?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","6 psi","10 psi"],"correctAnswer":"4 psi"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the tractor protection valve?","options":["Prevents total air loss from the trailer if the trailer breaks away","Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away","Holds the supply line and emergency line in place not allowing them to break away","Prevents over pressure in the system allowing excess air to escape"],"correctAnswer":"Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away"},{"Question":"What controls an air brake system\u2019s pressure range (cut-in and cut-out settings)?","options":["The governor","The compressor","The engine","The turbo-charger"],"correctAnswer":"The governor"},{"Question":"Failure of the spring brakes to hold the vehicle stationary indicates defective service brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What can indicate that an air tank or mounting bracket is not secure?","options":["Unusual movement","An air leak","A fluid leak","A deflated airbag"],"correctAnswer":"Unusual movement"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the safety valve?","options":["Starts building air pressure at 100 psi","Stops building air pressure at 140 psi","Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting","Ensures the trucks safety features are working correctly"],"correctAnswer":"Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting"},{"Question":"When testing the compressor, if there is a trailer attached, the trailer supply valve must be closed.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"The vehicle must be secured by the spring brakes or by wheel chocks before leaving the driver\u2019s seat or going under the vehicle.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"The engine must be running when testing the air-loss rate.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"If air exhausts from the service line, it means that the trailer supply valve is defective.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Where are air brake chambers located?","options":["At each wheel","At the drive wheels only","At the trailer wheels only","At both the drive and trailer wheels"],"correctAnswer":"At each wheel"},{"Question":"Why would a brake chamber need to be \'caged\'?","options":["To move the vehicle in an emergency","To allow for proper braking","To measure your pushrod travel","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To move the vehicle in an emergency"},{"Question":"What should you do before you exit the vehicle or get underneath it?","options":["Start the vehicle","Secure the vehicle","Grab your safety equipment","Turn off the vehicle"],"correctAnswer":"Secure the vehicle"},{"Question":"To ensure balanced braking, slack adjusters on each side of an axel should:","options":["Be the same effective lengths","Have no more than 1 inch difference","Be attached using different holes","Both B and C"],"correctAnswer":"Be the same effective lengths"},{"Question":"Why are automatic slack adjusters used?","options":["They make inspections and adjustments unnecessary","As a backup to a manual slack adjuster","To avoid the need to regularly perform manual re-adjustments","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To avoid the need to regularly perform manual re-adjustments"},{"Question":"If any single brake malfunctions, what affect will it have on the other brakes?","options":["None","The malfunctioning brake will overheat causing damage","They will overheat quickly and possibly fail","The braking power will be slightly reduced"],"correctAnswer":"They will overheat quickly and possibly fail"},{"Question":"When the pushrod stroke exceeds the adjustment limit of the brake chamber, the brake:","options":["Is out of adjustment","Is in adjustment","Needs to be replaced","Has a minor defect"],"correctAnswer":"Is out of adjustment"},{"Question":"What should the air pressure be when performing a brake adjustment inspection at each wheel?","options":["Between 80 - 90 psi","Between 90 - 100 psi","Between 100 - 110 psi","At maximum pressure"],"correctAnswer":"Between 90 - 100 psi"},{"Question":"Actual cut-in pressure of the governor should never be less than:","options":["55 psi","80 psi","100 psi","120 psi"],"correctAnswer":"100 psi"},{"Question":"What happens if a single brake malfunctions?","options":["It puts more pressure on the other brakes","It causes the other brakes to quickly overheat","It could cause the other brakes to fail","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"When testing the tractor protection system, the trailer supply valve must close before the pressure drops below:","options":["20 psi","55 psi","60 psi","100 psi"],"correctAnswer":"20 psi"},{"Question":"Damaged or worn air lines are not a concern until they have an obvious leak.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"For the brakes to work, the brake-shoe lining must be greased and pressed against the brake drum when the brakes are applied.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Who is responsible for ensuring air brakes are correctly adjusted?","options":["The employer","The manufacturer","The last person driving the vehicle","The current driver"],"correctAnswer":"The current driver"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not be lower than:","options":["60 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"120 psi"},{"Question":"Air compressors can be inspected with the engine running or stopped.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"An inspection of a vehicle\u2019s brake drums and rotors includes checking for the following defect:","options":["Cracked or broken brake drums","Cracked or broken rotors","Both A and B","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Both A and B"},{"Question":"The brake on each end of an axel should have a different sized air brake chamber to ensure brake forces are balanced.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the governor?","options":["The governor causes the compressor to start and stop pumping air (cut-in and cut-out)","The governor controls the amount of moisture the air dryer removes from the system","Once air flows through the supply tank, the governor prevents it from returning","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"The governor causes the compressor to start and stop pumping air (cut-in and cut-out)"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed when testing the air-loss rate of the brake system on a tractor and trailer?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","6 psi","10 psi"],"correctAnswer":"4 psi"},{"Question":"What controls an air brake system\u2019s pressure range (cut-in and cut-out settings)?","options":["The governor","The compressor","The engine","The turbo-charger"],"correctAnswer":"The governor"},{"Question":"If the governor fails to signal the compressor to cut-out what allows the excess air pressure to escape?","options":["The air dryer","A one way check valve","The low pressure warning system","A safety valve"],"correctAnswer":"A safety valve"},{"Question":"If the governor fails to signal the compressor to cut-out what allows the excess air pressure to escape?","options":["The air dryer","A one way check valve","The low pressure warning system","A safety valve"],"correctAnswer":"A safety valve"},{"Question":"A spring brake control valve is usually yellow?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What does the air compressor do?","options":["The air compressor draws power from the battery to power the vehicle","The air compressor builds air for the trailer only","The air compressor draws air in and forces it into a smaller space increasing air pressure","The air compressor removes moisture from the air brake system"],"correctAnswer":"The air compressor draws air in and forces it into a smaller space increasing air pressure"},{"Question":"At what level must the low pressure warning device activate?","options":["At or above 60 psi","Between 40 - 50 psi","At or above 85 psi","At or above 55 psi"],"correctAnswer":"At or above 55 psi"},{"Question":"Actual cut-in pressure of the governor should never be less than:","options":["55 psi","80 psi","100 psi","120 psi"],"correctAnswer":"100 psi"},{"Question":"When grease or oil is present on the brake lining:","options":["The brake lining is properly lubricated","Abnormal brake behaviour will result","The brake lining has been over-lubricated","The driver can continue to drive the vehicle as it will not cause any issues with brake function"],"correctAnswer":"Abnormal brake behaviour will result"},{"Question":"If any single brake malfunctions, what affect will it have on the other brakes?","options":["None","The malfunctioning brake will overheat causing damage","They will overheat quickly and possibly fail","The braking power will be slightly reduced"],"correctAnswer":"They will overheat quickly and possibly fail"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not be lower than:","options":["60 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"120 psi"},{"Question":"In Manitoba, who can perform brake adjustments on manual slack adjusters so the pushrod is less than the adjusted limit?","options":["A licensed driver with an A endorsement or a certified technician","A licensed driver with an S endorsement","The owner for the vehicle","A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"],"correctAnswer":"A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"},{"Question":"The engine must be running when testing the air-loss rate.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"As brakes heat up, you may experience a reduction in their effectiveness. This is known as:","options":["ABS brakes","Anti-lock braking","Brake fade","Combination braking"],"correctAnswer":"Brake fade"},{"Question":"Air brake chambers from different manufacturers may look different even if they are the same size.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Brake lining is defective when it is:","options":["Cracked","Missing","Loose","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the governor?","options":["The governor causes the compressor to start and stop pumping air (cut-in and cut-out)","The governor controls the amount of moisture the air dryer removes from the system","Once air flows through the supply tank, the governor prevents it from returning","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"The governor causes the compressor to start and stop pumping air (cut-in and cut-out)"},{"Question":"Inspecting a vehicle\u2019s air lines includes checking for the following defects:","options":["Audible air leak","Damaged or worn air lines","Improper fittings used to connect or repair air lines","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"When the pushrod stroke exceeds the adjustment limit of the brake chamber, the brake:","options":["Is out of adjustment","Is in adjustment","Needs to be replaced","Has a minor defect"],"correctAnswer":"Is out of adjustment"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel is within the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This:","options":["Is a minor defect","Is a major defect","Passes the inspection","Is a broken or defective part"],"correctAnswer":"Passes the inspection"},{"Question":"If air loss exceeds the maximum allowable limit specified for your vehicle, it would be considered a major defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"The air pressure must build from 85 psi to 100 psi in _______?","options":["30 seconds","One minute","Two minutes","Three minutes"],"correctAnswer":"Two minutes"},{"Question":"How often is it recommended that the air tanks be drained?","options":["At the beginning of every trip","At the end of every trip","Every day","Once a week"],"correctAnswer":"Every day"},{"Question":"When testing the air-loss rate of the brake system, the brake pedal must be fully applied.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"How would you know if the anti-lock braking system had a malfunction?","options":["The brakes won\'t function at all","The brakes will function intermittently","Only the trailer hand valve functions","The ABS malfunction warning light illuminates"],"correctAnswer":"The ABS malfunction warning light illuminates"},{"Question":"Failure of the spring brakes to hold the vehicle stationary indicates defective service brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What are the three different types of foundation brake systems?","options":["\'S\' cam brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes","ABS brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes","ABS brakes, \'S\' cam brakes, and wedge brakes","\'S\' cam brakes, ABS brakes, and disc brakes"],"correctAnswer":"\'S\' cam brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes"},{"Question":"The brake on each end of an axel should have a different sized air brake chamber to ensure brake forces are balanced.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Testing the performance of your brakes requires performing separate tests of each braking system.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Actual cut-in pressure of the governor should never be less than:","options":["55 psi","80 psi","100 psi","120 psi"],"correctAnswer":"100 psi"},{"Question":"Where are air brake chambers located?","options":["At each wheel","At the drive wheels only","At the trailer wheels only","At both the drive and trailer wheels"],"correctAnswer":"At each wheel"},{"Question":"If air exhausts from the service line, it means that the trailer supply valve is defective.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"A sudden increase in the amount of moisture or oil drained from any air-tank:","options":["Means the system is working correctly","Indicates the governor is faulty","Must be reported and repaired","Indicates an engine oil leak"],"correctAnswer":"Must be reported and repaired"},{"Question":"In Manitoba, who can perform brake adjustments on manual slack adjusters so the pushrod is less than the adjusted limit?","options":["A licensed driver with an A endorsement or a certified technician","A licensed driver with an S endorsement","The owner for the vehicle","A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"],"correctAnswer":"A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"},{"Question":"Why are automatic slack adjusters used?","options":["They make inspections and adjustments unnecessary","As a backup to a manual slack adjuster","To avoid the need to regularly perform manual re-adjustments","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To avoid the need to regularly perform manual re-adjustments"},{"Question":"When testing the compressor, if there is a trailer attached, the trailer supply valve must be closed.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What is a reliable method for inspecting your brake adjustment?","options":["Measuring the applied pushrod stroke","Checking the slack adjustment","Checking the condition of the brake drum","Measuring the brake chamber size"],"correctAnswer":"Measuring the applied pushrod stroke"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not be lower than:","options":["60 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"120 psi"},{"Question":"What can cause damage or deterioration to brake hoses and tubes?","options":["Wear and cuts","Wear, cuts, and heat damage","Wear, cuts, abrasions, and heat damage","Abrasions and heat damage"],"correctAnswer":"Wear, cuts, abrasions, and heat damage"},{"Question":"In what order should air tanks be drained?","options":["Wet, primary, secondary","Primary, secondary, wet","Primary, wet, secondary","All at the same time"],"correctAnswer":"Wet, primary, secondary"},{"Question":"At what pressure do the spring brakes normally start to apply because there is no longer enough pressure to keep them released?","options":["20 psi","40 psi","60 psi","85 psi"],"correctAnswer":"60 psi"},{"Question":"Wheels, dust shields, and other parts of the vehicle have no impact on your view of the brake drums and rotors.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"On a straight truck, tractor, or bus air loss test, what is the acceptable amount of air loss allowed within one minute?","options":["2 psi","3 psi","4 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"3 psi"},{"Question":"If air loss exceeds the maximum allowable limit specified for your vehicle, it would be considered a major defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"There is often a noticeable change in the behaviour of brakes with drums or rotors that are defective, cracked or broken.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"In order to make a service brake application?","options":["Pull the yellow button","Pull the red button","Push the brake pedal","Push the red and yellow buttons"],"correctAnswer":"Push the brake pedal"},{"Question":"Failure of the spring brakes to hold the vehicle stationary indicates defective service brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Older air systems may operate with lower pressure settings.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When conducting an inspection of the air brake system, be sure to:","options":["Park the vehicle on level ground","Park the vehicle away from traffic","Turn the engine off","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"The brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum is an example of:","options":["A foundation brake component defect","An issue with the brake chamber","An incorrectly measured pushrod","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"A foundation brake component defect"},{"Question":"When testing the air-loss rate of the brake system, the brake pedal must be fully applied.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Why would a brake chamber need to be \'caged\'?","options":["To move the vehicle in an emergency","To allow for proper braking","To measure your pushrod travel","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To move the vehicle in an emergency"},{"Question":"What happens when the trailer lines are not connected properly?","options":["Spring brakes may not release","The towing vehicle may lose air","Service brakes will not function properly","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Who is responsible for ensuring air brakes are correctly adjusted?","options":["The employer","The manufacturer","The last person driving the vehicle","The current driver"],"correctAnswer":"The current driver"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the safety valve?","options":["Starts building air pressure at 100 psi","Stops building air pressure at 140 psi","Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting","Ensures the trucks safety features are working correctly"],"correctAnswer":"Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting"},{"Question":"Inspecting the vehicle\u2019s air lines includes checking for the following defects:","options":["Audible air leak","Damage or worn air lines","Improper fittings used to connect or repair an air line","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Automatic slack adjusters, if working properly, require regular re-adjustment.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What is the size of an air brake chamber based on?","options":["The type of chamber","The area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches","The pushrod travel distance","The make and model of the vehicle"],"correctAnswer":"The area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches"},{"Question":"When testing the compressor, if there is a trailer attached, the trailer supply valve must be closed.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"As brakes heat up, you may experience a reduction in their effectiveness. This is known as:","options":["ABS brakes","Anti-lock braking","Brake fade","Combination braking"],"correctAnswer":"Brake fade"},{"Question":"When checking the air pressure buildup rate (compressor operation), what should the engine be idling between?","options":["200 - 500 rpm","500 - 800 rpm","600 - 900 rpm","900 - 1200 rpm"],"correctAnswer":"600 - 900 rpm"},{"Question":"Operating a vehicle with defects or failing to conduct the required inspections can result in:","options":["Charges against the driver and/or operator","Detainment or impoundment of the vehicle","Fines","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What should the air pressure be when performing a brake adjustment inspection at each wheel?","options":["Between 80 - 90 psi","Between 90 - 100 psi","Between 100 - 110 psi","At maximum pressure"],"correctAnswer":"Between 90 - 100 psi"},{"Question":"For the brakes to work, the brake-shoe lining must be greased and pressed against the brake drum when the brakes are applied.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Testing the performance of your brakes requires performing separate tests of each braking system.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"A sudden increase in the amount of moisture or oil drained from any air-tank:","options":["Means the system is working correctly","Indicates the governor is faulty","Must be reported and repaired","Indicates an engine oil leak"],"correctAnswer":"Must be reported and repaired"},{"Question":"Damaged or worn air lines are not a concern until they have an obvious leak.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"An inspection of a vehicle\u2019s brake drums and rotors includes checking for the following defect:","options":["Cracked or broken brake drums","Cracked or broken rotors","Both A and B","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Both A and B"},{"Question":"On a straight truck, tractor, or bus air loss test, what is the acceptable amount of air loss allowed within one minute?","options":["2 psi","3 psi","4 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"3 psi"},{"Question":"If the compressor takes longer than two minutes to build air from 85 psi to 100 psi, it would be considered a major defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle\u2019s air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel exceeds the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This is:","options":["A minor defect","A major defect","Within the acceptable adjustment limit","Something to keep track of"],"correctAnswer":"A major defect"},{"Question":"If you double your vehicle weight and double your speed, what does your stopping distance increase by?","options":["Four times","Six times","Eight times","Ten times"],"correctAnswer":"Eight times"},{"Question":"Why would a brake chamber need to be \'caged\'?","options":["To move the vehicle in an emergency","To allow for proper braking","To measure your pushrod travel","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To move the vehicle in an emergency"},{"Question":"The vehicle must be secured by the spring brakes or by wheel chocks before leaving the driver\u2019s seat or going under the vehicle.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"In what order should air tanks be drained?","options":["Wet, primary, secondary","Primary, secondary, wet","Primary, wet, secondary","All at the same time"],"correctAnswer":"Wet, primary, secondary"},{"Question":"When the pushrod stroke exceeds the adjustment limit of the brake chamber, the brake:","options":["Is out of adjustment","Is in adjustment","Needs to be replaced","Has a minor defect"],"correctAnswer":"Is out of adjustment"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the tractor protection valve?","options":["Prevents total air loss from the trailer if the trailer breaks away","Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away","Holds the supply line and emergency line in place not allowing them to break away","Prevents over pressure in the system allowing excess air to escape"],"correctAnswer":"Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away"},{"Question":"If air loss exceeds the maximum allowable limit specified for your vehicle, it would be considered a major defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the safety valve?","options":["Starts building air pressure at 100 psi","Stops building air pressure at 140 psi","Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting","Ensures the trucks safety features are working correctly"],"correctAnswer":"Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting"},{"Question":"What happens if a single brake malfunctions?","options":["It puts more pressure on the other brakes","It causes the other brakes to quickly overheat","It could cause the other brakes to fail","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"The first air tank that air enters is called the supply (wet tank).","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Wheels, dust shields, and other parts of the vehicle have no impact on your view of the brake drums and rotors.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"In order to make a service brake application?","options":["Pull the yellow button","Pull the red button","Push the brake pedal","Push the red and yellow buttons"],"correctAnswer":"Push the brake pedal"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the tractor protection valve?","options":["Prevents total air loss from the trailer if the trailer breaks away","Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away","Holds the supply line and emergency line in place not allowing them to break away","Prevents over pressure in the system allowing excess air to escape"],"correctAnswer":"Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away"},{"Question":"When grease or oil is present on the brake lining:","options":["The brake lining is properly lubricated","Abnormal brake behaviour will result","The brake lining has been over-lubricated","The driver can continue to drive the vehicle as it will not cause any issues with brake function"],"correctAnswer":"Abnormal brake behaviour will result"},{"Question":"What safety equipment is recommended while conducting an air brake inspection?","options":["Fire extinguisher, safety glasses, and  protective footwear","Safety glasses, protective headgear, and protective footwear","Protective headgear, ear plugs, and safety glasses","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Safety glasses, protective headgear, and protective footwear"},{"Question":"What is a reliable method for inspecting your brake adjustment?","options":["Measuring the applied pushrod stroke","Checking the slack adjustment","Checking the condition of the brake drum","Measuring the brake chamber size"],"correctAnswer":"Measuring the applied pushrod stroke"},{"Question":"The brake on each end of an axel should have a different sized air brake chamber to ensure brake forces are balanced.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When should the supply tank be drained?","options":["First","Last","In whatever order is most convenient for the driver","The supply tank should never be drained"],"correctAnswer":"First"},{"Question":"Spring brakes use air to apply the brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed in one minute on a tractor with two or more trailers?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","5 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"6 psi"},{"Question":"If the low air-pressure warning device activates below 55 psi, this would be considered a minor defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When checking the buildup rate (compressor operation) the engine should be building air pressure from _____ psi to ____ psi within two minutes:","options":["45 - 65","65 - 85","85 - 100","100 - 125"],"correctAnswer":"85 - 100"},{"Question":"Inspecting the vehicle\u2019s air lines includes checking for the following defects:","options":["Audible air leak","Damage or worn air lines","Improper fittings used to connect or repair an air line","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"An inspection of a vehicle\u2019s brake drums and rotors includes checking for the following defect:","options":["Cracked or broken brake drums","Cracked or broken rotors","Both A and B","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Both A and B"},{"Question":"When testing the air-loss rate of the brake system, the brake pedal must be fully applied.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Who is responsible for ensuring air brakes are correctly adjusted?","options":["The employer","The manufacturer","The last person driving the vehicle","The current driver"],"correctAnswer":"The current driver"},{"Question":"Failure of the spring brakes to hold the vehicle stationary indicates defective service brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What are the three different types of foundation brake systems?","options":["\'S\' cam brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes","ABS brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes","ABS brakes, \'S\' cam brakes, and wedge brakes","\'S\' cam brakes, ABS brakes, and disc brakes"],"correctAnswer":"\'S\' cam brakes, disc brakes, and wedge brakes"},{"Question":"In Manitoba, who can perform brake adjustments on manual slack adjusters so the pushrod is less than the adjusted limit?","options":["A licensed driver with an A endorsement or a certified technician","A licensed driver with an S endorsement","The owner for the vehicle","A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"],"correctAnswer":"A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the governor?","options":["The governor causes the compressor to start and stop pumping air (cut-in and cut-out)","The governor controls the amount of moisture the air dryer removes from the system","Once air flows through the supply tank, the governor prevents it from returning","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"The governor causes the compressor to start and stop pumping air (cut-in and cut-out)"},{"Question":"What should you do before you exit the vehicle or get underneath it?","options":["Start the vehicle","Secure the vehicle","Grab your safety equipment","Turn off the vehicle"],"correctAnswer":"Secure the vehicle"},{"Question":"Automatic slack adjusters, if working properly, require regular re-adjustment.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When checking the buildup rate (compressor operation) the engine should be building air pressure from _____ psi to ____ psi within two minutes:","options":["45 - 65","65 - 85","85 - 100","100 - 125"],"correctAnswer":"85 - 100"},{"Question":"When testing the compressor, if there is a trailer attached, the trailer supply valve must be closed.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What happens if a single brake malfunctions?","options":["It puts more pressure on the other brakes","It causes the other brakes to quickly overheat","It could cause the other brakes to fail","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What should you do before you exit the vehicle or get underneath it?","options":["Start the vehicle","Secure the vehicle","Grab your safety equipment","Turn off the vehicle"],"correctAnswer":"Secure the vehicle"},{"Question":"Inspecting a vehicle\u2019s air lines includes checking for the following defects:","options":["Audible air leak","Damaged or worn air lines","Improper fittings used to connect or repair air lines","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Inspecting the air compressor includes checking for which defects?","options":["Loose air compressor drive belt pulley","Loose, cut or frayed air compressor drive belt","Insecure air compressor mounting, bracket or fasteners","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"When testing the tractor protection system, the trailer supply valve must close before the pressure drops below:","options":["20 psi","55 psi","60 psi","100 psi"],"correctAnswer":"20 psi"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the tractor protection valve?","options":["Prevents total air loss from the trailer if the trailer breaks away","Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away","Holds the supply line and emergency line in place not allowing them to break away","Prevents over pressure in the system allowing excess air to escape"],"correctAnswer":"Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away"},{"Question":"If the compressor takes longer than two minutes to build air from 85 psi to 100 psi, it would be considered a major defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"The vehicle must be secured by the spring brakes or by wheel chocks before leaving the driver\u2019s seat or going under the vehicle.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"In what order should air tanks be drained?","options":["Wet, primary, secondary","Primary, secondary, wet","Primary, wet, secondary","All at the same time"],"correctAnswer":"Wet, primary, secondary"},{"Question":"When grease or oil is present on the brake lining:","options":["The brake lining is properly lubricated","Abnormal brake behaviour will result","The brake lining has been over-lubricated","The driver can continue to drive the vehicle as it will not cause any issues with brake function"],"correctAnswer":"Abnormal brake behaviour will result"},{"Question":"What does ABS stand for?","options":["Automatic Brake Stop","Automatic Braking System","Anti-lock Brake System","Accelerated Braking System"],"correctAnswer":"Anti-lock Brake System"},{"Question":"In Manitoba, who can perform brake adjustments on manual slack adjusters so the pushrod is less than the adjusted limit?","options":["A licensed driver with an A endorsement or a certified technician","A licensed driver with an S endorsement","The owner for the vehicle","A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"],"correctAnswer":"A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"},{"Question":"In order to make a service brake application?","options":["Pull the yellow button","Pull the red button","Push the brake pedal","Push the red and yellow buttons"],"correctAnswer":"Push the brake pedal"},{"Question":"If the governor fails to signal the compressor to cut-out what allows the excess air pressure to escape?","options":["The air dryer","A one way check valve","The low pressure warning system","A safety valve"],"correctAnswer":"A safety valve"},{"Question":"If any single brake malfunctions, what affect will it have on the other brakes?","options":["None","The malfunctioning brake will overheat causing damage","They will overheat quickly and possibly fail","The braking power will be slightly reduced"],"correctAnswer":"They will overheat quickly and possibly fail"},{"Question":"The air pressure must build from 85 psi to 100 psi in _______?","options":["30 seconds","One minute","Two minutes","Three minutes"],"correctAnswer":"Two minutes"},{"Question":"A sudden increase in the amount of moisture or oil drained from any air-tank:","options":["Means the system is working correctly","Indicates the governor is faulty","Must be reported and repaired","Indicates an engine oil leak"],"correctAnswer":"Must be reported and repaired"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the safety valve?","options":["Starts building air pressure at 100 psi","Stops building air pressure at 140 psi","Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting","Ensures the trucks safety features are working correctly"],"correctAnswer":"Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting"},{"Question":"Your spring brakes should be used when parking or in an emergency when your service brakes fail?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What should you do before you exit the vehicle or get underneath it?","options":["Start the vehicle","Secure the vehicle","Grab your safety equipment","Turn off the vehicle"],"correctAnswer":"Secure the vehicle"},{"Question":"Why are automatic slack adjusters used?","options":["They make inspections and adjustments unnecessary","As a backup to a manual slack adjuster","To avoid the need to regularly perform manual re-adjustments","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To avoid the need to regularly perform manual re-adjustments"},{"Question":"In order to make a service brake application?","options":["Pull the yellow button","Pull the red button","Push the brake pedal","Push the red and yellow buttons"],"correctAnswer":"Push the brake pedal"},{"Question":"A spring brake control valve is usually yellow?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Brake lining is defective when it is:","options":["Cracked","Missing","Loose","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"When conducting an inspection of the air brake system, be sure to:","options":["Park the vehicle on level ground","Park the vehicle away from traffic","Turn the engine off","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What should the air pressure be when performing a brake adjustment inspection at each wheel?","options":["Between 80 - 90 psi","Between 90 - 100 psi","Between 100 - 110 psi","At maximum pressure"],"correctAnswer":"Between 90 - 100 psi"},{"Question":"Why would a brake chamber need to be \'caged\'?","options":["To move the vehicle in an emergency","To allow for proper braking","To measure your pushrod travel","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"To move the vehicle in an emergency"},{"Question":"Inspecting the brake components includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum","Damaged, missing or malfunctioning foundation brake components","Cracked, loose, missing or contaminated brake lining, improper drum contact or lining thickness that is less than required","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"In Manitoba, who can perform brake adjustments on manual slack adjusters so the pushrod is less than the adjusted limit?","options":["A licensed driver with an A endorsement or a certified technician","A licensed driver with an S endorsement","The owner for the vehicle","A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"],"correctAnswer":"A licensed driver with an S endorsement or a certified technician"},{"Question":"Vehicles with air brakes must comply with The Highway Traffic Act and Regulations. If a vehicle does not comply, both the driver and the operator may be charged.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What controls an air brake system\u2019s pressure range (cut-in and cut-out settings)?","options":["The governor","The compressor","The engine","The turbo-charger"],"correctAnswer":"The governor"},{"Question":"When the brakes are applied, a brake malfunction is indicated by the brake lining not contacting the drum.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle\u2019s air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel exceeds the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This is:","options":["A minor defect","A major defect","Within the acceptable adjustment limit","Something to keep track of"],"correctAnswer":"A major defect"},{"Question":"The brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum is an example of:","options":["A foundation brake component defect","An issue with the brake chamber","An incorrectly measured pushrod","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"A foundation brake component defect"},{"Question":"When testing brake performance (tug tests), it would be considered a major defect if:","options":["The spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle in place","The service brakes fail to stop the vehicle","Only if the tractor spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle","Both A and B"],"correctAnswer":"Both A and B"},{"Question":"How would you know if the anti-lock braking system had a malfunction?","options":["The brakes won\'t function at all","The brakes will function intermittently","Only the trailer hand valve functions","The ABS malfunction warning light illuminates"],"correctAnswer":"The ABS malfunction warning light illuminates"},{"Question":"What happens if a single brake malfunctions?","options":["It puts more pressure on the other brakes","It causes the other brakes to quickly overheat","It could cause the other brakes to fail","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the tractor protection valve?","options":["Prevents total air loss from the trailer if the trailer breaks away","Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away","Holds the supply line and emergency line in place not allowing them to break away","Prevents over pressure in the system allowing excess air to escape"],"correctAnswer":"Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away"},{"Question":"Operating a vehicle with defects or failing to conduct the required inspections can result in:","options":["Charges against the driver and/or operator","Detainment or impoundment of the vehicle","Fines","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Inspecting the vehicle\u2019s air lines includes checking for the following defects:","options":["Audible air leak","Damage or worn air lines","Improper fittings used to connect or repair an air line","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"A sudden increase in the amount of moisture or oil drained from any air-tank:","options":["Means the system is working correctly","Indicates the governor is faulty","Must be reported and repaired","Indicates an engine oil leak"],"correctAnswer":"Must be reported and repaired"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the safety valve?","options":["Starts building air pressure at 100 psi","Stops building air pressure at 140 psi","Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting","Ensures the trucks safety features are working correctly"],"correctAnswer":"Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting"},{"Question":"Inspecting a vehicle\u2019s air brake chambers includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Audible air leaks","Cracks and non-manufactured holes","Brakes with different air brake chamber sizes on each end of a steering axle","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"When testing the tractor protection system, the trailer supply valve must close before the pressure drops below:","options":["20 psi","55 psi","60 psi","100 psi"],"correctAnswer":"20 psi"},{"Question":"Air brake chambers from different manufacturers may look different even if they are the same size.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"If the low air-pressure warning device activates below 55 psi, this would be considered a minor defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Wheels, dust shields, and other parts of the vehicle have no impact on your view of the brake drums and rotors.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Brake lining is defective when it is:","options":["Cracked","Missing","Loose","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed in one minute on a tractor with two or more trailers?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","5 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"6 psi"},{"Question":"When the brakes are applied, a brake malfunction is indicated by the brake lining not contacting the drum.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"If the compressor takes longer than two minutes to build air from 85 psi to 100 psi, it would be considered a major defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"Air compressors can be inspected with the engine running or stopped.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the tractor protection valve?","options":["Prevents total air loss from the trailer if the trailer breaks away","Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away","Holds the supply line and emergency line in place not allowing them to break away","Prevents over pressure in the system allowing excess air to escape"],"correctAnswer":"Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away"},{"Question":"Damaged or worn air lines are not a concern until they have an obvious leak.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When testing brake performance (tug tests), it would be considered a major defect if:","options":["The spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle in place","The service brakes fail to stop the vehicle","Only if the tractor spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle","Both A and B"],"correctAnswer":"Both A and B"},{"Question":"The brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum is an example of:","options":["A foundation brake component defect","An issue with the brake chamber","An incorrectly measured pushrod","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"A foundation brake component defect"},{"Question":"Inspecting the brake components includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum","Damaged, missing or malfunctioning foundation brake components","Cracked, loose, missing or contaminated brake lining, improper drum contact or lining thickness that is less than required","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"How would you know if the anti-lock braking system had a malfunction?","options":["The brakes won\'t function at all","The brakes will function intermittently","Only the trailer hand valve functions","The ABS malfunction warning light illuminates"],"correctAnswer":"The ABS malfunction warning light illuminates"},{"Question":"How can air brake chamber air leaks usually be detected?","options":["Visually","Audibly","By checking pushrod travel distance","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Audibly"},{"Question":"The brake on each end of an axel should have a different sized air brake chamber to ensure brake forces are balanced.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"The Highway Traffic Act and Regulations prohibit the operation of a vehicle with a brake that is out of adjustment.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When testing the compressor, if there is a trailer attached, the trailer supply valve must be closed.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What happens when the trailer lines are not connected properly?","options":["Spring brakes may not release","The towing vehicle may lose air","Service brakes will not function properly","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What controls an air brake system\u2019s pressure range (cut-in and cut-out settings)?","options":["The governor","The compressor","The engine","The turbo-charger"],"correctAnswer":"The governor"},{"Question":"The size of an air brake chamber is based on the area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When testing the air-loss rate of the brake system, the brake pedal must be fully applied.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What is the size of an air brake chamber based on?","options":["The type of chamber","The area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches","The pushrod travel distance","The make and model of the vehicle"],"correctAnswer":"The area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches"},{"Question":"How often is it recommended that the air tanks be drained?","options":["At the beginning of every trip","At the end of every trip","Every day","Once a week"],"correctAnswer":"Every day"},{"Question":"What happens if a single brake malfunctions?","options":["It puts more pressure on the other brakes","It causes the other brakes to quickly overheat","It could cause the other brakes to fail","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Damaged or worn air lines are not a concern until they have an obvious leak.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"What safety equipment is recommended while conducting an air brake inspection?","options":["Fire extinguisher, safety glasses, and  protective footwear","Safety glasses, protective headgear, and protective footwear","Protective headgear, ear plugs, and safety glasses","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Safety glasses, protective headgear, and protective footwear"},{"Question":"When damage extends into the reinforcing or inner layer, the air line is defective.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"If you double your vehicle weight and double your speed, what does your stopping distance increase by?","options":["Four times","Six times","Eight times","Ten times"],"correctAnswer":"Eight times"},{"Question":"What should you do before you exit the vehicle or get underneath it?","options":["Start the vehicle","Secure the vehicle","Grab your safety equipment","Turn off the vehicle"],"correctAnswer":"Secure the vehicle"},{"Question":"When inspecting foundation brake components, the driver is expected to be able to identify brake components that are damaged, missing or malfunctioning.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What do anti-lock braking systems (ABS) do?","options":["Help maintain steering control during emergency braking","Help prevent wheel lock","Do not shorten the stopping distance","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"When checking the air pressure buildup rate (compressor operation), what should the engine be idling between?","options":["200 - 500 rpm","500 - 800 rpm","600 - 900 rpm","900 - 1200 rpm"],"correctAnswer":"600 - 900 rpm"},{"Question":"If any single brake malfunctions, what affect will it have on the other brakes?","options":["None","The malfunctioning brake will overheat causing damage","They will overheat quickly and possibly fail","The braking power will be slightly reduced"],"correctAnswer":"They will overheat quickly and possibly fail"},{"Question":"Wheels, dust shields, and other parts of the vehicle have no impact on your view of the brake drums and rotors.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When testing the tractor protection system, the trailer supply valve must close before the pressure drops below:","options":["20 psi","55 psi","60 psi","100 psi"],"correctAnswer":"20 psi"},{"Question":"What should the air pressure be when performing a brake adjustment inspection at each wheel?","options":["Between 80 - 90 psi","Between 90 - 100 psi","Between 100 - 110 psi","At maximum pressure"],"correctAnswer":"Between 90 - 100 psi"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the tractor protection valve?","options":["Prevents total air loss from the trailer if the trailer breaks away","Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away","Holds the supply line and emergency line in place not allowing them to break away","Prevents over pressure in the system allowing excess air to escape"],"correctAnswer":"Prevents total air loss from the tractor if the trailer breaks away"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not be lower than:","options":["60 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"120 psi"},{"Question":"Spring brakes use air to apply the brakes.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When grease or oil is present on the brake lining:","options":["The brake lining is properly lubricated","Abnormal brake behaviour will result","The brake lining has been over-lubricated","The driver can continue to drive the vehicle as it will not cause any issues with brake function"],"correctAnswer":"Abnormal brake behaviour will result"},{"Question":"As brakes heat up, you may experience a reduction in their effectiveness. This is known as:","options":["ABS brakes","Anti-lock braking","Brake fade","Combination braking"],"correctAnswer":"Brake fade"},{"Question":"The vehicle must be secured by the spring brakes or by wheel chocks before leaving the driver\u2019s seat or going under the vehicle.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When testing brake performance (tug tests), it would be considered a major defect if:","options":["The spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle in place","The service brakes fail to stop the vehicle","Only if the tractor spring brakes fail to hold the vehicle","Both A and B"],"correctAnswer":"Both A and B"},{"Question":"The governor\u2019s cut-out pressure must not exceed:","options":["90 psi","120 psi","145 psi","150 psi"],"correctAnswer":"145 psi"},{"Question":"At what pressure do the spring brakes normally start to apply because there is no longer enough pressure to keep them released?","options":["20 psi","40 psi","60 psi","85 psi"],"correctAnswer":"60 psi"},{"Question":"On a straight truck, tractor, or bus air loss test, what is the acceptable amount of air loss allowed within one minute?","options":["2 psi","3 psi","4 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"3 psi"},{"Question":"What does ABS stand for?","options":["Automatic Brake Stop","Automatic Braking System","Anti-lock Brake System","Accelerated Braking System"],"correctAnswer":"Anti-lock Brake System"},{"Question":"Your spring brakes should be used when parking or in an emergency when your service brakes fail?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Brake lining is defective when it is:","options":["Cracked","Missing","Loose","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"At what level must the low pressure warning device activate?","options":["At or above 60 psi","Between 40 - 50 psi","At or above 85 psi","At or above 55 psi"],"correctAnswer":"At or above 55 psi"},{"Question":"When testing the low air-pressure warning device, the engine can be stopped or running but the ignition must be on.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Air brake chambers from different manufacturers may look different even if they are the same size.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"The brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum is an example of:","options":["A foundation brake component defect","An issue with the brake chamber","An incorrectly measured pushrod","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"A foundation brake component defect"},{"Question":"Damaged or worn air lines are not a concern until they have an obvious leak.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"A sudden increase in the amount of moisture or oil drained from any air-tank:","options":["Means the system is working correctly","Indicates the governor is faulty","Must be reported and repaired","Indicates an engine oil leak"],"correctAnswer":"Must be reported and repaired"},{"Question":"If the compressor takes longer than two minutes to build air from 85 psi to 100 psi, it would be considered a major defect.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"When checking the buildup rate (compressor operation) the engine should be building air pressure from _____ psi to ____ psi within two minutes:","options":["45 - 65","65 - 85","85 - 100","100 - 125"],"correctAnswer":"85 - 100"},{"Question":"In order to make a service brake application?","options":["Pull the yellow button","Pull the red button","Push the brake pedal","Push the red and yellow buttons"],"correctAnswer":"Push the brake pedal"},{"Question":"When testing the compressor, if there is a trailer attached, the trailer supply valve must be closed.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Brake lining is defective when it is:","options":["Cracked","Missing","Loose","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Inspecting the vehicle\u2019s air lines includes checking for the following defects:","options":["Audible air leak","Damage or worn air lines","Improper fittings used to connect or repair an air line","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"Inspecting the brake components includes checking for which of these defects?","options":["Brake-shoe lining not contacting the brake drum","Damaged, missing or malfunctioning foundation brake components","Cracked, loose, missing or contaminated brake lining, improper drum contact or lining thickness that is less than required","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"When conducting an inspection of the air brake system, be sure to:","options":["Park the vehicle on level ground","Park the vehicle away from traffic","Turn the engine off","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"The vehicle must be secured by the spring brakes or by wheel chocks before leaving the driver\u2019s seat or going under the vehicle.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Testing the performance of your brakes requires performing separate tests of each braking system.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When testing the air-loss rate of the brake system, the brake pedal must be fully applied.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When grease or oil is present on the brake lining:","options":["The brake lining is properly lubricated","Abnormal brake behaviour will result","The brake lining has been over-lubricated","The driver can continue to drive the vehicle as it will not cause any issues with brake function"],"correctAnswer":"Abnormal brake behaviour will result"},{"Question":"How can air brake chamber air leaks usually be detected?","options":["Visually","Audibly","By checking pushrod travel distance","None of the above"],"correctAnswer":"Audibly"},{"Question":"When inspecting foundation brake components, the driver is expected to be able to identify brake components that are damaged, missing or malfunctioning.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel is within the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This:","options":["Is a minor defect","Is a major defect","Passes the inspection","Is a broken or defective part"],"correctAnswer":"Passes the inspection"},{"Question":"What can cause damage to the foundation brake components?","options":["Debris","Component failure","Deterioration","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"To ensure balanced braking, slack adjusters on each side of an axel should:","options":["Be the same effective lengths","Have no more than 1 inch difference","Be attached using different holes","Both B and C"],"correctAnswer":"Be the same effective lengths"},{"Question":"What should the air pressure be when performing a brake adjustment inspection at each wheel?","options":["Between 80 - 90 psi","Between 90 - 100 psi","Between 100 - 110 psi","At maximum pressure"],"correctAnswer":"Between 90 - 100 psi"},{"Question":"The size of an air brake chamber is based on the area of the chamber diaphragm in square inches.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Operating a vehicle with defects or failing to conduct the required inspections can result in:","options":["Charges against the driver and/or operator","Detainment or impoundment of the vehicle","Fines","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":"All of the above"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed when testing the air-loss rate of the brake system on a tractor and trailer?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","6 psi","10 psi"],"correctAnswer":"4 psi"},{"Question":"Damaged or worn air lines are not a concern until they have an obvious leak.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"How often is it recommended that the air tanks be drained?","options":["At the beginning of every trip","At the end of every trip","Every day","Once a week"],"correctAnswer":"Every day"},{"Question":"When checking the air pressure buildup rate (compressor operation), what should the engine be idling between?","options":["200 - 500 rpm","500 - 800 rpm","600 - 900 rpm","900 - 1200 rpm"],"correctAnswer":"600 - 900 rpm"},{"Question":"What is the purpose of the safety valve?","options":["Starts building air pressure at 100 psi","Stops building air pressure at 140 psi","Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting","Ensures the trucks safety features are working correctly"],"correctAnswer":"Protects the supply reservoir from becoming over-pressurized and bursting"},{"Question":"Your spring brakes should be used when parking or in an emergency when your service brakes fail?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Air brake chambers from different manufacturers may look different even if they are the same size.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"Vehicles with air brakes must comply with The Highway Traffic Act and Regulations. If a vehicle does not comply, both the driver and the operator may be charged.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"When inspecting your vehicle air brake adjustment, the pushrod travel is within the allowable limit for the size and type of brake chamber. This:","options":["Is a minor defect","Is a major defect","Passes the inspection","Is a broken or defective part"],"correctAnswer":"Passes the inspection"},{"Question":"On a straight truck, tractor, or bus air loss test, what is the acceptable amount of air loss allowed within one minute?","options":["2 psi","3 psi","4 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"3 psi"},{"Question":"The Highway Traffic Act and Regulations prohibit the operation of a vehicle with a brake that is out of adjustment.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"If air exhausts from the service line, it means that the trailer supply valve is defective.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"To ensure balanced braking, slack adjusters on each side of an axel should:","options":["Be the same effective lengths","Have no more than 1 inch difference","Be attached using different holes","Both B and C"],"correctAnswer":"Be the same effective lengths"},{"Question":"The engine must be running when testing the air-loss rate.","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"False"},{"Question":"A spring brake control valve is usually yellow?","options":["True","False"],"correctAnswer":"True"},{"Question":"What is the maximum air loss allowed in one minute on a tractor with two or more trailers?","options":["3 psi","4 psi","5 psi","6 psi"],"correctAnswer":"6 psi"},{"Question":"If you double your vehicle weight and double your speed, what does your stopping distance increase by?","options":["Four times","Six times","Eight times","Ten times"],"correctAnswer":"Eight times"},{"Question":"Where are air brake chambers located?","options":["At each wheel","At the drive wheels only","At the trailer wheels only","At both the drive and trailer wheels"],"correctAnswer":"At each wheel"}]')},zUnb:function(e,t,r){"use strict";function o(e){return"function"==typeof e}r.r(t);let s=!1;const n={Promise:void 0,set useDeprecatedSynchronousErrorHandling(e){if(e){const e=new Error;console.warn("DEPRECATED! RxJS was set to use deprecated synchronous error handling behavior by code at: \n"+e.stack)}else s&&console.log("RxJS: Back to a better error behavior. Thank you. <3");s=e},get useDeprecatedSynchronousErrorHandling(){return s}};function i(e){setTimeout(()=>{throw e},0)}const a={closed:!0,next(e){},error(e){if(n.useDeprecatedSynchronousErrorHandling)throw e;i(e)},complete(){}},c=(()=>Array.isArray||(e=>e&&"number"==typeof e.length))();function l(e){return null!==e&&"object"==typeof e}const h=(()=>{function e(e){return Error.call(this),this.message=e?`${e.length} errors occurred during unsubscription:\n${e.map((e,t)=>`${t+1}) ${e.toString()}`).join("\n  ")}`:"",this.name="UnsubscriptionError",this.errors=e,this}return e.prototype=Object.create(Error.prototype),e})();let u=(()=>{class e{constructor(e){this.closed=!1,this._parentOrParents=null,this._subscriptions=null,e&&(this._unsubscribe=e)}unsubscribe(){let t;if(this.closed)return;let{_parentOrParents:r,_unsubscribe:s,_subscriptions:n}=this;if(this.closed=!0,this._parentOrParents=null,this._subscriptions=null,r instanceof e)r.remove(this);else if(null!==r)for(let e=0;e<r.length;++e)r[e].remove(this);if(o(s))try{s.call(this)}catch(i){t=i instanceof h?d(i.errors):[i]}if(c(n)){let e=-1,r=n.length;for(;++e<r;){const r=n[e];if(l(r))try{r.unsubscribe()}catch(i){t=t||[],i instanceof h?t=t.concat(d(i.errors)):t.push(i)}}}if(t)throw new h(t)}add(t){let r=t;if(!t)return e.EMPTY;switch(typeof t){case"function":r=new e(t);case"object":if(r===this||r.closed||"function"!=typeof r.unsubscribe)return r;if(this.closed)return r.unsubscribe(),r;if(!(r instanceof e)){const t=r;r=new e,r._subscriptions=[t]}break;default:throw new Error("unrecognized teardown "+t+" added to Subscription.")}let{_parentOrParents:o}=r;if(null===o)r._parentOrParents=this;else if(o instanceof e){if(o===this)return r;r._parentOrParents=[o,this]}else{if(-1!==o.indexOf(this))return r;o.push(this)}const s=this._subscriptions;return null===s?this._subscriptions=[r]:s.push(r),r}remove(e){const t=this._subscriptions;if(t){const r=t.indexOf(e);-1!==r&&t.splice(r,1)}}}return e.EMPTY=function(e){return e.closed=!0,e}(new e),e})();function d(e){return e.reduce((e,t)=>e.concat(t instanceof h?t.errors:t),[])}const p=(()=>"function"==typeof Symbol?Symbol("rxSubscriber"):"@@rxSubscriber_"+Math.random())();class m extends u{constructor(e,t,r){switch(super(),this.syncErrorValue=null,this.syncErrorThrown=!1,this.syncErrorThrowable=!1,this.isStopped=!1,arguments.length){case 0:this.destination=a;break;case 1:if(!e){this.destination=a;break}if("object"==typeof e){e instanceof m?(this.syncErrorThrowable=e.syncErrorThrowable,this.destination=e,e.add(this)):(this.syncErrorThrowable=!0,this.destination=new f(this,e));break}default:this.syncErrorThrowable=!0,this.destination=new f(this,e,t,r)}}[p](){return this}static create(e,t,r){const o=new m(e,t,r);return o.syncErrorThrowable=!1,o}next(e){this.isStopped||this._next(e)}error(e){this.isStopped||(this.isStopped=!0,this._error(e))}complete(){this.isStopped||(this.isStopped=!0,this._complete())}unsubscribe(){this.closed||(this.isStopped=!0,super.unsubscribe())}_next(e){this.destination.next(e)}_error(e){this.destination.error(e),this.unsubscribe()}_complete(){this.destination.complete(),this.unsubscribe()}_unsubscribeAndRecycle(){const{_parentOrParents:e}=this;return this._parentOrParents=null,this.unsubscribe(),this.closed=!1,this.isStopped=!1,this._parentOrParents=e,this}}class f extends m{constructor(e,t,r,s){let n;super(),this._parentSubscriber=e;let i=this;o(t)?n=t:t&&(n=t.next,r=t.error,s=t.complete,t!==a&&(i=Object.create(t),o(i.unsubscribe)&&this.add(i.unsubscribe.bind(i)),i.unsubscribe=this.unsubscribe.bind(this))),this._context=i,this._next=n,this._error=r,this._complete=s}next(e){if(!this.isStopped&&this._next){const{_parentSubscriber:t}=this;n.useDeprecatedSynchronousErrorHandling&&t.syncErrorThrowable?this.__tryOrSetError(t,this._next,e)&&this.unsubscribe():this.__tryOrUnsub(this._next,e)}}error(e){if(!this.isStopped){const{_parentSubscriber:t}=this,{useDeprecatedSynchronousErrorHandling:r}=n;if(this._error)r&&t.syncErrorThrowable?(this.__tryOrSetError(t,this._error,e),this.unsubscribe()):(this.__tryOrUnsub(this._error,e),this.unsubscribe());else if(t.syncErrorThrowable)r?(t.syncErrorValue=e,t.syncErrorThrown=!0):i(e),this.unsubscribe();else{if(this.unsubscribe(),r)throw e;i(e)}}}complete(){if(!this.isStopped){const{_parentSubscriber:e}=this;if(this._complete){const t=()=>this._complete.call(this._context);n.useDeprecatedSynchronousErrorHandling&&e.syncErrorThrowable?(this.__tryOrSetError(e,t),this.unsubscribe()):(this.__tryOrUnsub(t),this.unsubscribe())}else this.unsubscribe()}}__tryOrUnsub(e,t){try{e.call(this._context,t)}catch(r){if(this.unsubscribe(),n.useDeprecatedSynchronousErrorHandling)throw r;i(r)}}__tryOrSetError(e,t,r){if(!n.useDeprecatedSynchronousErrorHandling)throw new Error("bad call");try{t.call(this._context,r)}catch(o){return n.useDeprecatedSynchronousErrorHandling?(e.syncErrorValue=o,e.syncErrorThrown=!0,!0):(i(o),!0)}return!1}_unsubscribe(){const{_parentSubscriber:e}=this;this._context=null,this._parentSubscriber=null,e.unsubscribe()}}const b=(()=>"function"==typeof Symbol&&Symbol.observable||"@@observable")();function w(e){return e}let g=(()=>{class e{constructor(e){this._isScalar=!1,e&&(this._subscribe=e)}lift(t){const r=new e;return r.source=this,r.operator=t,r}subscribe(e,t,r){const{operator:o}=this,s=function(e,t,r){if(e){if(e instanceof m)return e;if(e[p])return e[p]()}return e||t||r?new m(e,t,r):new m(a)}(e,t,r);if(s.add(o?o.call(s,this.source):this.source||n.useDeprecatedSynchronousErrorHandling&&!s.syncErrorThrowable?this._subscribe(s):this._trySubscribe(s)),n.useDeprecatedSynchronousErrorHandling&&s.syncErrorThrowable&&(s.syncErrorThrowable=!1,s.syncErrorThrown))throw s.syncErrorValue;return s}_trySubscribe(e){try{return this._subscribe(e)}catch(t){n.useDeprecatedSynchronousErrorHandling&&(e.syncErrorThrown=!0,e.syncErrorValue=t),function(e){for(;e;){const{closed:t,destination:r,isStopped:o}=e;if(t||o)return!1;e=r&&r instanceof m?r:null}return!0}(e)?e.error(t):console.warn(t)}}forEach(e,t){return new(t=k(t))((t,r)=>{let o;o=this.subscribe(t=>{try{e(t)}catch(s){r(s),o&&o.unsubscribe()}},r,t)})}_subscribe(e){const{source:t}=this;return t&&t.subscribe(e)}[b](){return this}pipe(...e){return 0===e.length?this:(0===(t=e).length?w:1===t.length?t[0]:function(e){return t.reduce((e,t)=>t(e),e)})(this);var t}toPromise(e){return new(e=k(e))((e,t)=>{let r;this.subscribe(e=>r=e,e=>t(e),()=>e(r))})}}return e.create=t=>new e(t),e})();function k(e){if(e||(e=n.Promise||Promise),!e)throw new Error("no Promise impl found");return e}const v=(()=>{function e(){return Error.call(this),this.message="object unsubscribed",this.name="ObjectUnsubscribedError",this}return e.prototype=Object.create(Error.prototype),e})();class A extends u{constructor(e,t){super(),this.subject=e,this.subscriber=t,this.closed=!1}unsubscribe(){if(this.closed)return;this.closed=!0;const e=this.subject,t=e.observers;if(this.subject=null,!t||0===t.length||e.isStopped||e.closed)return;const r=t.indexOf(this.subscriber);-1!==r&&t.splice(r,1)}}class y extends m{constructor(e){super(e),this.destination=e}}let T=(()=>{class e extends g{constructor(){super(),this.observers=[],this.closed=!1,this.isStopped=!1,this.hasError=!1,this.thrownError=null}[p](){return new y(this)}lift(e){const t=new Q(this,this);return t.operator=e,t}next(e){if(this.closed)throw new v;if(!this.isStopped){const{observers:t}=this,r=t.length,o=t.slice();for(let s=0;s<r;s++)o[s].next(e)}}error(e){if(this.closed)throw new v;this.hasError=!0,this.thrownError=e,this.isStopped=!0;const{observers:t}=this,r=t.length,o=t.slice();for(let s=0;s<r;s++)o[s].error(e);this.observers.length=0}complete(){if(this.closed)throw new v;this.isStopped=!0;const{observers:e}=this,t=e.length,r=e.slice();for(let o=0;o<t;o++)r[o].complete();this.observers.length=0}unsubscribe(){this.isStopped=!0,this.closed=!0,this.observers=null}_trySubscribe(e){if(this.closed)throw new v;return super._trySubscribe(e)}_subscribe(e){if(this.closed)throw new v;return this.hasError?(e.error(this.thrownError),u.EMPTY):this.isStopped?(e.complete(),u.EMPTY):(this.observers.push(e),new A(this,e))}asObservable(){const e=new g;return e.source=this,e}}return e.create=(e,t)=>new Q(e,t),e})();class Q extends T{constructor(e,t){super(),this.destination=e,this.source=t}next(e){const{destination:t}=this;t&&t.next&&t.next(e)}error(e){const{destination:t}=this;t&&t.error&&this.destination.error(e)}complete(){const{destination:e}=this;e&&e.complete&&this.destination.complete()}_subscribe(e){const{source:t}=this;return t?this.source.subscribe(e):u.EMPTY}}class _ extends m{constructor(e,t,r){super(),this.parent=e,this.outerValue=t,this.outerIndex=r,this.index=0}_next(e){this.parent.notifyNext(this.outerValue,e,this.outerIndex,this.index++,this)}_error(e){this.parent.notifyError(e,this),this.unsubscribe()}_complete(){this.parent.notifyComplete(this),this.unsubscribe()}}const F=e=>t=>{for(let r=0,o=e.length;r<o&&!t.closed;r++)t.next(e[r]);t.complete()};function W(){return"function"==typeof Symbol&&Symbol.iterator?Symbol.iterator:"@@iterator"}const S=W();const I=e=>{if(e&&"function"==typeof e[b])return n=e,e=>{const t=n[b]();if("function"!=typeof t.subscribe)throw new TypeError("Provided object does not correctly implement Symbol.observable");return t.subscribe(e)};if((t=e)&&"number"==typeof t.length&&"function"!=typeof t)return F(e);var t,r,o,s,n;if((r=e)&&"function"!=typeof r.subscribe&&"function"==typeof r.then)return s=e,e=>(s.then(t=>{e.closed||(e.next(t),e.complete())},t=>e.error(t)).then(null,i),e);if(e&&"function"==typeof e[S])return o=e,e=>{const t=o[S]();for(;;){const r=t.next();if(r.done){e.complete();break}if(e.next(r.value),e.closed)break}return"function"==typeof t.return&&e.add(()=>{t.return&&t.return()}),e};{const t=l(e)?"an invalid object":`'${e}'`;throw new TypeError(`You provided ${t} where a stream was expected. You can provide an Observable, Promise, Array, or Iterable.`)}};class x extends m{notifyNext(e,t,r,o,s){this.destination.next(t)}notifyError(e,t){this.destination.error(e)}notifyComplete(e){this.destination.complete()}}class B{constructor(e,t){this.project=e,this.thisArg=t}call(e,t){return t.subscribe(new j(e,this.project,this.thisArg))}}class j extends m{constructor(e,t,r){super(e),this.project=t,this.count=0,this.thisArg=r||this}_next(e){let t;try{t=this.project.call(this.thisArg,e,this.count++)}catch(r){return void this.destination.error(r)}this.destination.next(t)}}class C{constructor(e,t=Number.POSITIVE_INFINITY){this.project=e,this.concurrent=t}call(e,t){return t.subscribe(new P(e,this.project,this.concurrent))}}class P extends x{constructor(e,t,r=Number.POSITIVE_INFINITY){super(e),this.project=t,this.concurrent=r,this.hasCompleted=!1,this.buffer=[],this.active=0,this.index=0}_next(e){this.active<this.concurrent?this._tryNext(e):this.buffer.push(e)}_tryNext(e){let t;const r=this.index++;try{t=this.project(e,r)}catch(o){return void this.destination.error(o)}this.active++,this._innerSub(t,e,r)}_innerSub(e,t,r){const o=new _(this,t,r),s=this.destination;s.add(o);const n=function(e,t,r,o,s=new _(e,r,o)){if(!s.closed)return t instanceof g?t.subscribe(s):I(t)(s)}(this,e,void 0,void 0,o);n!==o&&s.add(n)}_complete(){this.hasCompleted=!0,0===this.active&&0===this.buffer.length&&this.destination.complete(),this.unsubscribe()}notifyNext(e,t,r,o,s){this.destination.next(t)}notifyComplete(e){const t=this.buffer;this.remove(e),this.active--,t.length>0?this._next(t.shift()):0===this.active&&this.hasCompleted&&this.destination.complete()}}function E(){return function(e){return e.lift(new O(e))}}class O{constructor(e){this.connectable=e}call(e,t){const{connectable:r}=this;r._refCount++;const o=new D(e,r),s=t.subscribe(o);return o.closed||(o.connection=r.connect()),s}}class D extends m{constructor(e,t){super(e),this.connectable=t}_unsubscribe(){const{connectable:e}=this;if(!e)return void(this.connection=null);this.connectable=null;const t=e._refCount;if(t<=0)return void(this.connection=null);if(e._refCount=t-1,t>1)return void(this.connection=null);const{connection:r}=this,o=e._connection;this.connection=null,!o||r&&o!==r||o.unsubscribe()}}class M extends g{constructor(e,t){super(),this.source=e,this.subjectFactory=t,this._refCount=0,this._isComplete=!1}_subscribe(e){return this.getSubject().subscribe(e)}getSubject(){const e=this._subject;return e&&!e.isStopped||(this._subject=this.subjectFactory()),this._subject}connect(){let e=this._connection;return e||(this._isComplete=!1,e=this._connection=new u,e.add(this.source.subscribe(new N(this.getSubject(),this))),e.closed&&(this._connection=null,e=u.EMPTY)),e}refCount(){return E()(this)}}const H=(()=>{const e=M.prototype;return{operator:{value:null},_refCount:{value:0,writable:!0},_subject:{value:null,writable:!0},_connection:{value:null,writable:!0},_subscribe:{value:e._subscribe},_isComplete:{value:e._isComplete,writable:!0},getSubject:{value:e.getSubject},connect:{value:e.connect},refCount:{value:e.refCount}}})();class N extends y{constructor(e,t){super(e),this.connectable=t}_error(e){this._unsubscribe(),super._error(e)}_complete(){this.connectable._isComplete=!0,this._unsubscribe(),super._complete()}_unsubscribe(){const e=this.connectable;if(e){this.connectable=null;const t=e._connection;e._refCount=0,e._subject=null,e._connection=null,t&&t.unsubscribe()}}}function z(){return new T}function q(e){return{toString:e}.toString()}function R(e,t,r){return q(()=>{const o=function(e){return function(...t){if(e){const r=e(...t);for(const e in r)this[e]=r[e]}}}(t);function s(...e){if(this instanceof s)return o.apply(this,e),this;const t=new s(...e);return r.annotation=t,r;function r(e,r,o){const s=e.hasOwnProperty("__parameters__")?e.__parameters__:Object.defineProperty(e,"__parameters__",{value:[]}).__parameters__;for(;s.length<=o;)s.push(null);return(s[o]=s[o]||[]).push(t),e}}return r&&(s.prototype=Object.create(r.prototype)),s.prototype.ngMetadataName=e,s.annotationCls=s,s})}const V=R("Inject",e=>({token:e})),L=R("Optional"),U=R("Self"),Z=R("SkipSelf");var $=function(e){return e[e.Default=0]="Default",e[e.Host=1]="Host",e[e.Self=2]="Self",e[e.SkipSelf=4]="SkipSelf",e[e.Optional=8]="Optional",e}({});function G(e){for(let t in e)if(e[t]===G)return t;throw Error("Could not find renamed property on target object.")}function Y(e){return{token:e.token,providedIn:e.providedIn||null,factory:e.factory,value:void 0}}function J(e){return{factory:e.factory,providers:e.providers||[],imports:e.imports||[]}}function K(e){return X(e,e[te])||X(e,e[se])}function X(e,t){return t&&t.token===e?t:null}function ee(e){return e&&(e.hasOwnProperty(re)||e.hasOwnProperty(ne))?e[re]:null}const te=G({"\u0275prov":G}),re=G({"\u0275inj":G}),oe=G({"\u0275provFallback":G}),se=G({ngInjectableDef:G}),ne=G({ngInjectorDef:G});function ie(e){if("string"==typeof e)return e;if(Array.isArray(e))return"["+e.map(ie).join(", ")+"]";if(null==e)return""+e;if(e.overriddenName)return""+e.overriddenName;if(e.name)return""+e.name;const t=e.toString();if(null==t)return""+t;const r=t.indexOf("\n");return-1===r?t:t.substring(0,r)}function ae(e,t){return null==e||""===e?null===t?"":t:null==t||""===t?e:e+" "+t}const ce=G({__forward_ref__:G});function le(e){return e.__forward_ref__=le,e.toString=function(){return ie(this())},e}function he(e){return"function"==typeof(t=e)&&t.hasOwnProperty(ce)&&t.__forward_ref__===le?e():e;var t}const ue="undefined"!=typeof globalThis&&globalThis,de="undefined"!=typeof window&&window,pe="undefined"!=typeof self&&"undefined"!=typeof WorkerGlobalScope&&self instanceof WorkerGlobalScope&&self,me="undefined"!=typeof global&&global,fe=ue||me||de||pe,be=G({"\u0275cmp":G}),we=G({"\u0275dir":G}),ge=G({"\u0275pipe":G}),ke=G({"\u0275mod":G}),ve=G({"\u0275loc":G}),Ae=G({"\u0275fac":G}),ye=G({__NG_ELEMENT_ID__:G});class Te{constructor(e,t){this._desc=e,this.ngMetadataName="InjectionToken",this.\u0275prov=void 0,"number"==typeof t?this.__NG_ELEMENT_ID__=t:void 0!==t&&(this.\u0275prov=Y({token:this,providedIn:t.providedIn||"root",factory:t.factory}))}toString(){return"InjectionToken "+this._desc}}const Qe=new Te("INJECTOR",-1),_e={},Fe=/\n/gm,We=G({provide:String,useValue:G});let Se,Ie=void 0;function xe(e){const t=Ie;return Ie=e,t}function Be(e){const t=Se;return Se=e,t}function je(e,t=$.Default){if(void 0===Ie)throw new Error("inject() must be called from an injection context");return null===Ie?Pe(e,void 0,t):Ie.get(e,t&$.Optional?null:void 0,t)}function Ce(e,t=$.Default){return(Se||je)(he(e),t)}function Pe(e,t,r){const o=K(e);if(o&&"root"==o.providedIn)return void 0===o.value?o.value=o.factory():o.value;if(r&$.Optional)return null;if(void 0!==t)return t;throw new Error(`Injector: NOT_FOUND [${ie(e)}]`)}function Ee(e){const t=[];for(let r=0;r<e.length;r++){const o=he(e[r]);if(Array.isArray(o)){if(0===o.length)throw new Error("Arguments array must have arguments.");let e=void 0,r=$.Default;for(let t=0;t<o.length;t++){const s=o[t];s instanceof L||"Optional"===s.ngMetadataName||s===L?r|=$.Optional:s instanceof Z||"SkipSelf"===s.ngMetadataName||s===Z?r|=$.SkipSelf:s instanceof U||"Self"===s.ngMetadataName||s===U?r|=$.Self:e=s instanceof V||s===V?s.token:s}t.push(Ce(e,r))}else t.push(Ce(o))}return t}class Oe{get(e,t=_e){if(t===_e){const t=new Error(`NullInjectorError: No provider for ${ie(e)}!`);throw t.name="NullInjectorError",t}return t}}class De{}function Me(e,t){e.forEach(e=>Array.isArray(e)?Me(e,t):t(e))}function He(e,t,r){t>=e.length?e.push(r):e.splice(t,0,r)}function Ne(e,t){return t>=e.length-1?e.pop():e.splice(t,1)[0]}const ze=function(){var e={OnPush:0,Default:1};return e[e.OnPush]="OnPush",e[e.Default]="Default",e}(),qe=function(){var e={Emulated:0,Native:1,None:2,ShadowDom:3};return e[e.Emulated]="Emulated",e[e.Native]="Native",e[e.None]="None",e[e.ShadowDom]="ShadowDom",e}(),Re={},Ve=[];let Le=0;function Ue(e){return q(()=>{const t=e.type,r=t.prototype,o={},s={type:t,providersResolver:null,decls:e.decls,vars:e.vars,factory:null,template:e.template||null,consts:e.consts||null,ngContentSelectors:e.ngContentSelectors,hostBindings:e.hostBindings||null,hostVars:e.hostVars||0,hostAttrs:e.hostAttrs||null,contentQueries:e.contentQueries||null,declaredInputs:o,inputs:null,outputs:null,exportAs:e.exportAs||null,onChanges:null,onInit:r.ngOnInit||null,doCheck:r.ngDoCheck||null,afterContentInit:r.ngAfterContentInit||null,afterContentChecked:r.ngAfterContentChecked||null,afterViewInit:r.ngAfterViewInit||null,afterViewChecked:r.ngAfterViewChecked||null,onDestroy:r.ngOnDestroy||null,onPush:e.changeDetection===ze.OnPush,directiveDefs:null,pipeDefs:null,selectors:e.selectors||Ve,viewQuery:e.viewQuery||null,features:e.features||null,data:e.data||{},encapsulation:e.encapsulation||qe.Emulated,id:"c",styles:e.styles||Ve,_:null,setInput:null,schemas:e.schemas||null,tView:null},n=e.directives,i=e.features,a=e.pipes;return s.id+=Le++,s.inputs=Je(e.inputs,o),s.outputs=Je(e.outputs),i&&i.forEach(e=>e(s)),s.directiveDefs=n?()=>("function"==typeof n?n():n).map(Ze):null,s.pipeDefs=a?()=>("function"==typeof a?a():a).map($e):null,s})}function Ze(e){return Xe(e)||function(e){return e[we]||null}(e)}function $e(e){return function(e){return e[ge]||null}(e)}const Ge={};function Ye(e){const t={type:e.type,bootstrap:e.bootstrap||Ve,declarations:e.declarations||Ve,imports:e.imports||Ve,exports:e.exports||Ve,transitiveCompileScopes:null,schemas:e.schemas||null,id:e.id||null};return null!=e.id&&q(()=>{Ge[e.id]=e.type}),t}function Je(e,t){if(null==e)return Re;const r={};for(const o in e)if(e.hasOwnProperty(o)){let s=e[o],n=s;Array.isArray(s)&&(n=s[1],s=s[0]),r[s]=o,t&&(t[s]=n)}return r}const Ke=Ue;function Xe(e){return e[be]||null}function et(e,t){return e.hasOwnProperty(Ae)?e[Ae]:null}function tt(e,t){const r=e[ke]||null;if(!r&&!0===t)throw new Error(`Type ${ie(e)} does not have '\u0275mod' property.`);return r}function rt(e){return Array.isArray(e)&&"object"==typeof e[1]}function ot(e){return Array.isArray(e)&&!0===e[1]}function st(e){return 0!=(8&e.flags)}function nt(e){return 2==(2&e.flags)}function it(e){return 1==(1&e.flags)}function at(e){return null!==e.template}function ct(e){return 0!=(512&e[2])}let lt=void 0;function ht(e){return!!e.listen}const ut={createRenderer:(e,t)=>void 0!==lt?lt:"undefined"!=typeof document?document:void 0};function dt(e){for(;Array.isArray(e);)e=e[0];return e}function pt(e,t){return dt(t[e.index])}function mt(e,t){return e.data[t+20]}function ft(e,t){const r=t[e];return rt(r)?r:r[0]}function bt(e){const t=function(e){return e.__ngContext__||null}(e);return t?Array.isArray(t)?t:t.lView:null}function wt(e){return 128==(128&e[2])}function gt(e,t){return null===e||null==t?null:e[t]}function kt(e){e[18]=0}function vt(e,t){e[5]+=t;let r=e,o=e[3];for(;null!==o&&(1===t&&1===r[5]||-1===t&&0===r[5]);)o[5]+=t,r=o,o=o[3]}const At={lFrame:Dt(null),bindingsEnabled:!0,checkNoChangesMode:!1};function yt(){return At.bindingsEnabled}function Tt(){return At.lFrame.lView}function Qt(){return At.lFrame.tView}function _t(){return At.lFrame.previousOrParentTNode}function Ft(e,t){At.lFrame.previousOrParentTNode=e,At.lFrame.isParent=t}function Wt(){return At.lFrame.isParent}function St(){return At.checkNoChangesMode}function It(e){At.checkNoChangesMode=e}function xt(){return At.lFrame.bindingIndex++}function Bt(e,t){const r=At.lFrame;r.bindingIndex=r.bindingRootIndex=e,jt(t)}function jt(e){At.lFrame.currentDirectiveIndex=e}function Ct(e){At.lFrame.currentQueryIndex=e}function Pt(e,t){const r=Ot();At.lFrame=r,r.previousOrParentTNode=t,r.lView=e}function Et(e,t){const r=Ot(),o=e[1];At.lFrame=r,r.previousOrParentTNode=t,r.lView=e,r.tView=o,r.contextLView=e,r.bindingIndex=o.bindingStartIndex}function Ot(){const e=At.lFrame,t=null===e?null:e.child;return null===t?Dt(e):t}function Dt(e){const t={previousOrParentTNode:null,isParent:!0,lView:null,tView:null,selectedIndex:0,contextLView:null,elementDepthCount:0,currentNamespace:null,currentSanitizer:null,currentDirectiveIndex:-1,bindingRootIndex:-1,bindingIndex:-1,currentQueryIndex:0,parent:e,child:null};return null!==e&&(e.child=t),t}function Mt(){const e=At.lFrame;return At.lFrame=e.parent,e.previousOrParentTNode=null,e.lView=null,e}const Ht=Mt;function Nt(){const e=Mt();e.isParent=!0,e.tView=null,e.selectedIndex=0,e.contextLView=null,e.elementDepthCount=0,e.currentDirectiveIndex=-1,e.currentNamespace=null,e.currentSanitizer=null,e.bindingRootIndex=-1,e.bindingIndex=-1,e.currentQueryIndex=0}function zt(){return At.lFrame.selectedIndex}function qt(e){At.lFrame.selectedIndex=e}function Rt(e,t){for(let r=t.directiveStart,o=t.directiveEnd;r<o;r++){const t=e.data[r];t.afterContentInit&&(e.contentHooks||(e.contentHooks=[])).push(-r,t.afterContentInit),t.afterContentChecked&&((e.contentHooks||(e.contentHooks=[])).push(r,t.afterContentChecked),(e.contentCheckHooks||(e.contentCheckHooks=[])).push(r,t.afterContentChecked)),t.afterViewInit&&(e.viewHooks||(e.viewHooks=[])).push(-r,t.afterViewInit),t.afterViewChecked&&((e.viewHooks||(e.viewHooks=[])).push(r,t.afterViewChecked),(e.viewCheckHooks||(e.viewCheckHooks=[])).push(r,t.afterViewChecked)),null!=t.onDestroy&&(e.destroyHooks||(e.destroyHooks=[])).push(r,t.onDestroy)}}function Vt(e,t,r){Zt(e,t,3,r)}function Lt(e,t,r,o){(3&e[2])===r&&Zt(e,t,r,o)}function Ut(e,t){let r=e[2];(3&r)===t&&(r&=2047,r+=1,e[2]=r)}function Zt(e,t,r,o){const s=null!=o?o:-1;let n=0;for(let i=void 0!==o?65535&e[18]:0;i<t.length;i++)if("number"==typeof t[i+1]){if(n=t[i],null!=o&&n>=o)break}else t[i]<0&&(e[18]+=65536),(n<s||-1==s)&&($t(e,r,t,i),e[18]=(4294901760&e[18])+i+2),i++}function $t(e,t,r,o){const s=r[o]<0,n=r[o+1],i=e[s?-r[o]:r[o]];s?e[2]>>11<e[18]>>16&&(3&e[2])===t&&(e[2]+=2048,n.call(i)):n.call(i)}class Gt{constructor(e,t,r){this.factory=e,this.resolving=!1,this.canSeeViewProviders=t,this.injectImpl=r}}function Yt(e,t,r){const o=ht(e);let s=0;for(;s<r.length;){const n=r[s];if("number"==typeof n){if(0!==n)break;s++;const i=r[s++],a=r[s++],c=r[s++];o?e.setAttribute(t,a,c,i):t.setAttributeNS(i,a,c)}else{const i=n,a=r[++s];Jt(i)?o&&e.setProperty(t,i,a):o?e.setAttribute(t,i,a):t.setAttribute(i,a),s++}}return s}function Jt(e){return 64===e.charCodeAt(0)}function Kt(e,t){if(null===t||0===t.length);else if(null===e||0===e.length)e=t.slice();else{let r=-1;for(let o=0;o<t.length;o++){const s=t[o];"number"==typeof s?r=s:0===r||Xt(e,r,s,null,-1===r||2===r?t[++o]:null)}}return e}function Xt(e,t,r,o,s){let n=0,i=e.length;if(-1===t)i=-1;else for(;n<e.length;){const r=e[n++];if("number"==typeof r){if(r===t){i=-1;break}if(r>t){i=n-1;break}}}for(;n<e.length;){const t=e[n];if("number"==typeof t)break;if(t===r){if(null===o)return void(null!==s&&(e[n+1]=s));if(o===e[n+1])return void(e[n+2]=s)}n++,null!==o&&n++,null!==s&&n++}-1!==i&&(e.splice(i,0,t),n=i+1),e.splice(n++,0,r),null!==o&&e.splice(n++,0,o),null!==s&&e.splice(n++,0,s)}function er(e){return-1!==e}function tr(e){return 32767&e}function rr(e){return e>>16}function or(e,t){let r=rr(e),o=t;for(;r>0;)o=o[15],r--;return o}function sr(e){return"string"==typeof e?e:null==e?"":""+e}function nr(e){return"function"==typeof e?e.name||e.toString():"object"==typeof e&&null!=e&&"function"==typeof e.type?e.type.name||e.type.toString():sr(e)}const ir=(()=>("undefined"!=typeof requestAnimationFrame&&requestAnimationFrame||setTimeout).bind(fe))();function ar(e){return e instanceof Function?e():e}let cr=!0;function lr(e){const t=cr;return cr=e,t}let hr=0;function ur(e,t){const r=pr(e,t);if(-1!==r)return r;const o=t[1];o.firstCreatePass&&(e.injectorIndex=t.length,dr(o.data,e),dr(t,null),dr(o.blueprint,null));const s=mr(e,t),n=e.injectorIndex;if(er(s)){const e=tr(s),r=or(s,t),o=r[1].data;for(let s=0;s<8;s++)t[n+s]=r[e+s]|o[e+s]}return t[n+8]=s,n}function dr(e,t){e.push(0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,t)}function pr(e,t){return-1===e.injectorIndex||e.parent&&e.parent.injectorIndex===e.injectorIndex||null==t[e.injectorIndex+8]?-1:e.injectorIndex}function mr(e,t){if(e.parent&&-1!==e.parent.injectorIndex)return e.parent.injectorIndex;let r=t[6],o=1;for(;r&&-1===r.injectorIndex;)r=(t=t[15])?t[6]:null,o++;return r?r.injectorIndex|o<<16:-1}function fr(e,t,r){!function(e,t,r){let o="string"!=typeof r?r[ye]:r.charCodeAt(0)||0;null==o&&(o=r[ye]=hr++);const s=255&o,n=1<<s,i=64&s,a=32&s,c=t.data;128&s?i?a?c[e+7]|=n:c[e+6]|=n:a?c[e+5]|=n:c[e+4]|=n:i?a?c[e+3]|=n:c[e+2]|=n:a?c[e+1]|=n:c[e]|=n}(e,t,r)}function br(e,t,r,o=$.Default,s){if(null!==e){const s=function(e){if("string"==typeof e)return e.charCodeAt(0)||0;const t=e[ye];return"number"==typeof t&&t>0?255&t:t}(r);if("function"==typeof s){Pt(t,e);try{const e=s();if(null!=e||o&$.Optional)return e;throw new Error(`No provider for ${nr(r)}!`)}finally{Ht()}}else if("number"==typeof s){if(-1===s)return new yr(e,t);let n=null,i=pr(e,t),a=-1,c=o&$.Host?t[16][6]:null;for((-1===i||o&$.SkipSelf)&&(a=-1===i?mr(e,t):t[i+8],Ar(o,!1)?(n=t[1],i=tr(a),t=or(a,t)):i=-1);-1!==i;){a=t[i+8];const e=t[1];if(vr(s,i,e.data)){const e=gr(i,t,r,n,o,c);if(e!==wr)return e}Ar(o,t[1].data[i+8]===c)&&vr(s,i,t)?(n=e,i=tr(a),t=or(a,t)):i=-1}}}if(o&$.Optional&&void 0===s&&(s=null),0==(o&($.Self|$.Host))){const e=t[9],n=Be(void 0);try{return e?e.get(r,s,o&$.Optional):Pe(r,s,o&$.Optional)}finally{Be(n)}}if(o&$.Optional)return s;throw new Error(`NodeInjector: NOT_FOUND [${nr(r)}]`)}const wr={};function gr(e,t,r,o,s,n){const i=t[1],a=i.data[e+8],c=function(e,t,r,o,s){const n=e.providerIndexes,i=t.data,a=65535&n,c=e.directiveStart,l=n>>16,h=s?a+l:e.directiveEnd;for(let u=o?a:a+l;u<h;u++){const e=i[u];if(u<c&&r===e||u>=c&&e.type===r)return u}if(s){const e=i[c];if(e&&at(e)&&e.type===r)return c}return null}(a,i,r,null==o?nt(a)&&cr:o!=i&&3===a.type,s&$.Host&&n===a);return null!==c?kr(t,i,c,a):wr}function kr(e,t,r,o){let s=e[r];const n=t.data;if(s instanceof Gt){const i=s;if(i.resolving)throw new Error("Circular dep for "+nr(n[r]));const a=lr(i.canSeeViewProviders);let c;i.resolving=!0,i.injectImpl&&(c=Be(i.injectImpl)),Pt(e,o);try{s=e[r]=i.factory(void 0,n,e,o),t.firstCreatePass&&r>=o.directiveStart&&function(e,t,r){const{onChanges:o,onInit:s,doCheck:n}=t;o&&((r.preOrderHooks||(r.preOrderHooks=[])).push(e,o),(r.preOrderCheckHooks||(r.preOrderCheckHooks=[])).push(e,o)),s&&(r.preOrderHooks||(r.preOrderHooks=[])).push(-e,s),n&&((r.preOrderHooks||(r.preOrderHooks=[])).push(e,n),(r.preOrderCheckHooks||(r.preOrderCheckHooks=[])).push(e,n))}(r,n[r],t)}finally{i.injectImpl&&Be(c),lr(a),i.resolving=!1,Ht()}}return s}function vr(e,t,r){const o=64&e,s=32&e;let n;return n=128&e?o?s?r[t+7]:r[t+6]:s?r[t+5]:r[t+4]:o?s?r[t+3]:r[t+2]:s?r[t+1]:r[t],!!(n&1<<e)}function Ar(e,t){return!(e&$.Self||e&$.Host&&t)}class yr{constructor(e,t){this._tNode=e,this._lView=t}get(e,t){return br(this._tNode,this._lView,e,void 0,t)}}function Tr(e){return e.ngDebugContext}function Qr(e){return e.ngOriginalError}function _r(e,...t){e.error(...t)}class Fr{constructor(){this._console=console}handleError(e){const t=this._findOriginalError(e),r=this._findContext(e),o=function(e){return e.ngErrorLogger||_r}(e);o(this._console,"ERROR",e),t&&o(this._console,"ORIGINAL ERROR",t),r&&o(this._console,"ERROR CONTEXT",r)}_findContext(e){return e?Tr(e)?Tr(e):this._findContext(Qr(e)):null}_findOriginalError(e){let t=Qr(e);for(;t&&Qr(t);)t=Qr(t);return t}}let Wr=!0,Sr=!1;function Ir(){return Sr=!0,Wr}function xr(e,t){e.__ngContext__=t}function Br(e){throw new Error("Multiple components match node with tagname "+e.tagName)}function jr(){throw new Error("Cannot mix multi providers and regular providers")}function Cr(e,t,r){let o=e.length;for(;;){const s=e.indexOf(t,r);if(-1===s)return s;if(0===s||e.charCodeAt(s-1)<=32){const r=t.length;if(s+r===o||e.charCodeAt(s+r)<=32)return s}r=s+1}}function Pr(e,t,r){let o=0;for(;o<e.length;){let s=e[o++];if(r&&"class"===s){if(s=e[o],-1!==Cr(s.toLowerCase(),t,0))return!0}else if(1===s){for(;o<e.length&&"string"==typeof(s=e[o++]);)if(s.toLowerCase()===t)return!0;return!1}}return!1}function Er(e){return 0===e.type&&"ng-template"!==e.tagName}function Or(e,t,r){return t===(0!==e.type||r?e.tagName:"ng-template")}function Dr(e,t,r){let o=4;const s=e.attrs||[],n=function(e){for(let r=0;r<e.length;r++)if(3===(t=e[r])||4===t||6===t)return r;var t;return e.length}(s);let i=!1;for(let a=0;a<t.length;a++){const c=t[a];if("number"!=typeof c){if(!i)if(4&o){if(o=2|1&o,""!==c&&!Or(e,c,r)||""===c&&1===t.length){if(Mr(o))return!1;i=!0}}else{const l=8&o?c:t[++a];if(8&o&&null!==e.attrs){if(!Pr(e.attrs,l,r)){if(Mr(o))return!1;i=!0}continue}const h=Hr(8&o?"class":c,s,Er(e),r);if(-1===h){if(Mr(o))return!1;i=!0;continue}if(""!==l){let e;e=h>n?"":s[h+1].toLowerCase();const t=8&o?e:null;if(t&&-1!==Cr(t,l,0)||2&o&&l!==e){if(Mr(o))return!1;i=!0}}}}else{if(!i&&!Mr(o)&&!Mr(c))return!1;if(i&&Mr(c))continue;i=!1,o=c|1&o}}return Mr(o)||i}function Mr(e){return 0==(1&e)}function Hr(e,t,r,o){if(null===t)return-1;let s=0;if(o||!r){let r=!1;for(;s<t.length;){const o=t[s];if(o===e)return s;if(3===o||6===o)r=!0;else{if(1===o||2===o){let e=t[++s];for(;"string"==typeof e;)e=t[++s];continue}if(4===o)break;if(0===o){s+=4;continue}}s+=r?1:2}return-1}return function(e,t){let r=e.indexOf(4);if(r>-1)for(r++;r<e.length;){const o=e[r];if("number"==typeof o)return-1;if(o===t)return r;r++}return-1}(t,e)}function Nr(e,t,r=!1){for(let o=0;o<t.length;o++)if(Dr(e,t[o],r))return!0;return!1}function zr(e,t){return e?":not("+t.trim()+")":t}function qr(e){let t=e[0],r=1,o=2,s="",n=!1;for(;r<e.length;){let i=e[r];if("string"==typeof i)if(2&o){const t=e[++r];s+="["+i+(t.length>0?'="'+t+'"':"")+"]"}else 8&o?s+="."+i:4&o&&(s+=" "+i);else""===s||Mr(i)||(t+=zr(n,s),s=""),o=i,n=n||!Mr(o);r++}return""!==s&&(t+=zr(n,s)),t}const Rr={};function Vr(e){const t=e[3];return ot(t)?t[3]:t}function Lr(e){return Zr(e[13])}function Ur(e){return Zr(e[4])}function Zr(e){for(;null!==e&&!ot(e);)e=e[4];return e}function $r(e){Gr(Qt(),Tt(),zt()+e,St())}function Gr(e,t,r,o){if(!o)if(3==(3&t[2])){const o=e.preOrderCheckHooks;null!==o&&Vt(t,o,r)}else{const o=e.preOrderHooks;null!==o&&Lt(t,o,0,r)}qt(r)}function Yr(e,t){const r=e.contentQueries;if(null!==r)for(let o=0;o<r.length;o+=2){const s=r[o],n=r[o+1];if(-1!==n){const r=e.data[n];Ct(s),r.contentQueries(2,t[n],n)}}}function Jr(e,t,r){return ht(t)?t.createElement(e,r):null===r?t.createElement(e):t.createElementNS(r,e)}function Kr(e,t,r,o,s,n,i,a,c,l){const h=t.blueprint.slice();return h[0]=s,h[2]=140|o,kt(h),h[3]=h[15]=e,h[8]=r,h[10]=i||e&&e[10],h[11]=a||e&&e[11],h[12]=c||e&&e[12]||null,h[9]=l||e&&e[9]||null,h[6]=n,h[16]=2==t.type?e[16]:h,h}function Xr(e,t,r,o,s,n){const i=r+20,a=e.data[i]||function(e,t,r,o,s,n){const i=_t(),a=Wt(),c=a?i:i&&i.parent,l=e.data[r]=co(0,c&&c!==t?c:null,o,r,s,n);return null===e.firstChild&&(e.firstChild=l),i&&(!a||null!=i.child||null===l.parent&&2!==i.type?a||(i.next=l):i.child=l),l}(e,t,i,o,s,n);return Ft(a,!0),a}function eo(e,t,r){Et(t,t[6]);try{const o=e.viewQuery;null!==o&&Io(1,o,r);const s=e.template;null!==s&&oo(e,t,s,1,r),e.firstCreatePass&&(e.firstCreatePass=!1),e.staticContentQueries&&Yr(e,t),e.staticViewQueries&&Io(2,e.viewQuery,r);const n=e.components;null!==n&&function(e,t){for(let r=0;r<t.length;r++)_o(e,t[r])}(t,n)}catch(o){throw e.firstCreatePass&&(e.incompleteFirstPass=!0),o}finally{t[2]&=-5,Nt()}}function to(e,t,r,o){const s=t[2];if(256==(256&s))return;Et(t,t[6]);const n=St();try{kt(t),At.lFrame.bindingIndex=e.bindingStartIndex,null!==r&&oo(e,t,r,2,o);const i=3==(3&s);if(!n)if(i){const r=e.preOrderCheckHooks;null!==r&&Vt(t,r,null)}else{const r=e.preOrderHooks;null!==r&&Lt(t,r,0,null),Ut(t,0)}if(function(e){for(let t=Lr(e);null!==t;t=Ur(t)){if(!t[2])continue;const e=t[9];for(let t=0;t<e.length;t++){const r=e[t],o=r[3];0==(1024&r[2])&&vt(o,1),r[2]|=1024}}}(t),function(e){for(let t=Lr(e);null!==t;t=Ur(t))for(let e=10;e<t.length;e++){const r=t[e],o=r[1];wt(r)&&to(o,r,o.template,r[8])}}(t),null!==e.contentQueries&&Yr(e,t),!n)if(i){const r=e.contentCheckHooks;null!==r&&Vt(t,r)}else{const r=e.contentHooks;null!==r&&Lt(t,r,1),Ut(t,1)}!function(e,t){try{const r=e.expandoInstructions;if(null!==r){let o=e.expandoStartIndex,s=-1,n=-1;for(let e=0;e<r.length;e++){const i=r[e];"number"==typeof i?i<=0?(n=0-i,qt(n),o+=9+r[++e],s=o):o+=i:(null!==i&&(Bt(o,s),i(2,t[s])),s++)}}}finally{qt(-1)}}(e,t);const a=e.components;null!==a&&function(e,t){for(let r=0;r<t.length;r++)Qo(e,t[r])}(t,a);const c=e.viewQuery;if(null!==c&&Io(2,c,o),!n)if(i){const r=e.viewCheckHooks;null!==r&&Vt(t,r)}else{const r=e.viewHooks;null!==r&&Lt(t,r,2),Ut(t,2)}!0===e.firstUpdatePass&&(e.firstUpdatePass=!1),n||(t[2]&=-73),1024&t[2]&&(t[2]&=-1025,vt(t[3],-1))}finally{Nt()}}function ro(e,t,r,o){const s=t[10],n=!St(),i=4==(4&t[2]);try{n&&!i&&s.begin&&s.begin(),i&&eo(e,t,o),to(e,t,r,o)}finally{n&&!i&&s.end&&s.end()}}function oo(e,t,r,o,s){const n=zt();try{qt(-1),2&o&&t.length>20&&Gr(e,t,0,St()),r(o,s)}finally{qt(n)}}function so(e,t,r){yt()&&(function(e,t,r,o){const s=r.directiveStart,n=r.directiveEnd;e.firstCreatePass||ur(r,t),xr(o,t);const i=r.initialInputs;for(let a=s;a<n;a++){const o=e.data[a],n=at(o);n&&vo(t,r,o);const c=kr(t,e,a,r);xr(c,t),null!==i&&Ao(0,a-s,c,o,0,i),n&&(ft(r.index,t)[8]=c)}}(e,t,r,pt(r,t)),128==(128&r.flags)&&function(e,t,r){const o=r.directiveStart,s=r.directiveEnd,n=e.expandoInstructions,i=e.firstCreatePass,a=r.index-20,c=At.lFrame.currentDirectiveIndex;try{qt(a);for(let r=o;r<s;r++){const o=e.data[r],s=t[r];jt(r),null!==o.hostBindings||0!==o.hostVars||null!==o.hostAttrs?mo(o,s):i&&n.push(null)}}finally{qt(-1),jt(c)}}(e,t,r))}function no(e,t,r=pt){const o=t.localNames;if(null!==o){let s=t.index+1;for(let n=0;n<o.length;n+=2){const i=o[n+1],a=-1===i?r(t,e):e[i];e[s++]=a}}}function io(e){const t=e.tView;return null===t||t.incompleteFirstPass?e.tView=ao(1,-1,e.template,e.decls,e.vars,e.directiveDefs,e.pipeDefs,e.viewQuery,e.schemas,e.consts):t}function ao(e,t,r,o,s,n,i,a,c,l){const h=20+o,u=h+s,d=function(e,t){const r=[];for(let o=0;o<t;o++)r.push(o<e?null:Rr);return r}(h,u);return d[1]={type:e,id:t,blueprint:d,template:r,queries:null,viewQuery:a,node:null,data:d.slice().fill(null,h),bindingStartIndex:h,expandoStartIndex:u,expandoInstructions:null,firstCreatePass:!0,firstUpdatePass:!0,staticViewQueries:!1,staticContentQueries:!1,preOrderHooks:null,preOrderCheckHooks:null,contentHooks:null,contentCheckHooks:null,viewHooks:null,viewCheckHooks:null,destroyHooks:null,cleanup:null,contentQueries:null,components:null,directiveRegistry:"function"==typeof n?n():n,pipeRegistry:"function"==typeof i?i():i,firstChild:null,schemas:c,consts:l,incompleteFirstPass:!1}}function co(e,t,r,o,s,n){return{type:r,index:o,injectorIndex:t?t.injectorIndex:-1,directiveStart:-1,directiveEnd:-1,directiveStylingLast:-1,propertyBindings:null,flags:0,providerIndexes:0,tagName:s,attrs:n,mergedAttrs:null,localNames:null,initialInputs:void 0,inputs:null,outputs:null,tViews:null,next:null,projectionNext:null,child:null,parent:t,projection:null,styles:null,stylesWithoutHost:null,residualStyles:void 0,classes:null,classesWithoutHost:null,residualClasses:void 0,classBindings:0,styleBindings:0}}function lo(e,t,r){for(let o in e)if(e.hasOwnProperty(o)){const s=e[o];(r=null===r?{}:r).hasOwnProperty(o)?r[o].push(t,s):r[o]=[t,s]}return r}function ho(e,t,r,o){let s=!1;if(yt()){const n=function(e,t,r){const o=e.directiveRegistry;let s=null;if(o)for(let n=0;n<o.length;n++){const i=o[n];Nr(r,i.selectors,!1)&&(s||(s=[]),fr(ur(r,t),e,i.type),at(i)?(2&r.flags&&Br(r),bo(e,r),s.unshift(i)):s.push(i))}return s}(e,t,r),i=null===o?null:{"":-1};if(null!==n){let o=0;s=!0,go(r,e.data.length,n.length);for(let e=0;e<n.length;e++){const t=n[e];t.providersResolver&&t.providersResolver(t)}fo(e,r,n.length);let a=!1,c=!1;for(let s=0;s<n.length;s++){const l=n[s];r.mergedAttrs=Kt(r.mergedAttrs,l.hostAttrs),ko(e,t,l),wo(e.data.length-1,l,i),null!==l.contentQueries&&(r.flags|=8),null===l.hostBindings&&null===l.hostAttrs&&0===l.hostVars||(r.flags|=128),!a&&(l.onChanges||l.onInit||l.doCheck)&&((e.preOrderHooks||(e.preOrderHooks=[])).push(r.index-20),a=!0),c||!l.onChanges&&!l.doCheck||((e.preOrderCheckHooks||(e.preOrderCheckHooks=[])).push(r.index-20),c=!0),uo(e,l),o+=l.hostVars}!function(e,t){const r=t.directiveEnd,o=e.data,s=t.attrs,n=[];let i=null,a=null;for(let c=t.directiveStart;c<r;c++){const e=o[c],r=e.inputs,l=null===s||Er(t)?null:yo(r,s);n.push(l),i=lo(r,c,i),a=lo(e.outputs,c,a)}null!==i&&(i.hasOwnProperty("class")&&(t.flags|=16),i.hasOwnProperty("style")&&(t.flags|=32)),t.initialInputs=n,t.inputs=i,t.outputs=a}(e,r),po(e,t,o)}i&&function(e,t,r){if(t){const o=e.localNames=[];for(let e=0;e<t.length;e+=2){const s=r[t[e+1]];if(null==s)throw new Error(`Export of name '${t[e+1]}' not found!`);o.push(t[e],s)}}}(r,o,i)}return r.mergedAttrs=Kt(r.mergedAttrs,r.attrs),s}function uo(e,t){const r=e.expandoInstructions;r.push(t.hostBindings),0!==t.hostVars&&r.push(t.hostVars)}function po(e,t,r){for(let o=0;o<r;o++)t.push(Rr),e.blueprint.push(Rr),e.data.push(null)}function mo(e,t){null!==e.hostBindings&&e.hostBindings(1,t)}function fo(e,t,r){const o=20-t.index,s=e.data.length-(65535&t.providerIndexes);(e.expandoInstructions||(e.expandoInstructions=[])).push(o,s,r)}function bo(e,t){t.flags|=2,(e.components||(e.components=[])).push(t.index)}function wo(e,t,r){if(r){if(t.exportAs)for(let o=0;o<t.exportAs.length;o++)r[t.exportAs[o]]=e;at(t)&&(r[""]=e)}}function go(e,t,r){e.flags|=1,e.directiveStart=t,e.directiveEnd=t+r,e.providerIndexes=t}function ko(e,t,r){e.data.push(r);const o=r.factory||(r.factory=et(r.type)),s=new Gt(o,at(r),null);e.blueprint.push(s),t.push(s)}function vo(e,t,r){const o=pt(t,e),s=io(r),n=e[10],i=Fo(e,Kr(e,s,null,r.onPush?64:16,o,t,n,n.createRenderer(o,r)));e[t.index]=i}function Ao(e,t,r,o,s,n){const i=n[t];if(null!==i){const e=o.setInput;for(let t=0;t<i.length;){const s=i[t++],n=i[t++],a=i[t++];null!==e?o.setInput(r,a,s,n):r[n]=a}}}function yo(e,t){let r=null,o=0;for(;o<t.length;){const s=t[o];if(0!==s)if(5!==s){if("number"==typeof s)break;e.hasOwnProperty(s)&&(null===r&&(r=[]),r.push(s,e[s],t[o+1])),o+=2}else o+=2;else o+=4}return r}function To(e,t,r,o){return new Array(e,!0,!1,t,null,0,o,r,null,null)}function Qo(e,t){const r=ft(t,e);if(wt(r)){const e=r[1];80&r[2]?to(e,r,e.template,r[8]):r[5]>0&&function e(t){for(let o=Lr(t);null!==o;o=Ur(o))for(let t=10;t<o.length;t++){const r=o[t];if(1024&r[2]){const e=r[1];to(e,r,e.template,r[8])}else r[5]>0&&e(r)}const r=t[1].components;if(null!==r)for(let o=0;o<r.length;o++){const s=ft(r[o],t);wt(s)&&s[5]>0&&e(s)}}(r)}}function _o(e,t){const r=ft(t,e),o=r[1];!function(e,t){for(let r=t.length;r<e.blueprint.length;r++)t.push(e.blueprint[r])}(o,r),eo(o,r,r[8])}function Fo(e,t){return e[13]?e[14][4]=t:e[13]=t,e[14]=t,t}function Wo(e,t,r){const o=t[10];o.begin&&o.begin();try{to(e,t,e.template,r)}catch(s){throw function(e,t){const r=e[9],o=r?r.get(Fr,null):null;o&&o.handleError(t)}(t,s),s}finally{o.end&&o.end()}}function So(e){!function(e){for(let t=0;t<e.components.length;t++){const r=e.components[t],o=bt(r),s=o[1];ro(s,o,s.template,r)}}(e[8])}function Io(e,t,r){Ct(0),t(e,r)}const xo=(()=>Promise.resolve(null))();function Bo(e,t,r,o,s){for(let n=0;n<r.length;){const i=r[n++],a=r[n++],c=t[i],l=e.data[i];null!==l.setInput?l.setInput(c,s,o,a):c[a]=s}}function jo(e,t){const r=t[3];return-1===e.index?ot(r)?r:null:r}function Co(e,t){const r=jo(e,t);return r?Vo(t[11],r[7]):null}function Po(e,t,r,o,s){if(null!=o){let n,i=!1;ot(o)?n=o:rt(o)&&(i=!0,o=o[0]);const a=dt(o);0===e&&null!==r?null==s?qo(t,r,a):zo(t,r,a,s||null):1===e&&null!==r?zo(t,r,a,s||null):2===e?function(e,t,r){const o=Vo(e,t);o&&function(e,t,r,o){ht(e)?e.removeChild(t,r,o):t.removeChild(r)}(e,o,t,r)}(t,a,i):3===e&&t.destroyNode(a),null!=n&&function(e,t,r,o,s){const n=r[7];n!==dt(r)&&Po(t,e,o,n,s);for(let i=10;i<r.length;i++){const s=r[i];$o(s[1],s,e,t,o,n)}}(t,e,n,r,s)}}function Eo(e,t,r,o){const s=Co(e.node,t);s&&$o(e,t,t[11],r?1:2,s,o)}function Oo(e,t){const r=e[9],o=r.indexOf(t);1024&t[2]&&vt(t[3],-1),r.splice(o,1)}function Do(e,t){if(e.length<=10)return;const r=10+t,o=e[r];if(o){const s=o[17];null!==s&&s!==e&&Oo(s,o),t>0&&(e[r-1][4]=o[4]);const n=Ne(e,10+t);Eo(o[1],o,!1,null);const i=n[19];null!==i&&i.detachView(n[1]),o[3]=null,o[4]=null,o[2]&=-129}return o}function Mo(e,t){if(!(256&t[2])){const r=t[11];ht(r)&&r.destroyNode&&$o(e,t,r,3,null,null),function(e){let t=e[13];if(!t)return No(e[1],e);for(;t;){let r=null;if(rt(t))r=t[13];else{const e=t[10];e&&(r=e)}if(!r){for(;t&&!t[4]&&t!==e;)rt(t)&&No(t[1],t),t=Ho(t,e);null===t&&(t=e),rt(t)&&No(t[1],t),r=t&&t[4]}t=r}}(t)}}function Ho(e,t){let r;return rt(e)&&(r=e[6])&&2===r.type?jo(r,e):e[3]===t?null:e[3]}function No(e,t){if(!(256&t[2])){t[2]&=-129,t[2]|=256,function(e,t){let r;if(null!=e&&null!=(r=e.destroyHooks))for(let o=0;o<r.length;o+=2){const e=t[r[o]];if(!(e instanceof Gt)){const t=r[o+1];if(Array.isArray(t))for(let r=0;r<t.length;r+=2)t[r+1].call(e[t[r]]);else t.call(e)}}}(e,t),function(e,t){const r=e.cleanup;if(null!==r){const e=t[7];for(let o=0;o<r.length-1;o+=2)if("string"==typeof r[o]){const s=r[o+1],n="function"==typeof s?s(t):dt(t[s]),i=e[r[o+2]],a=r[o+3];"boolean"==typeof a?n.removeEventListener(r[o],i,a):a>=0?e[a]():e[-a].unsubscribe(),o+=2}else r[o].call(e[r[o+1]]);t[7]=null}}(e,t);const r=t[6];r&&3===r.type&&ht(t[11])&&t[11].destroy();const o=t[17];if(null!==o&&ot(t[3])){o!==t[3]&&Oo(o,t);const r=t[19];null!==r&&r.detachView(e)}}}function zo(e,t,r,o){ht(e)?e.insertBefore(t,r,o):t.insertBefore(r,o,!0)}function qo(e,t,r){ht(e)?e.appendChild(t,r):t.appendChild(r)}function Ro(e,t,r,o){null!==o?zo(e,t,r,o):qo(e,t,r)}function Vo(e,t){return ht(e)?e.parentNode(t):t.parentNode}function Lo(e,t,r,o){const s=function(e,t,r){let o=t.parent;for(;null!=o&&(4===o.type||5===o.type);)o=(t=o).parent;if(null==o){const e=r[6];return 2===e.type?Co(e,r):r[0]}if(t&&5===t.type&&4&t.flags)return pt(t,r).parentNode;if(2&o.flags){const t=e.data,r=t[t[o.index].directiveStart].encapsulation;if(r!==qe.ShadowDom&&r!==qe.Native)return null}return pt(o,r)}(e,o,t);if(null!=s){const e=t[11],n=function(e,t){if(2===e.type){const r=jo(e,t);return null===r?null:Uo(r.indexOf(t,10)-10,r)}return 4===e.type||5===e.type?pt(e,t):null}(o.parent||t[6],t);if(Array.isArray(r))for(let t=0;t<r.length;t++)Ro(e,s,r[t],n);else Ro(e,s,r,n)}}function Uo(e,t){const r=10+e+1;if(r<t.length){const e=t[r],o=e[1].firstChild;if(null!==o)return function e(t,r){if(null!==r){const o=r.type;if(3===o)return pt(r,t);if(0===o)return Uo(-1,t[r.index]);if(4===o||5===o){const o=r.child;if(null!==o)return e(t,o);{const e=t[r.index];return ot(e)?Uo(-1,e):dt(e)}}{const o=t[16],s=o[6],n=Vr(o),i=s.projection[r.projection];return null!=i?e(n,i):e(t,r.next)}}return null}(e,o)}return t[7]}function Zo(e,t,r,o,s,n,i){for(;null!=r;){const a=o[r.index],c=r.type;i&&0===t&&(a&&xr(dt(a),o),r.flags|=4),64!=(64&r.flags)&&(4===c||5===c?(Zo(e,t,r.child,o,s,n,!1),Po(t,e,s,a,n)):1===c?Go(e,t,o,r,s,n):Po(t,e,s,a,n)),r=i?r.projectionNext:r.next}}function $o(e,t,r,o,s,n){Zo(r,o,e.node.child,t,s,n,!1)}function Go(e,t,r,o,s,n){const i=r[16],a=i[6].projection[o.projection];if(Array.isArray(a))for(let c=0;c<a.length;c++)Po(t,e,s,a[c],n);else Zo(e,t,a,i[3],s,n,!0)}function Yo(e,t,r){ht(e)?e.setAttribute(t,"style",r):t.style.cssText=r}function Jo(e,t,r){ht(e)?""===r?e.removeAttribute(t,"class"):e.setAttribute(t,"class",r):t.className=r}class Ko{constructor(e,t){this._lView=e,this._cdRefInjectingView=t,this._appRef=null,this._viewContainerRef=null}get rootNodes(){const e=this._lView;return null==e[0]?function e(t,r,o,s,n=!1){for(;null!==o;){const i=r[o.index];if(null!==i&&s.push(dt(i)),ot(i))for(let t=10;t<i.length;t++){const r=i[t],o=r[1].firstChild;null!==o&&e(r[1],r,o,s)}const a=o.type;if(4===a||5===a)e(t,r,o.child,s);else if(1===a){const t=r[16],n=t[6].projection[o.projection];if(Array.isArray(n))s.push(...n);else{const r=Vr(t);e(r[1],r,n,s,!0)}}o=n?o.projectionNext:o.next}return s}(e[1],e,e[6].child,[]):[]}get context(){return this._lView[8]}get destroyed(){return 256==(256&this._lView[2])}destroy(){if(this._appRef)this._appRef.detachView(this);else if(this._viewContainerRef){const e=this._viewContainerRef.indexOf(this);e>-1&&this._viewContainerRef.detach(e),this._viewContainerRef=null}Mo(this._lView[1],this._lView)}onDestroy(e){var t,r,o,s;t=this._lView[1],o=e,(s=r=this._lView,s[7]||(s[7]=[])).push(o),t.firstCreatePass&&function(e){return e.cleanup||(e.cleanup=[])}(t).push(r[7].length-1,null)}markForCheck(){!function(e){for(;e;){e[2]|=64;const t=Vr(e);if(ct(e)&&!t)return e;e=t}}(this._cdRefInjectingView||this._lView)}detach(){this._lView[2]&=-129}reattach(){this._lView[2]|=128}detectChanges(){Wo(this._lView[1],this._lView,this.context)}checkNoChanges(){!function(e,t,r){It(!0);try{Wo(e,t,r)}finally{It(!1)}}(this._lView[1],this._lView,this.context)}attachToViewContainerRef(e){if(this._appRef)throw new Error("This view is already attached directly to the ApplicationRef!");this._viewContainerRef=e}detachFromAppRef(){var e;this._appRef=null,$o(this._lView[1],e=this._lView,e[11],2,null,null)}attachToAppRef(e){if(this._viewContainerRef)throw new Error("This view is already attached to a ViewContainer!");this._appRef=e}}class Xo extends Ko{constructor(e){super(e),this._view=e}detectChanges(){So(this._view)}checkNoChanges(){!function(e){It(!0);try{So(e)}finally{It(!1)}}(this._view)}get context(){return null}}let es,ts,rs;function os(e,t,r){return es||(es=class extends e{}),new es(pt(t,r))}const ss=new Te("Set Injector scope."),ns={},is={},as=[];let cs=void 0;function ls(){return void 0===cs&&(cs=new Oe),cs}function hs(e,t=null,r=null,o){return new us(e,r,t||ls(),o)}class us{constructor(e,t,r,o=null){this.parent=r,this.records=new Map,this.injectorDefTypes=new Set,this.onDestroy=new Set,this._destroyed=!1;const s=[];t&&Me(t,r=>this.processProvider(r,e,t)),Me([e],e=>this.processInjectorType(e,[],s)),this.records.set(Qe,ps(void 0,this));const n=this.records.get(ss);this.scope=null!=n?n.value:null,this.source=o||("object"==typeof e?null:ie(e))}get destroyed(){return this._destroyed}destroy(){this.assertNotDestroyed(),this._destroyed=!0;try{this.onDestroy.forEach(e=>e.ngOnDestroy())}finally{this.records.clear(),this.onDestroy.clear(),this.injectorDefTypes.clear()}}get(e,t=_e,r=$.Default){this.assertNotDestroyed();const o=xe(this);try{if(!(r&$.SkipSelf)){let t=this.records.get(e);if(void 0===t){const r=("function"==typeof(s=e)||"object"==typeof s&&s instanceof Te)&&K(e);t=r&&this.injectableDefInScope(r)?ps(ds(e),ns):null,this.records.set(e,t)}if(null!=t)return this.hydrate(e,t)}return(r&$.Self?ls():this.parent).get(e,t=r&$.Optional&&t===_e?null:t)}catch(n){if("NullInjectorError"===n.name){if((n.ngTempTokenPath=n.ngTempTokenPath||[]).unshift(ie(e)),o)throw n;return function(e,t,r,o){const s=e.ngTempTokenPath;throw t.__source&&s.unshift(t.__source),e.message=function(e,t,r,o=null){e=e&&"\n"===e.charAt(0)&&"\u0275"==e.charAt(1)?e.substr(2):e;let s=ie(t);if(Array.isArray(t))s=t.map(ie).join(" -> ");else if("object"==typeof t){let e=[];for(let r in t)if(t.hasOwnProperty(r)){let o=t[r];e.push(r+":"+("string"==typeof o?JSON.stringify(o):ie(o)))}s=`{${e.join(", ")}}`}return`${r}${o?"("+o+")":""}[${s}]: ${e.replace(Fe,"\n  ")}`}("\n"+e.message,s,r,o),e.ngTokenPath=s,e.ngTempTokenPath=null,e}(n,e,"R3InjectorError",this.source)}throw n}finally{xe(o)}var s}_resolveInjectorDefTypes(){this.injectorDefTypes.forEach(e=>this.get(e))}toString(){const e=[];return this.records.forEach((t,r)=>e.push(ie(r))),`R3Injector[${e.join(", ")}]`}assertNotDestroyed(){if(this._destroyed)throw new Error("Injector has already been destroyed.")}processInjectorType(e,t,r){if(!(e=he(e)))return!1;let o=ee(e);const s=null==o&&e.ngModule||void 0,n=void 0===s?e:s,i=-1!==r.indexOf(n);if(void 0!==s&&(o=ee(s)),null==o)return!1;if(null!=o.imports&&!i){let e;r.push(n);try{Me(o.imports,o=>{this.processInjectorType(o,t,r)&&(void 0===e&&(e=[]),e.push(o))})}finally{}if(void 0!==e)for(let t=0;t<e.length;t++){const{ngModule:r,providers:o}=e[t];Me(o,e=>this.processProvider(e,r,o||as))}}this.injectorDefTypes.add(n),this.records.set(n,ps(o.factory,ns));const a=o.providers;if(null!=a&&!i){const t=e;Me(a,e=>this.processProvider(e,t,a))}return void 0!==s&&void 0!==e.providers}processProvider(e,t,r){let o=fs(e=he(e))?e:he(e&&e.provide);const s=function(e,t,r){return ms(e)?ps(void 0,e.useValue):ps(function(e,t,r){let o=void 0;if(fs(e)){const t=he(e);return et(t)||ds(t)}if(ms(e))o=()=>he(e.useValue);else if((s=e)&&s.useFactory)o=()=>e.useFactory(...Ee(e.deps||[]));else if(function(e){return!(!e||!e.useExisting)}(e))o=()=>Ce(he(e.useExisting));else{const s=he(e&&(e.useClass||e.provide));if(s||function(e,t,r){let o="";throw e&&t&&(o=` - only instances of Provider and Type are allowed, got: [${t.map(e=>e==r?"?"+r+"?":"...").join(", ")}]`),new Error(`Invalid provider for the NgModule '${ie(e)}'`+o)}(t,r,e),!function(e){return!!e.deps}(e))return et(s)||ds(s);o=()=>new s(...Ee(e.deps))}var s;return o}(e,t,r),ns)}(e,t,r);if(fs(e)||!0!==e.multi){const e=this.records.get(o);e&&void 0!==e.multi&&jr()}else{let t=this.records.get(o);t?void 0===t.multi&&jr():(t=ps(void 0,ns,!0),t.factory=()=>Ee(t.multi),this.records.set(o,t)),o=e,t.multi.push(e)}this.records.set(o,s)}hydrate(e,t){var r;return t.value===is?function(e){throw new Error("Cannot instantiate cyclic dependency! "+e)}(ie(e)):t.value===ns&&(t.value=is,t.value=t.factory()),"object"==typeof t.value&&t.value&&null!==(r=t.value)&&"object"==typeof r&&"function"==typeof r.ngOnDestroy&&this.onDestroy.add(t.value),t.value}injectableDefInScope(e){return!!e.providedIn&&("string"==typeof e.providedIn?"any"===e.providedIn||e.providedIn===this.scope:this.injectorDefTypes.has(e.providedIn))}}function ds(e){const t=K(e),r=null!==t?t.factory:et(e);if(null!==r)return r;const o=ee(e);if(null!==o)return o.factory;if(e instanceof Te)throw new Error(`Token ${ie(e)} is missing a \u0275prov definition.`);if(e instanceof Function)return function(e){const t=e.length;if(t>0){const r=function(e,t){const r=[];for(let o=0;o<e;o++)r.push("?");return r}(t);throw new Error(`Can't resolve all parameters for ${ie(e)}: (${r.join(", ")}).`)}const r=function(e){const t=e&&(e[te]||e[se]||e[oe]&&e[oe]());if(t){const r=function(e){if(e.hasOwnProperty("name"))return e.name;const t=(""+e).match(/^function\s*([^\s(]+)/);return null===t?"":t[1]}(e);return console.warn(`DEPRECATED: DI is instantiating a token "${r}" that inherits its @Injectable decorator but does not provide one itself.\nThis will become an error in v10. Please add @Injectable() to the "${r}" class.`),t}return null}(e);return null!==r?()=>r.factory(e):()=>new e}(e);throw new Error("unreachable")}function ps(e,t,r=!1){return{factory:e,value:t,multi:r?[]:void 0}}function ms(e){return null!==e&&"object"==typeof e&&We in e}function fs(e){return"function"==typeof e}const bs=function(e,t,r){return function(e,t=null,r=null,o){const s=hs(e,t,r,o);return s._resolveInjectorDefTypes(),s}({name:r},t,e,r)};let ws=(()=>{class e{static create(e,t){return Array.isArray(e)?bs(e,t,""):bs(e.providers,e.parent,e.name||"")}}return e.THROW_IF_NOT_FOUND=_e,e.NULL=new Oe,e.\u0275prov=Y({token:e,providedIn:"any",factory:()=>Ce(Qe)}),e.__NG_ELEMENT_ID__=-1,e})(),gs=new Map;const ks=new Set;function vs(e){return"string"==typeof e?e:e.text()}function As(e,t,r){let o=r?e.styles:null,s=r?e.classes:null,n=0;if(null!==t)for(let i=0;i<t.length;i++){const e=t[i];"number"==typeof e?n=e:1==n?s=ae(s,e):2==n&&(o=ae(o,e+": "+t[++i]+";"))}r?e.styles=o:e.stylesWithoutHost=o,r?e.classes=s:e.classesWithoutHost=s}let ys=null;function Ts(){if(!ys){const e=fe.Symbol;if(e&&e.iterator)ys=e.iterator;else{const e=Object.getOwnPropertyNames(Map.prototype);for(let t=0;t<e.length;++t){const r=e[t];"entries"!==r&&"size"!==r&&Map.prototype[r]===Map.prototype.entries&&(ys=r)}}}return ys}function Qs(e,t){return e===t||"number"==typeof e&&"number"==typeof t&&isNaN(e)&&isNaN(t)}function _s(e){return!!Fs(e)&&(Array.isArray(e)||!(e instanceof Map)&&Ts()in e)}function Fs(e){return null!==e&&("function"==typeof e||"object"==typeof e)}function Ws(e,t,r){return!Object.is(e[t],r)&&(e[t]=r,!0)}function Ss(e,t,r,o,s,n,i,a){const c=Tt(),l=Qt(),h=e+20,u=l.firstCreatePass?function(e,t,r,o,s,n,i,a,c){const l=t.consts,h=Xr(t,r[6],e,0,i||null,gt(l,a));ho(t,r,h,gt(l,c)),Rt(t,h);const u=h.tViews=ao(2,-1,o,s,n,t.directiveRegistry,t.pipeRegistry,null,t.schemas,l),d=co(0,null,2,-1,null,null);return d.injectorIndex=h.injectorIndex,u.node=d,null!==t.queries&&(t.queries.template(t,h),u.queries=t.queries.embeddedTView(h)),h}(e,l,c,t,r,o,s,n,i):l.data[h];Ft(u,!1);const d=c[11].createComment("");Lo(l,c,d,u),xr(d,c),Fo(c,c[h]=To(d,c,d,u)),it(u)&&so(l,c,u),null!=i&&no(c,u,a)}function Is(e,t=$.Default){const r=Tt();return null==r?Ce(e,t):br(_t(),r,he(e),t)}function xs(e,t,r){const o=Tt();return Ws(o,xt(),t)&&function(e,t,r,o,s,n,i,a){const c=pt(t,r);let l,h=t.inputs;var u;null!=h&&(l=h[o])?(Bo(e,r,l,o,s),nt(t)&&function(e,t){const r=ft(t,e);16&r[2]||(r[2]|=64)}(r,t.index)):3===t.type&&(o="class"===(u=o)?"className":"for"===u?"htmlFor":"formaction"===u?"formAction":"innerHtml"===u?"innerHTML":"readonly"===u?"readOnly":"tabindex"===u?"tabIndex":u,s=null!=i?i(s,t.tagName||"",o):s,ht(n)?n.setProperty(c,o,s):Jt(o)||(c.setProperty?c.setProperty(o,s):c[o]=s))}(Qt(),function(){const e=At.lFrame;return mt(e.tView,e.selectedIndex)}(),o,e,t,o[11],r),xs}function Bs(e,t,r,o,s){const n=s?"class":"style";Bo(e,r,t.inputs[n],n,o)}function js(e,t,r,o){const s=Tt(),n=Qt(),i=20+e,a=s[11],c=s[i]=Jr(t,a,At.lFrame.currentNamespace),l=n.firstCreatePass?function(e,t,r,o,s,n,i){const a=t.consts,c=gt(a,n),l=Xr(t,r[6],e,3,s,c);return ho(t,r,l,gt(a,i)),null!==l.attrs&&As(l,l.attrs,!1),null!==l.mergedAttrs&&As(l,l.mergedAttrs,!0),null!==t.queries&&t.queries.elementStart(t,l),l}(e,n,s,0,t,r,o):n.data[i];Ft(l,!0);const h=l.mergedAttrs;null!==h&&Yt(a,c,h);const u=l.classes;null!==u&&Jo(a,c,u);const d=l.styles;null!==d&&Yo(a,c,d),Lo(n,s,c,l),0===At.lFrame.elementDepthCount&&xr(c,s),At.lFrame.elementDepthCount++,it(l)&&(so(n,s,l),function(e,t,r){if(st(t)){const o=t.directiveEnd;for(let s=t.directiveStart;s<o;s++){const t=e.data[s];t.contentQueries&&t.contentQueries(1,r[s],s)}}}(n,l,s)),null!==o&&no(s,l)}function Cs(){let e=_t();Wt()?At.lFrame.isParent=!1:(e=e.parent,Ft(e,!1));const t=e;At.lFrame.elementDepthCount--;const r=Qt();r.firstCreatePass&&(Rt(r,e),st(e)&&r.queries.elementEnd(e)),null!=t.classesWithoutHost&&function(e){return 0!=(16&e.flags)}(t)&&Bs(r,t,Tt(),t.classesWithoutHost,!0),null!=t.stylesWithoutHost&&function(e){return 0!=(32&e.flags)}(t)&&Bs(r,t,Tt(),t.stylesWithoutHost,!1)}function Ps(e){return!!e&&"function"==typeof e.then}function Es(e,t=""){const r=Tt(),o=Qt(),s=e+20,n=o.firstCreatePass?Xr(o,r[6],e,3,null,null):o.data[s],i=r[s]=function(e,t){return ht(t)?t.createText(e):t.createTextNode(e)}(t,r[11]);Lo(o,r,i,n),Ft(n,!1)}function Os(e){return Ds("",e,""),Os}function Ds(e,t,r){const o=Tt(),s=function(e,t,r,o){return Ws(e,xt(),r)?t+sr(r)+o:Rr}(o,e,t,r);return s!==Rr&&function(e,t,r){const o=function(e,t){return dt(t[e+20])}(t,e),s=e[11];ht(s)?s.setValue(o,r):o.textContent=r}(o,zt(),s),Ds}function Ms(e,t){const r=bt(e)[1],o=r.data.length-1;Rt(r,{directiveStart:o,directiveEnd:o+1})}class Hs{}class Ns{resolveComponentFactory(e){throw function(e){const t=Error(`No component factory found for ${ie(e)}. Did you add it to @NgModule.entryComponents?`);return t.ngComponent=e,t}(e)}}let zs=(()=>{class e{}return e.NULL=new Ns,e})(),qs=(()=>{class e{constructor(e){this.nativeElement=e}}return e.__NG_ELEMENT_ID__=()=>Rs(e),e})();const Rs=function(e){return os(e,_t(),Tt())};class Vs{}const Ls=function(){var e={Important:1,DashCase:2};return e[e.Important]="Important",e[e.DashCase]="DashCase",e}();let Us=(()=>{class e{}return e.\u0275prov=Y({token:e,providedIn:"root",factory:()=>null}),e})();class Zs{constructor(e){this.full=e,this.major=e.split(".")[0],this.minor=e.split(".")[1],this.patch=e.split(".").slice(2).join(".")}}const $s=new Zs("9.1.12");class Gs{constructor(){}supports(e){return _s(e)}create(e){return new Js(e)}}const Ys=(e,t)=>t;class Js{constructor(e){this.length=0,this._linkedRecords=null,this._unlinkedRecords=null,this._previousItHead=null,this._itHead=null,this._itTail=null,this._additionsHead=null,this._additionsTail=null,this._movesHead=null,this._movesTail=null,this._removalsHead=null,this._removalsTail=null,this._identityChangesHead=null,this._identityChangesTail=null,this._trackByFn=e||Ys}forEachItem(e){let t;for(t=this._itHead;null!==t;t=t._next)e(t)}forEachOperation(e){let t=this._itHead,r=this._removalsHead,o=0,s=null;for(;t||r;){const n=!r||t&&t.currentIndex<tn(r,o,s)?t:r,i=tn(n,o,s),a=n.currentIndex;if(n===r)o--,r=r._nextRemoved;else if(t=t._next,null==n.previousIndex)o++;else{s||(s=[]);const e=i-o,t=a-o;if(e!=t){for(let r=0;r<e;r++){const o=r<s.length?s[r]:s[r]=0,n=o+r;t<=n&&n<e&&(s[r]=o+1)}s[n.previousIndex]=t-e}}i!==a&&e(n,i,a)}}forEachPreviousItem(e){let t;for(t=this._previousItHead;null!==t;t=t._nextPrevious)e(t)}forEachAddedItem(e){let t;for(t=this._additionsHead;null!==t;t=t._nextAdded)e(t)}forEachMovedItem(e){let t;for(t=this._movesHead;null!==t;t=t._nextMoved)e(t)}forEachRemovedItem(e){let t;for(t=this._removalsHead;null!==t;t=t._nextRemoved)e(t)}forEachIdentityChange(e){let t;for(t=this._identityChangesHead;null!==t;t=t._nextIdentityChange)e(t)}diff(e){if(null==e&&(e=[]),!_s(e))throw new Error(`Error trying to diff '${ie(e)}'. Only arrays and iterables are allowed`);return this.check(e)?this:null}onDestroy(){}check(e){this._reset();let t,r,o,s=this._itHead,n=!1;if(Array.isArray(e)){this.length=e.length;for(let t=0;t<this.length;t++)r=e[t],o=this._trackByFn(t,r),null!==s&&Qs(s.trackById,o)?(n&&(s=this._verifyReinsertion(s,r,o,t)),Qs(s.item,r)||this._addIdentityChange(s,r)):(s=this._mismatch(s,r,o,t),n=!0),s=s._next}else t=0,function(e,t){if(Array.isArray(e))for(let r=0;r<e.length;r++)t(e[r]);else{const r=e[Ts()]();let o;for(;!(o=r.next()).done;)t(o.value)}}(e,e=>{o=this._trackByFn(t,e),null!==s&&Qs(s.trackById,o)?(n&&(s=this._verifyReinsertion(s,e,o,t)),Qs(s.item,e)||this._addIdentityChange(s,e)):(s=this._mismatch(s,e,o,t),n=!0),s=s._next,t++}),this.length=t;return this._truncate(s),this.collection=e,this.isDirty}get isDirty(){return null!==this._additionsHead||null!==this._movesHead||null!==this._removalsHead||null!==this._identityChangesHead}_reset(){if(this.isDirty){let e,t;for(e=this._previousItHead=this._itHead;null!==e;e=e._next)e._nextPrevious=e._next;for(e=this._additionsHead;null!==e;e=e._nextAdded)e.previousIndex=e.currentIndex;for(this._additionsHead=this._additionsTail=null,e=this._movesHead;null!==e;e=t)e.previousIndex=e.currentIndex,t=e._nextMoved;this._movesHead=this._movesTail=null,this._removalsHead=this._removalsTail=null,this._identityChangesHead=this._identityChangesTail=null}}_mismatch(e,t,r,o){let s;return null===e?s=this._itTail:(s=e._prev,this._remove(e)),null!==(e=null===this._linkedRecords?null:this._linkedRecords.get(r,o))?(Qs(e.item,t)||this._addIdentityChange(e,t),this._moveAfter(e,s,o)):null!==(e=null===this._unlinkedRecords?null:this._unlinkedRecords.get(r,null))?(Qs(e.item,t)||this._addIdentityChange(e,t),this._reinsertAfter(e,s,o)):e=this._addAfter(new Ks(t,r),s,o),e}_verifyReinsertion(e,t,r,o){let s=null===this._unlinkedRecords?null:this._unlinkedRecords.get(r,null);return null!==s?e=this._reinsertAfter(s,e._prev,o):e.currentIndex!=o&&(e.currentIndex=o,this._addToMoves(e,o)),e}_truncate(e){for(;null!==e;){const t=e._next;this._addToRemovals(this._unlink(e)),e=t}null!==this._unlinkedRecords&&this._unlinkedRecords.clear(),null!==this._additionsTail&&(this._additionsTail._nextAdded=null),null!==this._movesTail&&(this._movesTail._nextMoved=null),null!==this._itTail&&(this._itTail._next=null),null!==this._removalsTail&&(this._removalsTail._nextRemoved=null),null!==this._identityChangesTail&&(this._identityChangesTail._nextIdentityChange=null)}_reinsertAfter(e,t,r){null!==this._unlinkedRecords&&this._unlinkedRecords.remove(e);const o=e._prevRemoved,s=e._nextRemoved;return null===o?this._removalsHead=s:o._nextRemoved=s,null===s?this._removalsTail=o:s._prevRemoved=o,this._insertAfter(e,t,r),this._addToMoves(e,r),e}_moveAfter(e,t,r){return this._unlink(e),this._insertAfter(e,t,r),this._addToMoves(e,r),e}_addAfter(e,t,r){return this._insertAfter(e,t,r),this._additionsTail=null===this._additionsTail?this._additionsHead=e:this._additionsTail._nextAdded=e,e}_insertAfter(e,t,r){const o=null===t?this._itHead:t._next;return e._next=o,e._prev=t,null===o?this._itTail=e:o._prev=e,null===t?this._itHead=e:t._next=e,null===this._linkedRecords&&(this._linkedRecords=new en),this._linkedRecords.put(e),e.currentIndex=r,e}_remove(e){return this._addToRemovals(this._unlink(e))}_unlink(e){null!==this._linkedRecords&&this._linkedRecords.remove(e);const t=e._prev,r=e._next;return null===t?this._itHead=r:t._next=r,null===r?this._itTail=t:r._prev=t,e}_addToMoves(e,t){return e.previousIndex===t||(this._movesTail=null===this._movesTail?this._movesHead=e:this._movesTail._nextMoved=e),e}_addToRemovals(e){return null===this._unlinkedRecords&&(this._unlinkedRecords=new en),this._unlinkedRecords.put(e),e.currentIndex=null,e._nextRemoved=null,null===this._removalsTail?(this._removalsTail=this._removalsHead=e,e._prevRemoved=null):(e._prevRemoved=this._removalsTail,this._removalsTail=this._removalsTail._nextRemoved=e),e}_addIdentityChange(e,t){return e.item=t,this._identityChangesTail=null===this._identityChangesTail?this._identityChangesHead=e:this._identityChangesTail._nextIdentityChange=e,e}}class Ks{constructor(e,t){this.item=e,this.trackById=t,this.currentIndex=null,this.previousIndex=null,this._nextPrevious=null,this._prev=null,this._next=null,this._prevDup=null,this._nextDup=null,this._prevRemoved=null,this._nextRemoved=null,this._nextAdded=null,this._nextMoved=null,this._nextIdentityChange=null}}class Xs{constructor(){this._head=null,this._tail=null}add(e){null===this._head?(this._head=this._tail=e,e._nextDup=null,e._prevDup=null):(this._tail._nextDup=e,e._prevDup=this._tail,e._nextDup=null,this._tail=e)}get(e,t){let r;for(r=this._head;null!==r;r=r._nextDup)if((null===t||t<=r.currentIndex)&&Qs(r.trackById,e))return r;return null}remove(e){const t=e._prevDup,r=e._nextDup;return null===t?this._head=r:t._nextDup=r,null===r?this._tail=t:r._prevDup=t,null===this._head}}class en{constructor(){this.map=new Map}put(e){const t=e.trackById;let r=this.map.get(t);r||(r=new Xs,this.map.set(t,r)),r.add(e)}get(e,t){const r=this.map.get(e);return r?r.get(e,t):null}remove(e){const t=e.trackById;return this.map.get(t).remove(e)&&this.map.delete(t),e}get isEmpty(){return 0===this.map.size}clear(){this.map.clear()}}function tn(e,t,r){const o=e.previousIndex;if(null===o)return o;let s=0;return r&&o<r.length&&(s=r[o]),o+t+s}class rn{constructor(){}supports(e){return e instanceof Map||Fs(e)}create(){return new on}}class on{constructor(){this._records=new Map,this._mapHead=null,this._appendAfter=null,this._previousMapHead=null,this._changesHead=null,this._changesTail=null,this._additionsHead=null,this._additionsTail=null,this._removalsHead=null,this._removalsTail=null}get isDirty(){return null!==this._additionsHead||null!==this._changesHead||null!==this._removalsHead}forEachItem(e){let t;for(t=this._mapHead;null!==t;t=t._next)e(t)}forEachPreviousItem(e){let t;for(t=this._previousMapHead;null!==t;t=t._nextPrevious)e(t)}forEachChangedItem(e){let t;for(t=this._changesHead;null!==t;t=t._nextChanged)e(t)}forEachAddedItem(e){let t;for(t=this._additionsHead;null!==t;t=t._nextAdded)e(t)}forEachRemovedItem(e){let t;for(t=this._removalsHead;null!==t;t=t._nextRemoved)e(t)}diff(e){if(e){if(!(e instanceof Map||Fs(e)))throw new Error(`Error trying to diff '${ie(e)}'. Only maps and objects are allowed`)}else e=new Map;return this.check(e)?this:null}onDestroy(){}check(e){this._reset();let t=this._mapHead;if(this._appendAfter=null,this._forEach(e,(e,r)=>{if(t&&t.key===r)this._maybeAddToChanges(t,e),this._appendAfter=t,t=t._next;else{const o=this._getOrCreateRecordForKey(r,e);t=this._insertBeforeOrAppend(t,o)}}),t){t._prev&&(t._prev._next=null),this._removalsHead=t;for(let e=t;null!==e;e=e._nextRemoved)e===this._mapHead&&(this._mapHead=null),this._records.delete(e.key),e._nextRemoved=e._next,e.previousValue=e.currentValue,e.currentValue=null,e._prev=null,e._next=null}return this._changesTail&&(this._changesTail._nextChanged=null),this._additionsTail&&(this._additionsTail._nextAdded=null),this.isDirty}_insertBeforeOrAppend(e,t){if(e){const r=e._prev;return t._next=e,t._prev=r,e._prev=t,r&&(r._next=t),e===this._mapHead&&(this._mapHead=t),this._appendAfter=e,e}return this._appendAfter?(this._appendAfter._next=t,t._prev=this._appendAfter):this._mapHead=t,this._appendAfter=t,null}_getOrCreateRecordForKey(e,t){if(this._records.has(e)){const r=this._records.get(e);this._maybeAddToChanges(r,t);const o=r._prev,s=r._next;return o&&(o._next=s),s&&(s._prev=o),r._next=null,r._prev=null,r}const r=new sn(e);return this._records.set(e,r),r.currentValue=t,this._addToAdditions(r),r}_reset(){if(this.isDirty){let e;for(this._previousMapHead=this._mapHead,e=this._previousMapHead;null!==e;e=e._next)e._nextPrevious=e._next;for(e=this._changesHead;null!==e;e=e._nextChanged)e.previousValue=e.currentValue;for(e=this._additionsHead;null!=e;e=e._nextAdded)e.previousValue=e.currentValue;this._changesHead=this._changesTail=null,this._additionsHead=this._additionsTail=null,this._removalsHead=null}}_maybeAddToChanges(e,t){Qs(t,e.currentValue)||(e.previousValue=e.currentValue,e.currentValue=t,this._addToChanges(e))}_addToAdditions(e){null===this._additionsHead?this._additionsHead=this._additionsTail=e:(this._additionsTail._nextAdded=e,this._additionsTail=e)}_addToChanges(e){null===this._changesHead?this._changesHead=this._changesTail=e:(this._changesTail._nextChanged=e,this._changesTail=e)}_forEach(e,t){e instanceof Map?e.forEach(t):Object.keys(e).forEach(r=>t(e[r],r))}}class sn{constructor(e){this.key=e,this.previousValue=null,this.currentValue=null,this._nextPrevious=null,this._next=null,this._prev=null,this._nextAdded=null,this._nextRemoved=null,this._nextChanged=null}}let nn=(()=>{class e{constructor(e){this.factories=e}static create(t,r){if(null!=r){const e=r.factories.slice();t=t.concat(e)}return new e(t)}static extend(t){return{provide:e,useFactory:r=>{if(!r)throw new Error("Cannot extend IterableDiffers without a parent injector");return e.create(t,r)},deps:[[e,new Z,new L]]}}find(e){const t=this.factories.find(t=>t.supports(e));if(null!=t)return t;throw new Error(`Cannot find a differ supporting object '${e}' of type '${r=e,r.name||typeof r}'`);var r}}return e.\u0275prov=Y({token:e,providedIn:"root",factory:()=>new e([new Gs])}),e})(),an=(()=>{class e{constructor(e){this.factories=e}static create(t,r){if(r){const e=r.factories.slice();t=t.concat(e)}return new e(t)}static extend(t){return{provide:e,useFactory:r=>{if(!r)throw new Error("Cannot extend KeyValueDiffers without a parent injector");return e.create(t,r)},deps:[[e,new Z,new L]]}}find(e){const t=this.factories.find(t=>t.supports(e));if(t)return t;throw new Error(`Cannot find a differ supporting object '${e}'`)}}return e.\u0275prov=Y({token:e,providedIn:"root",factory:()=>new e([new rn])}),e})();const cn=[new rn],ln=new nn([new Gs]),hn=new an(cn);let un=(()=>{class e{}return e.__NG_ELEMENT_ID__=()=>dn(e,qs),e})();const dn=function(e,t){return function(e,t,r,o){return ts||(ts=class extends e{constructor(e,t,r){super(),this._declarationView=e,this._declarationTContainer=t,this.elementRef=r}createEmbeddedView(e){const t=this._declarationTContainer.tViews,r=Kr(this._declarationView,t,e,16,null,t.node);r[17]=this._declarationView[this._declarationTContainer.index];const o=this._declarationView[19];return null!==o&&(r[19]=o.createEmbeddedView(t)),eo(t,r,e),new Ko(r)}}),0===r.type?new ts(o,r,os(t,r,o)):null}(e,t,_t(),Tt())};let pn=(()=>{class e{}return e.__NG_ELEMENT_ID__=()=>mn(e,qs),e})();const mn=function(e,t){return function(e,t,r,o){let s;rs||(rs=class extends e{constructor(e,t,r){super(),this._lContainer=e,this._hostTNode=t,this._hostView=r}get element(){return os(t,this._hostTNode,this._hostView)}get injector(){return new yr(this._hostTNode,this._hostView)}get parentInjector(){const e=mr(this._hostTNode,this._hostView),t=or(e,this._hostView),r=function(e,t,r){if(r.parent&&-1!==r.parent.injectorIndex){const e=r.parent.injectorIndex;let t=r.parent;for(;null!=t.parent&&e==t.parent.injectorIndex;)t=t.parent;return t}let o=rr(e),s=t,n=t[6];for(;o>1;)s=s[15],n=s[6],o--;return n}(e,this._hostView,this._hostTNode);return er(e)&&null!=r?new yr(r,t):new yr(null,this._hostView)}clear(){for(;this.length>0;)this.remove(this.length-1)}get(e){return null!==this._lContainer[8]&&this._lContainer[8][e]||null}get length(){return this._lContainer.length-10}createEmbeddedView(e,t,r){const o=e.createEmbeddedView(t||{});return this.insert(o,r),o}createComponent(e,t,r,o,s){const n=r||this.parentInjector;if(!s&&null==e.ngModule&&n){const e=n.get(De,null);e&&(s=e)}const i=e.create(n,o,void 0,s);return this.insert(i.hostView,t),i}insert(e,t){const r=e._lView,o=r[1];if(e.destroyed)throw new Error("Cannot insert a destroyed View in a ViewContainer!");if(this.allocateContainerIfNeeded(),ot(r[3])){const t=this.indexOf(e);if(-1!==t)this.detach(t);else{const t=r[3],o=new rs(t,t[6],t[3]);o.detach(o.indexOf(e))}}const s=this._adjustIndex(t);return function(e,t,r,o){const s=10+o,n=r.length;o>0&&(r[s-1][4]=t),o<n-10?(t[4]=r[s],He(r,10+o,t)):(r.push(t),t[4]=null),t[3]=r;const i=t[17];null!==i&&r!==i&&function(e,t){const r=e[9];t[16]!==t[3][3][16]&&(e[2]=!0),null===r?e[9]=[t]:r.push(t)}(i,t);const a=t[19];null!==a&&a.insertView(e),t[2]|=128}(o,r,this._lContainer,s),Eo(o,r,!0,Uo(s,this._lContainer)),e.attachToViewContainerRef(this),He(this._lContainer[8],s,e),e}move(e,t){if(e.destroyed)throw new Error("Cannot move a destroyed View in a ViewContainer!");return this.insert(e,t)}indexOf(e){const t=this._lContainer[8];return null!==t?t.indexOf(e):-1}remove(e){this.allocateContainerIfNeeded();const t=this._adjustIndex(e,-1);!function(e,t){const r=Do(e,t);r&&Mo(r[1],r)}(this._lContainer,t),Ne(this._lContainer[8],t)}detach(e){this.allocateContainerIfNeeded();const t=this._adjustIndex(e,-1),r=Do(this._lContainer,t);return r&&null!=Ne(this._lContainer[8],t)?new Ko(r):null}_adjustIndex(e,t=0){return null==e?this.length+t:e}allocateContainerIfNeeded(){null===this._lContainer[8]&&(this._lContainer[8]=[])}});const n=o[r.index];if(ot(n))s=n;else{let e;if(4===r.type)e=dt(n);else if(e=o[11].createComment(""),ct(o)){const t=o[11],s=pt(r,o);zo(t,Vo(t,s),e,function(e,t){return ht(e)?e.nextSibling(t):t.nextSibling}(t,s))}else Lo(o[1],o,e,r);o[r.index]=s=To(n,o,e,r),Fo(o,s)}return new rs(s,r,o)}(e,t,_t(),Tt())},fn={};class bn extends zs{constructor(e){super(),this.ngModule=e}resolveComponentFactory(e){const t=Xe(e);return new kn(t,this.ngModule)}}function wn(e){const t=[];for(let r in e)e.hasOwnProperty(r)&&t.push({propName:e[r],templateName:r});return t}const gn=new Te("SCHEDULER_TOKEN",{providedIn:"root",factory:()=>ir});class kn extends Hs{constructor(e,t){super(),this.componentDef=e,this.ngModule=t,this.componentType=e.type,this.selector=e.selectors.map(qr).join(","),this.ngContentSelectors=e.ngContentSelectors?e.ngContentSelectors:[],this.isBoundToModule=!!t}get inputs(){return wn(this.componentDef.inputs)}get outputs(){return wn(this.componentDef.outputs)}create(e,t,r,o){const s=(o=o||this.ngModule)?function(e,t){return{get:(r,o,s)=>{const n=e.get(r,fn,s);return n!==fn||o===fn?n:t.get(r,o,s)}}}(e,o.injector):e,n=s.get(Vs,ut),i=s.get(Us,null),a=n.createRenderer(null,this.componentDef),c=this.componentDef.selectors[0][0]||"div",l=r?function(e,t,r){if(ht(e))return e.selectRootElement(t,r===qe.ShadowDom);let o="string"==typeof t?e.querySelector(t):t;return o.textContent="",o}(a,r,this.componentDef.encapsulation):Jr(c,n.createRenderer(null,this.componentDef),function(e){const t=e.toLowerCase();return"svg"===t?"http://www.w3.org/2000/svg":"math"===t?"http://www.w3.org/1998/MathML/":null}(c)),h=this.componentDef.onPush?576:528,u="string"==typeof r&&/^#root-ng-internal-isolated-\d+/.test(r),d={components:[],scheduler:ir,clean:xo,playerHandler:null,flags:0},p=ao(0,-1,null,1,0,null,null,null,null,null),m=Kr(null,p,d,h,null,null,n,a,i,s);let f,b;Et(m,null);try{const e=function(e,t,r,o,s,n){const i=r[1];r[20]=e;const a=Xr(i,null,0,3,null,null),c=a.mergedAttrs=t.hostAttrs;null!==c&&(As(a,c,!0),null!==e&&(Yt(s,e,c),null!==a.classes&&Jo(s,e,a.classes),null!==a.styles&&Yo(s,e,a.styles)));const l=o.createRenderer(e,t),h=Kr(r,io(t),null,t.onPush?64:16,r[20],a,o,l,void 0);return i.firstCreatePass&&(fr(ur(a,r),i,t.type),bo(i,a),go(a,r.length,1)),Fo(r,h),r[20]=h}(l,this.componentDef,m,n,a);if(l)if(r)Yt(a,l,["ng-version",$s.full]);else{const{attrs:e,classes:t}=function(e){const t=[],r=[];let o=1,s=2;for(;o<e.length;){let n=e[o];if("string"==typeof n)2===s?""!==n&&t.push(n,e[++o]):8===s&&r.push(n);else{if(!Mr(s))break;s=n}o++}return{attrs:t,classes:r}}(this.componentDef.selectors[0]);e&&Yt(a,l,e),t&&t.length>0&&Jo(a,l,t.join(" "))}if(b=mt(p,0),void 0!==t){const e=b.projection=[];for(let r=0;r<this.ngContentSelectors.length;r++){const o=t[r];e.push(null!=o?Array.from(o):null)}}f=function(e,t,r,o,s){const n=r[1],i=function(e,t,r){const o=_t();e.firstCreatePass&&(r.providersResolver&&r.providersResolver(r),fo(e,o,1),ko(e,t,r));const s=kr(t,e,t.length-1,o);xr(s,t);const n=pt(o,t);return n&&xr(n,t),s}(n,r,t);o.components.push(i),e[8]=i,s&&s.forEach(e=>e(i,t)),t.contentQueries&&t.contentQueries(1,i,r.length-1);const a=_t();if(n.firstCreatePass&&(null!==t.hostBindings||null!==t.hostAttrs)){qt(a.index-20);const e=r[1];uo(e,t),po(e,r,t.hostVars),mo(t,i)}return i}(e,this.componentDef,m,d,[Ms]),eo(p,m,null)}finally{Nt()}const w=new vn(this.componentType,f,os(qs,b,m),m,b);return r&&!u||(p.node.child=b),w}}class vn extends class{}{constructor(e,t,r,o,s){super(),this.location=r,this._rootLView=o,this._tNode=s,this.destroyCbs=[],this.instance=t,this.hostView=this.changeDetectorRef=new Xo(o),function(e,t,r,o){let s=e.node;null==s&&(e.node=s=co(0,null,2,-1,null,null)),o[6]=s}(o[1],0,0,o),this.componentType=e}get injector(){return new yr(this._tNode,this._rootLView)}destroy(){this.destroyCbs&&(this.destroyCbs.forEach(e=>e()),this.destroyCbs=null,!this.hostView.destroyed&&this.hostView.destroy())}onDestroy(e){this.destroyCbs&&this.destroyCbs.push(e)}}const An=void 0;var yn=["en",[["a","p"],["AM","PM"],An],[["AM","PM"],An,An],[["S","M","T","W","T","F","S"],["Sun","Mon","Tue","Wed","Thu","Fri","Sat"],["Sunday","Monday","Tuesday","Wednesday","Thursday","Friday","Saturday"],["Su","Mo","Tu","We","Th","Fr","Sa"]],An,[["J","F","M","A","M","J","J","A","S","O","N","D"],["Jan","Feb","Mar","Apr","May","Jun","Jul","Aug","Sep","Oct","Nov","Dec"],["January","February","March","April","May","June","July","August","September","October","November","December"]],An,[["B","A"],["BC","AD"],["Before Christ","Anno Domini"]],0,[6,0],["M/d/yy","MMM d, y","MMMM d, y","EEEE, MMMM d, y"],["h:mm a","h:mm:ss a","h:mm:ss a z","h:mm:ss a zzzz"],["{1}, {0}",An,"{1} 'at' {0}",An],[".",",",";","%","+","-","E","\xd7","\u2030","\u221e","NaN",":"],["#,##0.###","#,##0%","\xa4#,##0.00","#E0"],"USD","$","US Dollar",{},"ltr",function(e){let t=Math.floor(Math.abs(e)),r=e.toString().replace(/^[^.]*\.?/,"").length;return 1===t&&0===r?1:5}];let Tn={};function Qn(e){return e in Tn||(Tn[e]=fe.ng&&fe.ng.common&&fe.ng.common.locales&&fe.ng.common.locales[e]),Tn[e]}const _n=function(){var e={LocaleId:0,DayPeriodsFormat:1,DayPeriodsStandalone:2,DaysFormat:3,DaysStandalone:4,MonthsFormat:5,MonthsStandalone:6,Eras:7,FirstDayOfWeek:8,WeekendRange:9,DateFormat:10,TimeFormat:11,DateTimeFormat:12,NumberSymbols:13,NumberFormats:14,CurrencyCode:15,CurrencySymbol:16,CurrencyName:17,Currencies:18,Directionality:19,PluralCase:20,ExtraData:21};return e[e.LocaleId]="LocaleId",e[e.DayPeriodsFormat]="DayPeriodsFormat",e[e.DayPeriodsStandalone]="DayPeriodsStandalone",e[e.DaysFormat]="DaysFormat",e[e.DaysStandalone]="DaysStandalone",e[e.MonthsFormat]="MonthsFormat",e[e.MonthsStandalone]="MonthsStandalone",e[e.Eras]="Eras",e[e.FirstDayOfWeek]="FirstDayOfWeek",e[e.WeekendRange]="WeekendRange",e[e.DateFormat]="DateFormat",e[e.TimeFormat]="TimeFormat",e[e.DateTimeFormat]="DateTimeFormat",e[e.NumberSymbols]="NumberSymbols",e[e.NumberFormats]="NumberFormats",e[e.CurrencyCode]="CurrencyCode",e[e.CurrencySymbol]="CurrencySymbol",e[e.CurrencyName]="CurrencyName",e[e.Currencies]="Currencies",e[e.Directionality]="Directionality",e[e.PluralCase]="PluralCase",e[e.ExtraData]="ExtraData",e}();let Fn="en-US";function Wn(e){var t,r;r="Expected localeId to be defined",null==(t=e)&&function(e,t,r,o){throw new Error("ASSERTION ERROR: "+e+` [Expected=> null != ${t} <=Actual]`)}(r,t),"string"==typeof e&&(Fn=e.toLowerCase().replace(/_/g,"-"))}const Sn=new Map;class In extends De{constructor(e,t){super(),this._parent=t,this._bootstrapComponents=[],this.injector=this,this.destroyCbs=[],this.componentFactoryResolver=new bn(this);const r=tt(e),o=e[ve]||null;o&&Wn(o),this._bootstrapComponents=ar(r.bootstrap),this._r3Injector=hs(e,t,[{provide:De,useValue:this},{provide:zs,useValue:this.componentFactoryResolver}],ie(e)),this._r3Injector._resolveInjectorDefTypes(),this.instance=this.get(e)}get(e,t=ws.THROW_IF_NOT_FOUND,r=$.Default){return e===ws||e===De||e===Qe?this:this._r3Injector.get(e,t,r)}destroy(){const e=this._r3Injector;!e.destroyed&&e.destroy(),this.destroyCbs.forEach(e=>e()),this.destroyCbs=null}onDestroy(e){this.destroyCbs.push(e)}}class xn extends class{}{constructor(e){super(),this.moduleType=e,null!==tt(e)&&function e(t){if(null!==t.\u0275mod.id){const e=t.\u0275mod.id;(function(e,t,r){if(t&&t!==r)throw new Error(`Duplicate module registered for ${e} - ${ie(t)} vs ${ie(t.name)}`)})(e,Sn.get(e),t),Sn.set(e,t)}let r=t.\u0275mod.imports;r instanceof Function&&(r=r()),r&&r.forEach(t=>e(t))}(e)}create(e){return new In(this.moduleType,e)}}class Bn extends T{constructor(e=!1){super(),this.__isAsync=e}emit(e){super.next(e)}subscribe(e,t,r){let o,s=e=>null,n=()=>null;e&&"object"==typeof e?(o=this.__isAsync?t=>{setTimeout(()=>e.next(t))}:t=>{e.next(t)},e.error&&(s=this.__isAsync?t=>{setTimeout(()=>e.error(t))}:t=>{e.error(t)}),e.complete&&(n=this.__isAsync?()=>{setTimeout(()=>e.complete())}:()=>{e.complete()})):(o=this.__isAsync?t=>{setTimeout(()=>e(t))}:t=>{e(t)},t&&(s=this.__isAsync?e=>{setTimeout(()=>t(e))}:e=>{t(e)}),r&&(n=this.__isAsync?()=>{setTimeout(()=>r())}:()=>{r()}));const i=super.subscribe(o,s,n);return e instanceof u&&e.add(i),i}}const jn=new Te("Application Initializer");let Cn=(()=>{class e{constructor(e){this.appInits=e,this.initialized=!1,this.done=!1,this.donePromise=new Promise((e,t)=>{this.resolve=e,this.reject=t})}runInitializers(){if(this.initialized)return;const e=[],t=()=>{this.done=!0,this.resolve()};if(this.appInits)for(let r=0;r<this.appInits.length;r++){const t=this.appInits[r]();Ps(t)&&e.push(t)}Promise.all(e).then(()=>{t()}).catch(e=>{this.reject(e)}),0===e.length&&t(),this.initialized=!0}}return e.\u0275fac=function(t){return new(t||e)(Ce(jn,8))},e.\u0275prov=Y({token:e,factory:e.\u0275fac}),e})();const Pn=new Te("AppId"),En={provide:Pn,useFactory:function(){return`${On()}${On()}${On()}`},deps:[]};function On(){return String.fromCharCode(97+Math.floor(25*Math.random()))}const Dn=new Te("Platform Initializer"),Mn=new Te("Platform ID"),Hn=new Te("appBootstrapListener");let Nn=(()=>{class e{log(e){console.log(e)}warn(e){console.warn(e)}}return e.\u0275fac=function(t){return new(t||e)},e.\u0275prov=Y({token:e,factory:e.\u0275fac}),e})();const zn=new Te("LocaleId"),qn=new Te("DefaultCurrencyCode");class Rn{constructor(e,t){this.ngModuleFactory=e,this.componentFactories=t}}const Vn=function(e){return new xn(e)},Ln=Vn,Un=function(e){return Promise.resolve(Vn(e))},Zn=function(e){const t=Vn(e),r=ar(tt(e).declarations).reduce((e,t)=>{const r=Xe(t);return r&&e.push(new kn(r)),e},[]);return new Rn(t,r)},$n=Zn,Gn=function(e){return Promise.resolve(Zn(e))};let Yn=(()=>{class e{constructor(){this.compileModuleSync=Ln,this.compileModuleAsync=Un,this.compileModuleAndAllComponentsSync=$n,this.compileModuleAndAllComponentsAsync=Gn}clearCache(){}clearCacheFor(e){}getModuleId(e){}}return e.\u0275fac=function(t){return new(t||e)},e.\u0275prov=Y({token:e,factory:e.\u0275fac}),e})();const Jn=new Te("compilerOptions"),Kn=(()=>Promise.resolve(0))();function Xn(e){"undefined"==typeof Zone?Kn.then(()=>{e&&e.apply(null,null)}):Zone.current.scheduleMicroTask("scheduleMicrotask",e)}class ei{constructor({enableLongStackTrace:e=!1,shouldCoalesceEventChangeDetection:t=!1}){if(this.hasPendingMacrotasks=!1,this.hasPendingMicrotasks=!1,this.isStable=!0,this.onUnstable=new Bn(!1),this.onMicrotaskEmpty=new Bn(!1),this.onStable=new Bn(!1),this.onError=new Bn(!1),"undefined"==typeof Zone)throw new Error("In this configuration Angular requires Zone.js");Zone.assertZonePatched(),this._nesting=0,this._outer=this._inner=Zone.current,Zone.wtfZoneSpec&&(this._inner=this._inner.fork(Zone.wtfZoneSpec)),Zone.TaskTrackingZoneSpec&&(this._inner=this._inner.fork(new Zone.TaskTrackingZoneSpec)),e&&Zone.longStackTraceZoneSpec&&(this._inner=this._inner.fork(Zone.longStackTraceZoneSpec)),this.shouldCoalesceEventChangeDetection=t,this.lastRequestAnimationFrameId=-1,this.nativeRequestAnimationFrame=function(){let e=fe.requestAnimationFrame,t=fe.cancelAnimationFrame;if("undefined"!=typeof Zone&&e&&t){const r=e[Zone.__symbol__("OriginalDelegate")];r&&(e=r);const o=t[Zone.__symbol__("OriginalDelegate")];o&&(t=o)}return{nativeRequestAnimationFrame:e,nativeCancelAnimationFrame:t}}().nativeRequestAnimationFrame,function(e){const t=!!e.shouldCoalesceEventChangeDetection&&e.nativeRequestAnimationFrame&&(()=>{!function(e){-1===e.lastRequestAnimationFrameId&&(e.lastRequestAnimationFrameId=e.nativeRequestAnimationFrame.call(fe,()=>{e.lastRequestAnimationFrameId=-1,si(e),oi(e)}),si(e))}(e)});e._inner=e._inner.fork({name:"angular",properties:{isAngularZone:!0,maybeDelayChangeDetection:t},onInvokeTask:(r,o,s,n,i,a)=>{try{return ni(e),r.invokeTask(s,n,i,a)}finally{t&&"eventTask"===n.type&&t(),ii(e)}},onInvoke:(t,r,o,s,n,i,a)=>{try{return ni(e),t.invoke(o,s,n,i,a)}finally{ii(e)}},onHasTask:(t,r,o,s)=>{t.hasTask(o,s),r===o&&("microTask"==s.change?(e._hasPendingMicrotasks=s.microTask,si(e),oi(e)):"macroTask"==s.change&&(e.hasPendingMacrotasks=s.macroTask))},onHandleError:(t,r,o,s)=>(t.handleError(o,s),e.runOutsideAngular(()=>e.onError.emit(s)),!1)})}(this)}static isInAngularZone(){return!0===Zone.current.get("isAngularZone")}static assertInAngularZone(){if(!ei.isInAngularZone())throw new Error("Expected to be in Angular Zone, but it is not!")}static assertNotInAngularZone(){if(ei.isInAngularZone())throw new Error("Expected to not be in Angular Zone, but it is!")}run(e,t,r){return this._inner.run(e,t,r)}runTask(e,t,r,o){const s=this._inner,n=s.scheduleEventTask("NgZoneEvent: "+o,e,ri,ti,ti);try{return s.runTask(n,t,r)}finally{s.cancelTask(n)}}runGuarded(e,t,r){return this._inner.runGuarded(e,t,r)}runOutsideAngular(e){return this._outer.run(e)}}function ti(){}const ri={};function oi(e){if(0==e._nesting&&!e.hasPendingMicrotasks&&!e.isStable)try{e._nesting++,e.onMicrotaskEmpty.emit(null)}finally{if(e._nesting--,!e.hasPendingMicrotasks)try{e.runOutsideAngular(()=>e.onStable.emit(null))}finally{e.isStable=!0}}}function si(e){e.hasPendingMicrotasks=!!(e._hasPendingMicrotasks||e.shouldCoalesceEventChangeDetection&&-1!==e.lastRequestAnimationFrameId)}function ni(e){e._nesting++,e.isStable&&(e.isStable=!1,e.onUnstable.emit(null))}function ii(e){e._nesting--,oi(e)}class ai{constructor(){this.hasPendingMicrotasks=!1,this.hasPendingMacrotasks=!1,this.isStable=!0,this.onUnstable=new Bn,this.onMicrotaskEmpty=new Bn,this.onStable=new Bn,this.onError=new Bn}run(e,t,r){return e.apply(t,r)}runGuarded(e,t,r){return e.apply(t,r)}runOutsideAngular(e){return e()}runTask(e,t,r,o){return e.apply(t,r)}}let ci=(()=>{class e{constructor(e){this._ngZone=e,this._pendingCount=0,this._isZoneStable=!0,this._didWork=!1,this._callbacks=[],this.taskTrackingZone=null,this._watchAngularEvents(),e.run(()=>{this.taskTrackingZone="undefined"==typeof Zone?null:Zone.current.get("TaskTrackingZone")})}_watchAngularEvents(){this._ngZone.onUnstable.subscribe({next:()=>{this._didWork=!0,this._isZoneStable=!1}}),this._ngZone.runOutsideAngular(()=>{this._ngZone.onStable.subscribe({next:()=>{ei.assertNotInAngularZone(),Xn(()=>{this._isZoneStable=!0,this._runCallbacksIfReady()})}})})}increasePendingRequestCount(){return this._pendingCount+=1,this._didWork=!0,this._pendingCount}decreasePendingRequestCount(){if(this._pendingCount-=1,this._pendingCount<0)throw new Error("pending async requests below zero");return this._runCallbacksIfReady(),this._pendingCount}isStable(){return this._isZoneStable&&0===this._pendingCount&&!this._ngZone.hasPendingMacrotasks}_runCallbacksIfReady(){if(this.isStable())Xn(()=>{for(;0!==this._callbacks.length;){let e=this._callbacks.pop();clearTimeout(e.timeoutId),e.doneCb(this._didWork)}this._didWork=!1});else{let e=this.getPendingTasks();this._callbacks=this._callbacks.filter(t=>!t.updateCb||!t.updateCb(e)||(clearTimeout(t.timeoutId),!1)),this._didWork=!0}}getPendingTasks(){return this.taskTrackingZone?this.taskTrackingZone.macroTasks.map(e=>({source:e.source,creationLocation:e.creationLocation,data:e.data})):[]}addCallback(e,t,r){let o=-1;t&&t>0&&(o=setTimeout(()=>{this._callbacks=this._callbacks.filter(e=>e.timeoutId!==o),e(this._didWork,this.getPendingTasks())},t)),this._callbacks.push({doneCb:e,timeoutId:o,updateCb:r})}whenStable(e,t,r){if(r&&!this.taskTrackingZone)throw new Error('Task tracking zone is required when passing an update callback to whenStable(). Is "zone.js/dist/task-tracking.js" loaded?');this.addCallback(e,t,r),this._runCallbacksIfReady()}getPendingRequestCount(){return this._pendingCount}findProviders(e,t,r){return[]}}return e.\u0275fac=function(t){return new(t||e)(Ce(ei))},e.\u0275prov=Y({token:e,factory:e.\u0275fac}),e})(),li=(()=>{class e{constructor(){this._applications=new Map,di.addToWindow(this)}registerApplication(e,t){this._applications.set(e,t)}unregisterApplication(e){this._applications.delete(e)}unregisterAllApplications(){this._applications.clear()}getTestability(e){return this._applications.get(e)||null}getAllTestabilities(){return Array.from(this._applications.values())}getAllRootElements(){return Array.from(this._applications.keys())}findTestabilityInTree(e,t=!0){return di.findTestabilityInTree(this,e,t)}}return e.\u0275fac=function(t){return new(t||e)},e.\u0275prov=Y({token:e,factory:e.\u0275fac}),e})();class hi{addToWindow(e){}findTestabilityInTree(e,t,r){return null}}let ui,di=new hi,pi=function(e,t,r){const o=e.get(Jn,[]).concat(t),s=new xn(r);if(0===gs.size)return Promise.resolve(s);const n=function(e){const t=[];return e.forEach(e=>e&&t.push(...e)),t}(o.map(e=>e.providers));if(0===n.length)return Promise.resolve(s);const i=function(){const e=fe.ng;if(!e||!e.\u0275compilerFacade)throw new Error("Angular JIT compilation failed: '@angular/compiler' not loaded!\n  - JIT compilation is discouraged for production use-cases! Consider AOT mode instead.\n  - Did you bootstrap using '@angular/platform-browser-dynamic' or '@angular/platform-server'?\n  - Alternatively provide the compiler with 'import \"@angular/compiler\";' before bootstrapping.");return e.\u0275compilerFacade}(),a=ws.create({providers:n}).get(i.ResourceLoader);return function(e){const t=[],r=new Map;function o(e){let t=r.get(e);if(!t){const o=(e=>Promise.resolve(a.get(e)))(e);r.set(e,t=o.then(vs))}return t}return gs.forEach((e,r)=>{const s=[];e.templateUrl&&s.push(o(e.templateUrl).then(t=>{e.template=t}));const n=e.styleUrls,i=e.styles||(e.styles=[]),a=e.styles.length;n&&n.forEach((t,r)=>{i.push(""),s.push(o(t).then(o=>{i[a+r]=o,n.splice(n.indexOf(t),1),0==n.length&&(e.styleUrls=void 0)}))});const c=Promise.all(s).then(()=>function(e){ks.delete(e)}(r));t.push(c)}),gs=new Map,Promise.all(t).then(()=>{})}().then(()=>s)};const mi=new Te("AllowMultipleToken");function fi(e,t,r=[]){const o="Platform: "+t,s=new Te(o);return(t=[])=>{let n=bi();if(!n||n.injector.get(mi,!1))if(e)e(r.concat(t).concat({provide:s,useValue:!0}));else{const e=r.concat(t).concat({provide:s,useValue:!0},{provide:ss,useValue:"platform"});!function(e){if(ui&&!ui.destroyed&&!ui.injector.get(mi,!1))throw new Error("There can be only one platform. Destroy the previous one to create a new one.");ui=e.get(wi);const t=e.get(Dn,null);t&&t.forEach(e=>e())}(ws.create({providers:e,name:o}))}return function(e){const t=bi();if(!t)throw new Error("No platform exists!");if(!t.injector.get(e,null))throw new Error("A platform with a different configuration has been created. Please destroy it first.");return t}(s)}}function bi(){return ui&&!ui.destroyed?ui:null}let wi=(()=>{class e{constructor(e){this._injector=e,this._modules=[],this._destroyListeners=[],this._destroyed=!1}bootstrapModuleFactory(e,t){const r=function(e,t){let r;return r="noop"===e?new ai:("zone.js"===e?void 0:e)||new ei({enableLongStackTrace:Ir(),shouldCoalesceEventChangeDetection:t}),r}(t?t.ngZone:void 0,t&&t.ngZoneEventCoalescing||!1),o=[{provide:ei,useValue:r}];return r.run(()=>{const t=ws.create({providers:o,parent:this.injector,name:e.moduleType.name}),s=e.create(t),n=s.injector.get(Fr,null);if(!n)throw new Error("No ErrorHandler. Is platform module (BrowserModule) included?");return s.onDestroy(()=>vi(this._modules,s)),r.runOutsideAngular(()=>r.onError.subscribe({next:e=>{n.handleError(e)}})),function(e,t,r){try{const o=r();return Ps(o)?o.catch(r=>{throw t.runOutsideAngular(()=>e.handleError(r)),r}):o}catch(o){throw t.runOutsideAngular(()=>e.handleError(o)),o}}(n,r,()=>{const e=s.injector.get(Cn);return e.runInitializers(),e.donePromise.then(()=>(Wn(s.injector.get(zn,"en-US")||"en-US"),this._moduleDoBootstrap(s),s))})})}bootstrapModule(e,t=[]){const r=gi({},t);return pi(this.injector,r,e).then(e=>this.bootstrapModuleFactory(e,r))}_moduleDoBootstrap(e){const t=e.injector.get(ki);if(e._bootstrapComponents.length>0)e._bootstrapComponents.forEach(e=>t.bootstrap(e));else{if(!e.instance.ngDoBootstrap)throw new Error(`The module ${ie(e.instance.constructor)} was bootstrapped, but it does not declare "@NgModule.bootstrap" components nor a "ngDoBootstrap" method. Please define one of these.`);e.instance.ngDoBootstrap(t)}this._modules.push(e)}onDestroy(e){this._destroyListeners.push(e)}get injector(){return this._injector}destroy(){if(this._destroyed)throw new Error("The platform has already been destroyed!");this._modules.slice().forEach(e=>e.destroy()),this._destroyListeners.forEach(e=>e()),this._destroyed=!0}get destroyed(){return this._destroyed}}return e.\u0275fac=function(t){return new(t||e)(Ce(ws))},e.\u0275prov=Y({token:e,factory:e.\u0275fac}),e})();function gi(e,t){return Array.isArray(t)?t.reduce(gi,e):Object.assign(Object.assign({},e),t)}let ki=(()=>{class e{constructor(e,t,r,o,s,n){this._zone=e,this._console=t,this._injector=r,this._exceptionHandler=o,this._componentFactoryResolver=s,this._initStatus=n,this._bootstrapListeners=[],this._views=[],this._runningTick=!1,this._enforceNoNewChanges=!1,this._stable=!0,this.componentTypes=[],this.components=[],this._enforceNoNewChanges=Ir(),this._zone.onMicrotaskEmpty.subscribe({next:()=>{this._zone.run(()=>{this.tick()})}});const i=new g(e=>{this._stable=this._zone.isStable&&!this._zone.hasPendingMacrotasks&&!this._zone.hasPendingMicrotasks,this._zone.runOutsideAngular(()=>{e.next(this._stable),e.complete()})}),a=new g(e=>{let t;this._zone.runOutsideAngular(()=>{t=this._zone.onStable.subscribe(()=>{ei.assertNotInAngularZone(),Xn(()=>{this._stable||this._zone.hasPendingMacrotasks||this._zone.hasPendingMicrotasks||(this._stable=!0,e.next(!0))})})});const r=this._zone.onUnstable.subscribe(()=>{ei.assertInAngularZone(),this._stable&&(this._stable=!1,this._zone.runOutsideAngular(()=>{e.next(!1)}))});return()=>{t.unsubscribe(),r.unsubscribe()}});this.isStable=function(...e){let t=Number.POSITIVE_INFINITY,r=null,o=e[e.length-1];var s;return(s=o)&&"function"==typeof s.schedule?(r=e.pop(),e.length>1&&"number"==typeof e[e.length-1]&&(t=e.pop())):"number"==typeof o&&(t=e.pop()),null===r&&1===e.length&&e[0]instanceof g?e[0]:function(e=Number.POSITIVE_INFINITY){return function e(t,r,o=Number.POSITIVE_INFINITY){return"function"==typeof r?s=>s.pipe(e((e,o)=>{return(s=t(e,o),s instanceof g?s:new g(I(s))).pipe(function(e,t){return function(t){return t.lift(new B(e,void 0))}}((t,s)=>r(e,t,o,s)));var s},o)):("number"==typeof r&&(o=r),e=>e.lift(new C(t,o)))}(w,e)}(t)(function(e,t){return t?function(e,t){return new g(r=>{const o=new u;let s=0;return o.add(t.schedule((function(){s!==e.length?(r.next(e[s++]),r.closed||o.add(this.schedule())):r.complete()}))),o})}(e,t):new g(F(e))}(e,r))}(i,a.pipe(e=>{return E()((t=z,function(e){let r;r="function"==typeof t?t:function(){return t};const o=Object.create(e,H);return o.source=e,o.subjectFactory=r,o})(e));var t}))}bootstrap(e,t){if(!this._initStatus.done)throw new Error("Cannot bootstrap as there are still asynchronous initializers running. Bootstrap components in the `ngDoBootstrap` method of the root module.");let r;r=e instanceof Hs?e:this._componentFactoryResolver.resolveComponentFactory(e),this.componentTypes.push(r.componentType);const o=r.isBoundToModule?void 0:this._injector.get(De),s=r.create(ws.NULL,[],t||r.selector,o);s.onDestroy(()=>{this._unloadComponent(s)});const n=s.injector.get(ci,null);return n&&s.injector.get(li).registerApplication(s.location.nativeElement,n),this._loadComponent(s),Ir()&&this._console.log("Angular is running in the development mode. Call enableProdMode() to enable the production mode."),s}tick(){if(this._runningTick)throw new Error("ApplicationRef.tick is called recursively");try{this._runningTick=!0;for(let e of this._views)e.detectChanges();if(this._enforceNoNewChanges)for(let e of this._views)e.checkNoChanges()}catch(e){this._zone.runOutsideAngular(()=>this._exceptionHandler.handleError(e))}finally{this._runningTick=!1}}attachView(e){const t=e;this._views.push(t),t.attachToAppRef(this)}detachView(e){const t=e;vi(this._views,t),t.detachFromAppRef()}_loadComponent(e){this.attachView(e.hostView),this.tick(),this.components.push(e),this._injector.get(Hn,[]).concat(this._bootstrapListeners).forEach(t=>t(e))}_unloadComponent(e){this.detachView(e.hostView),vi(this.components,e)}ngOnDestroy(){this._views.slice().forEach(e=>e.destroy())}get viewCount(){return this._views.length}}return e.\u0275fac=function(t){return new(t||e)(Ce(ei),Ce(Nn),Ce(ws),Ce(Fr),Ce(zs),Ce(Cn))},e.\u0275prov=Y({token:e,factory:e.\u0275fac}),e})();function vi(e,t){const r=e.indexOf(t);r>-1&&e.splice(r,1)}const Ai=fi(null,"core",[{provide:Mn,useValue:"unknown"},{provide:wi,deps:[ws]},{provide:li,deps:[]},{provide:Nn,deps:[]}]),yi=[{provide:ki,useClass:ki,deps:[ei,Nn,ws,Fr,zs,Cn]},{provide:gn,deps:[ei],useFactory:function(e){let t=[];return e.onStable.subscribe(()=>{for(;t.length;)t.pop()()}),function(e){t.push(e)}}},{provide:Cn,useClass:Cn,deps:[[new L,jn]]},{provide:Yn,useClass:Yn,deps:[]},En,{provide:nn,useFactory:function(){return ln},deps:[]},{provide:an,useFactory:function(){return hn},deps:[]},{provide:zn,useFactory:function(e){return Wn(e=e||"undefined"!=typeof $localize&&$localize.locale||"en-US"),e},deps:[[new V(zn),new L,new Z]]},{provide:qn,useValue:"USD"}];let Ti=(()=>{class e{constructor(e){}}return e.\u0275mod=Ye({type:e}),e.\u0275inj=J({factory:function(t){return new(t||e)(Ce(ki))},providers:yi}),e})(),Qi=null;function _i(){return Qi}const Fi=new Te("DocumentToken"),Wi=function(){var e={Zero:0,One:1,Two:2,Few:3,Many:4,Other:5};return e[e.Zero]="Zero",e[e.One]="One",e[e.Two]="Two",e[e.Few]="Few",e[e.Many]="Many",e[e.Other]="Other",e}();class Si{}let Ii=(()=>{class e extends Si{constructor(e){super(),this.locale=e}getPluralCategory(e,t){switch(function(e){return function(e){const t=function(e){return e.toLowerCase().replace(/_/g,"-")}(e);let r=Qn(t);if(r)return r;const o=t.split("-")[0];if(r=Qn(o),r)return r;if("en"===o)return yn;throw new Error(`Missing locale data for the locale "${e}".`)}(e)[_n.PluralCase]}(t||this.locale)(e)){case Wi.Zero:return"zero";case Wi.One:return"one";case Wi.Two:return"two";case Wi.Few:return"few";case Wi.Many:return"many";default:return"other"}}}return e.\u0275fac=function(t){return new(t||e)(Ce(zn))},e.\u0275prov=Y({token:e,factory:e.\u0275fac}),e})();class xi{constructor(e,t,r,o){this.$implicit=e,this.ngForOf=t,this.index=r,this.count=o}get first(){return 0===this.index}get last(){return this.index===this.count-1}get even(){return this.index%2==0}get odd(){return!this.even}}let Bi=(()=>{class e{constructor(e,t,r){this._viewContainer=e,this._template=t,this._differs=r,this._ngForOf=null,this._ngForOfDirty=!0,this._differ=null}set ngForOf(e){this._ngForOf=e,this._ngForOfDirty=!0}set ngForTrackBy(e){Ir()&&null!=e&&"function"!=typeof e&&console&&console.warn&&console.warn(`trackBy must be a function, but received ${JSON.stringify(e)}. See https://angular.io/api/common/NgForOf#change-propagation for more information.`),this._trackByFn=e}get ngForTrackBy(){return this._trackByFn}set ngForTemplate(e){e&&(this._template=e)}ngDoCheck(){if(this._ngForOfDirty){this._ngForOfDirty=!1;const r=this._ngForOf;if(!this._differ&&r)try{this._differ=this._differs.find(r).create(this.ngForTrackBy)}catch(t){throw new Error(`Cannot find a differ supporting object '${r}' of type '${e=r,e.name||typeof e}'. NgFor only supports binding to Iterables such as Arrays.`)}}var e;if(this._differ){const e=this._differ.diff(this._ngForOf);e&&this._applyChanges(e)}}_applyChanges(e){const t=[];e.forEachOperation((e,r,o)=>{if(null==e.previousIndex){const r=this._viewContainer.createEmbeddedView(this._template,new xi(null,this._ngForOf,-1,-1),null===o?void 0:o),s=new ji(e,r);t.push(s)}else if(null==o)this._viewContainer.remove(null===r?void 0:r);else if(null!==r){const s=this._viewContainer.get(r);this._viewContainer.move(s,o);const n=new ji(e,s);t.push(n)}});for(let r=0;r<t.length;r++)this._perViewChange(t[r].view,t[r].record);for(let r=0,o=this._viewContainer.length;r<o;r++){const e=this._viewContainer.get(r);e.context.index=r,e.context.count=o,e.context.ngForOf=this._ngForOf}e.forEachIdentityChange(e=>{this._viewContainer.get(e.currentIndex).context.$implicit=e.item})}_perViewChange(e,t){e.context.$implicit=t.item}static ngTemplateContextGuard(e,t){return!0}}return e.\u0275fac=function(t){return new(t||e)(Is(pn),Is(un),Is(nn))},e.\u0275dir=Ke({type:e,selectors:[["","ngFor","","ngForOf",""]],inputs:{ngForOf:"ngForOf",ngForTrackBy:"ngForTrackBy",ngForTemplate:"ngForTemplate"}}),e})();class ji{constructor(e,t){this.record=e,this.view=t}}let Ci=(()=>{class e{}return e.\u0275mod=Ye({type:e}),e.\u0275inj=J({factory:function(t){return new(t||e)},providers:[{provide:Si,useClass:Ii}]}),e})();class Pi extends class extends class{}{constructor(){super()}supportsDOMEvents(){return!0}}{static makeCurrent(){var e;e=new Pi,Qi||(Qi=e)}getProperty(e,t){return e[t]}log(e){window.console&&window.console.log&&window.console.log(e)}logGroup(e){window.console&&window.console.group&&window.console.group(e)}logGroupEnd(){window.console&&window.console.groupEnd&&window.console.groupEnd()}onAndCancel(e,t,r){return e.addEventListener(t,r,!1),()=>{e.removeEventListener(t,r,!1)}}dispatchEvent(e,t){e.dispatchEvent(t)}remove(e){return e.parentNode&&e.parentNode.removeChild(e),e}getValue(e){return e.value}createElement(e,t){return(t=t||this.getDefaultDocument()).createElement(e)}createHtmlDocument(){return document.implementation.createHTMLDocument("fakeTitle")}getDefaultDocument(){return document}isElementNode(e){return e.nodeType===Node.ELEMENT_NODE}isShadowRoot(e){return e instanceof DocumentFragment}getGlobalEventTarget(e,t){return"window"===t?window:"document"===t?e:"body"===t?e.body:null}getHistory(){return window.history}getLocation(){return window.location}getBaseHref(e){const t=Oi||(Oi=document.querySelector("base"),Oi)?Oi.getAttribute("href"):null;return null==t?null:(r=t,Ei||(Ei=document.createElement("a")),Ei.setAttribute("href",r),"/"===Ei.pathname.charAt(0)?Ei.pathname:"/"+Ei.pathname);var r}resetBaseElement(){Oi=null}getUserAgent(){return window.navigator.userAgent}performanceNow(){return window.performance&&window.performance.now?window.performance.now():(new Date).getTime()}supportsCookies(){return!0}getCookie(e){return function(e,t){t=encodeURIComponent(t);for(const r of e.split(";")){const e=r.indexOf("="),[o,s]=-1==e?[r,""]:[r.slice(0,e),r.slice(e+1)];if(o.trim()===t)return decodeURIComponent(s)}return null}(document.cookie,e)}}let Ei,Oi=null;const Di=new Te("TRANSITION_ID"),Mi=[{provide:jn,useFactory:function(e,t,r){return()=>{r.get(Cn).donePromise.then(()=>{const r=_i();Array.prototype.slice.apply(t.querySelectorAll("style[ng-transition]")).filter(t=>t.getAttribute("ng-transition")===e).forEach(e=>r.remove(e))})}},deps:[Di,Fi,ws],multi:!0}];class Hi{static init(){var e;e=new Hi,di=e}addToWindow(e){fe.getAngularTestability=(t,r=!0)=>{const o=e.findTestabilityInTree(t,r);if(null==o)throw new Error("Could not find testability for element.");return o},fe.getAllAngularTestabilities=()=>e.getAllTestabilities(),fe.getAllAngularRootElements=()=>e.getAllRootElements(),fe.frameworkStabilizers||(fe.frameworkStabilizers=[]),fe.frameworkStabilizers.push(e=>{const t=fe.getAllAngularTestabilities();let r=t.length,o=!1;const s=function(t){o=o||t,r--,0==r&&e(o)};t.forEach((function(e){e.whenStable(s)}))})}findTestabilityInTree(e,t,r){if(null==t)return null;const o=e.getTestability(t);return null!=o?o:r?_i().isShadowRoot(t)?this.findTestabilityInTree(e,t.host,!0):this.findTestabilityInTree(e,t.parentElement,!0):null}}const Ni=new Te("EventManagerPlugins");let zi=(()=>{class e{constructor(e,t){this._zone=t,this._eventNameToPlugin=new Map,e.forEach(e=>e.manager=this),this._plugins=e.slice().reverse()}addEventListener(e,t,r){return this._findPluginFor(t).addEventListener(e,t,r)}addGlobalEventListener(e,t,r){return this._findPluginFor(t).addGlobalEventListener(e,t,r)}getZone(){return this._zone}_findPluginFor(e){const t=this._eventNameToPlugin.get(e);if(t)return t;const r=this._plugins;for(let o=0;o<r.length;o++){const t=r[o];if(t.supports(e))return this._eventNameToPlugin.set(e,t),t}throw new Error("No event manager plugin found for event "+e)}}return e.\u0275fac=function(t){return new(t||e)(Ce(Ni),Ce(ei))},e.\u0275prov=Y({token:e,factory:e.\u0275fac}),e})();class qi{constructor(e){this._doc=e}addGlobalEventListener(e,t,r){const o=_i().getGlobalEventTarget(this._doc,e);if(!o)throw new Error(`Unsupported event target ${o} for event ${t}`);return this.addEventListener(o,t,r)}}let Ri=(()=>{class e{constructor(){this._stylesSet=new Set}addStyles(e){const t=new Set;e.forEach(e=>{this._stylesSet.has(e)||(this._stylesSet.add(e),t.add(e))}),this.onStylesAdded(t)}onStylesAdded(e){}getAllStyles(){return Array.from(this._stylesSet)}}return e.\u0275fac=function(t){return new(t||e)},e.\u0275prov=Y({token:e,factory:e.\u0275fac}),e})(),Vi=(()=>{class e extends Ri{constructor(e){super(),this._doc=e,this._hostNodes=new Set,this._styleNodes=new Set,this._hostNodes.add(e.head)}_addStylesToHost(e,t){e.forEach(e=>{const r=this._doc.createElement("style");r.textContent=e,this._styleNodes.add(t.appendChild(r))})}addHost(e){this._addStylesToHost(this._stylesSet,e),this._hostNodes.add(e)}removeHost(e){this._hostNodes.delete(e)}onStylesAdded(e){this._hostNodes.forEach(t=>this._addStylesToHost(e,t))}ngOnDestroy(){this._styleNodes.forEach(e=>_i().remove(e))}}return e.\u0275fac=function(t){return new(t||e)(Ce(Fi))},e.\u0275prov=Y({token:e,factory:e.\u0275fac}),e})();const Li={svg:"http://www.w3.org/2000/svg",xhtml:"http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml",xlink:"http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink",xml:"http://www.w3.org/XML/1998/namespace",xmlns:"http://www.w3.org/2000/xmlns/"},Ui=/%COMP%/g;function Zi(e,t,r){for(let o=0;o<t.length;o++){let s=t[o];Array.isArray(s)?Zi(e,s,r):(s=s.replace(Ui,e),r.push(s))}return r}function $i(e){return t=>{if("__ngUnwrap__"===t)return e;!1===e(t)&&(t.preventDefault(),t.returnValue=!1)}}let Gi=(()=>{class e{constructor(e,t,r){this.eventManager=e,this.sharedStylesHost=t,this.appId=r,this.rendererByCompId=new Map,this.defaultRenderer=new Yi(e)}createRenderer(e,t){if(!e||!t)return this.defaultRenderer;switch(t.encapsulation){case qe.Emulated:{let r=this.rendererByCompId.get(t.id);return r||(r=new Ji(this.eventManager,this.sharedStylesHost,t,this.appId),this.rendererByCompId.set(t.id,r)),r.applyToHost(e),r}case qe.Native:case qe.ShadowDom:return new Ki(this.eventManager,this.sharedStylesHost,e,t);default:if(!this.rendererByCompId.has(t.id)){const e=Zi(t.id,t.styles,[]);this.sharedStylesHost.addStyles(e),this.rendererByCompId.set(t.id,this.defaultRenderer)}return this.defaultRenderer}}begin(){}end(){}}return e.\u0275fac=function(t){return new(t||e)(Ce(zi),Ce(Vi),Ce(Pn))},e.\u0275prov=Y({token:e,factory:e.\u0275fac}),e})();class Yi{constructor(e){this.eventManager=e,this.data=Object.create(null)}destroy(){}createElement(e,t){return t?document.createElementNS(Li[t]||t,e):document.createElement(e)}createComment(e){return document.createComment(e)}createText(e){return document.createTextNode(e)}appendChild(e,t){e.appendChild(t)}insertBefore(e,t,r){e&&e.insertBefore(t,r)}removeChild(e,t){e&&e.removeChild(t)}selectRootElement(e,t){let r="string"==typeof e?document.querySelector(e):e;if(!r)throw new Error(`The selector "${e}" did not match any elements`);return t||(r.textContent=""),r}parentNode(e){return e.parentNode}nextSibling(e){return e.nextSibling}setAttribute(e,t,r,o){if(o){t=o+":"+t;const s=Li[o];s?e.setAttributeNS(s,t,r):e.setAttribute(t,r)}else e.setAttribute(t,r)}removeAttribute(e,t,r){if(r){const o=Li[r];o?e.removeAttributeNS(o,t):e.removeAttribute(`${r}:${t}`)}else e.removeAttribute(t)}addClass(e,t){e.classList.add(t)}removeClass(e,t){e.classList.remove(t)}setStyle(e,t,r,o){o&Ls.DashCase?e.style.setProperty(t,r,o&Ls.Important?"important":""):e.style[t]=r}removeStyle(e,t,r){r&Ls.DashCase?e.style.removeProperty(t):e.style[t]=""}setProperty(e,t,r){e[t]=r}setValue(e,t){e.nodeValue=t}listen(e,t,r){return"string"==typeof e?this.eventManager.addGlobalEventListener(e,t,$i(r)):this.eventManager.addEventListener(e,t,$i(r))}}class Ji extends Yi{constructor(e,t,r,o){super(e),this.component=r;const s=Zi(o+"-"+r.id,r.styles,[]);t.addStyles(s),this.contentAttr="_ngcontent-%COMP%".replace(Ui,o+"-"+r.id),this.hostAttr=function(e){return"_nghost-%COMP%".replace(Ui,e)}(o+"-"+r.id)}applyToHost(e){super.setAttribute(e,this.hostAttr,"")}createElement(e,t){const r=super.createElement(e,t);return super.setAttribute(r,this.contentAttr,""),r}}class Ki extends Yi{constructor(e,t,r,o){super(e),this.sharedStylesHost=t,this.hostEl=r,this.component=o,this.shadowRoot=o.encapsulation===qe.ShadowDom?r.attachShadow({mode:"open"}):r.createShadowRoot(),this.sharedStylesHost.addHost(this.shadowRoot);const s=Zi(o.id,o.styles,[]);for(let n=0;n<s.length;n++){const e=document.createElement("style");e.textContent=s[n],this.shadowRoot.appendChild(e)}}nodeOrShadowRoot(e){return e===this.hostEl?this.shadowRoot:e}destroy(){this.sharedStylesHost.removeHost(this.shadowRoot)}appendChild(e,t){return super.appendChild(this.nodeOrShadowRoot(e),t)}insertBefore(e,t,r){return super.insertBefore(this.nodeOrShadowRoot(e),t,r)}removeChild(e,t){return super.removeChild(this.nodeOrShadowRoot(e),t)}parentNode(e){return this.nodeOrShadowRoot(super.parentNode(this.nodeOrShadowRoot(e)))}}let Xi=(()=>{class e extends qi{constructor(e){super(e)}supports(e){return!0}addEventListener(e,t,r){return e.addEventListener(t,r,!1),()=>this.removeEventListener(e,t,r)}removeEventListener(e,t,r){return e.removeEventListener(t,r)}}return e.\u0275fac=function(t){return new(t||e)(Ce(Fi))},e.\u0275prov=Y({token:e,factory:e.\u0275fac}),e})();const ea=["alt","control","meta","shift"],ta={"\b":"Backspace","\t":"Tab","\x7f":"Delete","\x1b":"Escape",Del:"Delete",Esc:"Escape",Left:"ArrowLeft",Right:"ArrowRight",Up:"ArrowUp",Down:"ArrowDown",Menu:"ContextMenu",Scroll:"ScrollLock",Win:"OS"},ra={A:"1",B:"2",C:"3",D:"4",E:"5",F:"6",G:"7",H:"8",I:"9",J:"*",K:"+",M:"-",N:".",O:"/","`":"0","\x90":"NumLock"},oa={alt:e=>e.altKey,control:e=>e.ctrlKey,meta:e=>e.metaKey,shift:e=>e.shiftKey};let sa=(()=>{class e extends qi{constructor(e){super(e)}supports(t){return null!=e.parseEventName(t)}addEventListener(t,r,o){const s=e.parseEventName(r),n=e.eventCallback(s.fullKey,o,this.manager.getZone());return this.manager.getZone().runOutsideAngular(()=>_i().onAndCancel(t,s.domEventName,n))}static parseEventName(t){const r=t.toLowerCase().split("."),o=r.shift();if(0===r.length||"keydown"!==o&&"keyup"!==o)return null;const s=e._normalizeKey(r.pop());let n="";if(ea.forEach(e=>{const t=r.indexOf(e);t>-1&&(r.splice(t,1),n+=e+".")}),n+=s,0!=r.length||0===s.length)return null;const i={};return i.domEventName=o,i.fullKey=n,i}static getEventFullKey(e){let t="",r=function(e){let t=e.key;if(null==t){if(t=e.keyIdentifier,null==t)return"Unidentified";t.startsWith("U+")&&(t=String.fromCharCode(parseInt(t.substring(2),16)),3===e.location&&ra.hasOwnProperty(t)&&(t=ra[t]))}return ta[t]||t}(e);return r=r.toLowerCase()," "===r?r="space":"."===r&&(r="dot"),ea.forEach(o=>{o!=r&&(0,oa[o])(e)&&(t+=o+".")}),t+=r,t}static eventCallback(t,r,o){return s=>{e.getEventFullKey(s)===t&&o.runGuarded(()=>r(s))}}static _normalizeKey(e){switch(e){case"esc":return"escape";default:return e}}}return e.\u0275fac=function(t){return new(t||e)(Ce(Fi))},e.\u0275prov=Y({token:e,factory:e.\u0275fac}),e})();const na=fi(Ai,"browser",[{provide:Mn,useValue:"browser"},{provide:Dn,useValue:function(){Pi.makeCurrent(),Hi.init()},multi:!0},{provide:Fi,useFactory:function(){return function(e){lt=e}(document),document},deps:[]}]),ia=[[],{provide:ss,useValue:"root"},{provide:Fr,useFactory:function(){return new Fr},deps:[]},{provide:Ni,useClass:Xi,multi:!0,deps:[Fi,ei,Mn]},{provide:Ni,useClass:sa,multi:!0,deps:[Fi]},[],{provide:Gi,useClass:Gi,deps:[zi,Vi,Pn]},{provide:Vs,useExisting:Gi},{provide:Ri,useExisting:Vi},{provide:Vi,useClass:Vi,deps:[Fi]},{provide:ci,useClass:ci,deps:[ei]},{provide:zi,useClass:zi,deps:[Ni,ei]},[]];let aa=(()=>{class e{constructor(e){if(e)throw new Error("BrowserModule has already been loaded. If you need access to common directives such as NgIf and NgFor from a lazy loaded module, import CommonModule instead.")}static withServerTransition(t){return{ngModule:e,providers:[{provide:Pn,useValue:t.appId},{provide:Di,useExisting:Pn},Mi]}}}return e.\u0275mod=Ye({type:e}),e.\u0275inj=J({factory:function(t){return new(t||e)(Ce(e,12))},providers:ia,imports:[Ci,Ti]}),e})();"undefined"!=typeof window&&window;var ca=r("Gz50"),la=r.t(ca,2);function ha(e,t){if(1&e&&(js(0,"div"),js(1,"div",11),js(2,"label",12),js(3,"input",13,void 0),Cs(),js(4,"span"),Es(5),Cs(),Cs(),Cs(),Cs()),2&e){const e=t.$implicit;$r(5),Os(e)}}function ua(e,t){if(1&e&&(js(0,"div"),js(1,"div",4),js(2,"div",7),js(3,"h3",8),Es(4),Cs(),js(5,"h5",9),Es(6),Cs(),Cs(),Ss(7,ha,6,1,"div",6),js(8,"div",10),Es(9),Cs(),Cs(),Cs()),2&e){const e=t.$implicit,r=t.index;$r(4),Ds("Q.",r+1,""),$r(2),Os(e.Question),$r(1),xs("ngForOf",e.options),$r(2),Ds("Correct Answer : ",e.correctAnswer,"")}}let da=(()=>{class e{constructor(){this.title="ManitobaAirBrake",this.data=[],console.log("json data"),console.log(la);let e=ca.map(e=>JSON.stringify(e));const t=[...new Set(e)];this.data=t.map(e=>JSON.parse(e))}ngOnInit(){}}return e.\u0275fac=function(t){return new(t||e)},e.\u0275cmp=Ue({type:e,selectors:[["app-root"]],decls:9,vars:1,consts:[[1,"container","mt-5"],[1,"d-flex","justify-content-center","row"],[1,"col-md-10","col-lg-10"],[1,"border"],[1,"question","bg-white","p-3","border-bottom"],[1,"d-flex","flex-row","justify-content-between","align-items-center","mcq"],[4,"ngFor","ngForOf"],[1,"d-flex","flex-row","align-items-center","question-title"],[1,"text-danger"],[1,"mt-1","ml-2"],[1,"d-flex","flex-row","justify-content-between","align-items-center","p-3","bg-white"],[1,"ans","ml-2"],[1,"radio"],["type","radio"]],template:function(e,t){1&e&&(js(0,"div",0),js(1,"div",1),js(2,"div",2),js(3,"div",3),js(4,"div",4),js(5,"div",5),js(6,"h4"),Es(7," Manitoba Air Brake Question "),Cs(),Cs(),Cs(),Ss(8,ua,10,4,"div",6),Cs(),Cs(),Cs(),Cs()),2&e&&($r(8),xs("ngForOf",t.data))},directives:[Bi],styles:["body[_ngcontent-%COMP%]{background-color:#eee}label.radio[_ngcontent-%COMP%]{cursor:pointer}label.radio[_ngcontent-%COMP%]   input[_ngcontent-%COMP%]{position:absolute;top:0;left:0;visibility:hidden;pointer-events:none}label.radio[_ngcontent-%COMP%]   span[_ngcontent-%COMP%]{padding:4px;border:1px solid red;display:inline-block;color:red;width:100%;min-width:100px;text-align:center;border-radius:3px;margin-top:7px;text-transform:uppercase}label.radio[_ngcontent-%COMP%]   input[_ngcontent-%COMP%]:checked + span[_ngcontent-%COMP%]{border-color:red;background-color:red;color:#fff}.ans[_ngcontent-%COMP%]{margin-left:36px!important}.btn[_ngcontent-%COMP%]:active, .btn[_ngcontent-%COMP%]:focus{outline:0!important;box-shadow:none!important}"]}),e})(),pa=(()=>{class e{}return e.\u0275mod=Ye({type:e,bootstrap:[da]}),e.\u0275inj=J({factory:function(t){return new(t||e)},providers:[],imports:[[aa]]}),e})();(function(){if(Sr)throw new Error("Cannot enable prod mode after platform setup.");Wr=!1})(),na().bootstrapModule(pa).catch(e=>console.error(e))},zn8P:function(e,t){function r(e){return Promise.resolve().then((function(){var t=new Error("Cannot find module '"+e+"'");throw t.code="MODULE_NOT_FOUND",t}))}r.keys=function(){return[]},r.resolve=r,e.exports=r,r.id="zn8P"}},[[0,0]]]);